Well, what are you doing so early on your legs, my child?
I'm waiting for my aunt.
For your aunt Dete?
Good morning, Thomas. How are you?
I'm very well, but what's going on with you?
Nothing special. I want to fly with Heidi to the village.
I could take you to Mayenfeld.
Oh, thank you, Thomas. That's nice of you.
Well, let's go, you two.
Immediately. Here, Heidi, tie your scarf so you don't lose it.
- I'm hot. - You'd rather sweat than wear it.
Hold on tight.
Come on, Lottie, we have to go.
So, so, so, there you two pretty girls want to fly to the village in the early
morning.
Is there a church today or some kind of child baptism?
No, I'm bringing Heidi up to the Alme Öhi.
What is she supposed to do there?
She's supposed to stay there.
I found a position in Frankfurt.
Unfortunately, I can't use it.
Done.
There she goes, little Heidi, and doesn't even know what's going to happen to
her.
After the death of her parents, she lived with her aunt Dete.
And Heidi always thought that aunt Dete would be her only relative.
But suddenly everyone was talking about an old Moorish moor.
And this moor should be her grandfather.
And every time Heidi asked how he looked, no one could give her an answer.
For years, no one had seen this grandfather again.
I'm sorry, I have to sit you down here.
Thank you, Thomas, that has already helped.
Heidi, what are you doing again now?
Try it too, it's nice and cold.
Goodbye, take care.
How is that supposed to be with those old men?
Here!
Can't you run a little faster?
Heidi, where are you staying? Don't move!
The mountain is too steep. I'm warm.
Heidi, if we don't hurry, we'll never get to the top. Come on!
What's going on? Are you tired?
How far is it? It's so warm here. I can't take it anymore.
It's over there. Look, Heidi. That's Dörfli. That's where you were born.
That's where I was born?
That's the bell of the village church. Come on, Heidi, let's go.
Well, that's something, isn't it, Dede? Hello.
Good morning.
Come on in for a moment.
Another time, we're in a hurry.
Dede, well, something like that.
Good morning.
I haven't seen you in a long time.
People say you're working now.
I'm even going to Frankfurt.
What? And now just say the sweet little one, there's your child.
I don't have a child yet, that's Heidi.
Heidi? What kind of Heidi?
The daughter of Adelheid, my older sister.
You know that.
Well, isn't that...
Of course it is.
She told the little one, there's the child of Adelheid.
If that's the case, then you have to be the little Heidi. I've heard a lot about
you.
What do you two want here in the village?
We're on our way to the Almyrhy. I'll take Heidi to him.
- What about the old one? - But don't you want to leave the little one alone
with the old one?
I have nothing else to do. I found a job in Frankfurt and now the grandfather
has to take care of her.
What? You're giving him the child?
- I'm already sorry for the little one. - That can't be serious, Dete.
Oh yes.
For years the old one hasn't been allowed to look at us in the village.
He doesn't even come to church on Sunday.
If only I knew what the old one is up to, that he's up there alone on the
almshouse.
- You know what? - Dieter!
- Dieter, stay here! - Goodbye!
But you're not talking to any more people.
And he has such terribly bushy eyebrows.
- You must be totally crazy. - I don't care what you think of me.
He's your grandfather and he's on it now.
But no one knows what he's doing.
He can be seen at least once a year and even then he doesn't say a word to any
of us.
Something's not right up there.
No man keeps his whole life, mother soul alone, somewhere in the mountains on an
alp.
What kind of a terrible child is that? Completely uneducated.
He just ran over you. Did you hurt yourself, Heidi?
Come on, come here.
Kiss.
I can understand you, Deete, but still, I don't think it's right of you.
Just try to put yourself in Heidi's shoes.
There you are again.
Well, do you want to jump on the mountain now a little easier after the cold
bath?
Besides, it's not even my goat!
Dede, think about it again with Heidi. The old öhi can't do anything with
children. He can't do anything with anyone.
He will get used to it. He just has to work a little harder.
Heidi! Heidi!
She's running over there. She's running after Peter. She's well taken care of
there. Peter will be careful.
Heidi is used to taking care of herself. She will somehow get along.
Hopefully you're right. Aldi is still quite small. She is only five years old
and she has got used to you.
You can't just plant children like that. You can't even do that with trees.
I always have to go after everyone.
But slowly I also don't feel like it anymore.
The old thing is coming down now.
That too.
Nanou?
Why not?
Not yet. It's much better in the underwear.
From today on I was always the fastest.
From today on you know someone who is faster than you.
Where are you running to?
To the Alpüi, that's where I live.
What? You live at the old Krieskram?
Yes, from today on.
I don't believe you. No human is able to keep up with you.
Maybe you'll make a face.
Tell me, aren't you afraid at all?
Why? Should I?
Don't you know?
Oh, forget it.
Where are you going with all those goats if they don't belong to you?
I'll bring them up the mountain and I'll take care of them.
What do they want up there?
Nothing special. They just want to eat.
Nothing more?
This is my goat. She barks like a dog. Then you live in the little house back
there.
I guess we should hurry. The sun is going down soon.
Come on, come on! Yes, good!
So Heidi got to know the goat herder Peter. The two became thick friends very
soon.
Peter got to know each other in the mountains and Heidi liked that.
I have to weigh you now.
Think about what I said. Heidi is nothing for the mountains. Take her with you.
-Live well. -Live well, Barbel.
-I'm coming. -Heidi, what do you look like?
-What did you do with your clothes? -I just took them off, nothing else.
You just threw them away? What did you think?
I was so hot, so I took them off.
You took them off? Heidi, Heidi.
Peter, be so nice and get the clothes back, okay?
I'm sorry, but I don't have time.
Maybe you have some time now.
-Yes, I think so. -Well, you always have some time.
Yes, I do.
Yes, I will hurry up too.
I'm coming with you. -You stay here.
Thank you. Quick, the wind is coming again.
Good bye, grandfather.
We have arrived.
Greetings, you must be the Almöhi.
That's me.
And with whom do I have the pleasure of speaking?
With me.
Oh, I'm about to burst.
This is Heidi Almöhi, your niece.
You won't recognize her anymore.
The last time you saw her, she was a very small baby.
A very small baby.
You're late.
Yes.
Don't act as if you couldn't count to three.
Make sure you bring the goats to the pasture and take mine with you.
Wait!
You stay here. You'll be needed in a moment, Heidi.
Okay, Dede, say what you want.
You definitely didn't bring the baby here for no reason.
I know you.
I can't take care of her any longer. I want to leave her with you.
What?
There's no other way.
I've been taking care of Heidi for the last four years. I've done what I could.
And now you're on the line, Almöhi.
If you know that, then you can definitely explain to me
what an old man like me should do in the middle of the mountains with a little
girl.
You'll come up with something. And no matter what it is,
it's finally time you took care of her.
When Heidi's parents died, she was only a year old. Today she's five years old.
It's finally time that you do something for her.
After all, you're her next relative.
Heidi is the daughter of your son. Don't forget that.
And if you don't want to keep her here, then do with her what you want.
But whatever happens, it happens on your responsibility.
But I assume you're so hard-hearted that you're not even interested in what will
happen to a little girl.
You don't seem to have ever heard the word "responsibility" before.
You crawl up here and don't speak a word with a human soul.
What do you think you're doing? But that's all I can tell you.
Out!
Stop!
You're not saying anything anymore.
Make sure you finally get out of here.
And don't you dare to look at me one more time.
I've had enough of your gossip.
Enough for once and for all.
Take your things and go.
Good-bye, Heidi.
Be brave, little one,
and please try to understand me.
It will be all right.
Live well, aunt Dete!
I think I can get used to you
For Heidi it looked like it wouldn't be easy to live with this grandfather
Why did he have to get used to her first?
Couldn't he have her at the same time?
Just like she liked Heidi from the beginning
Heidi still couldn't know what her life would look like up here on the Alp
For her everything was strange and full of adventures
Every day there was something new to see and to learn
And Heidi learned quickly
It didn't take long and she knew exactly how she had to treat this Norwegian
grandfather that everyone in the village feared
The life of Nunan changed for the Alp too
The one who was used to it
to be alone, suddenly had a little overbearing guest. But we want to tell you
about that in our next story.