When Heidi was one year old, her parents died and since then Heidi grew up with
Aunt Dete.
She lived with her aunt for four years and all the time she believed that Aunt
Dete was her only relative.
But all of a sudden everyone was talking about a mysterious grandfather, about
the old Almy.
And Heidi was brought to this grandfather.
Heidi must stay with you. I have found a job in Frankfurt.
Out!
Go!
Get out of my sight!
And never let yourself be seen up here again!
And dare to disturb my peace on the Alps ever again in my life!
Good-bye, Heidi.
It will be all right.
Live well, Aunt Dede!
So you left her here, Dede. How could you just leave such a little child like
Heidi up there at the old gravestone?
That was not right of you.
What should I do?
Something, but not that.
Where should I go with her? I have loved Heidi with all my heart.
Do you think it's easy for me?
I know it's bad.
I'm young, Babel. I'm only 26 years old.
Since my sister died, I've been taking care of Heidi like a mother.
We hardly had money to live, Babel.
For the first time, I've found the right position.
In Frankfurt, Babel, you don't belong here.
Take her with you.
What am I supposed to do in Frankfurt with Heidi when I'm working?
You all have no idea!
I'm afraid we have to do something with you.
If you can't think of anything better, you could show me the house from the
inside.
Maybe that's the best idea at the moment.
Collect your clothes and come with me.
Why do I need my clothes?
What kind of a strange child are you?
Don't children need any clothes?
Yes, but my clothes just bother me when I jump.
Watch out!
That's what I learned from the goats.
Still, it's better to bring your clothes home.
- Do you still fit in there? - If you give it your all, yes.
What a huge pot. Cheese. I think it smells like cheese. Right? - Yes, it does.
Since you live alone, you probably cook yourself, don't you? - Yes.
From now on, I'll cook for you, grandfather.
Oh, hard. That must be your bed. But where should I sleep? - Wherever you want.
I can't sleep in the cheese pot, can I?
Why don't you look for a place you like?
You think so?
Well, if you think so, I'll take a look around.
Oh, it smells good in here.
I want to sleep here.
Oh, yes.
Oh, it's beautiful up here.
Grandfather, look how incredibly beautiful it is up here.
I know.
Well, what happened?
Nobody in the world has such a bed. Only me, Heidi.
I thought you dropped the ladder. What's going on?
I like it. It smells so good. It's the most beautiful bed in the world.
I always want to sleep here.
Here and nowhere else.
Up here I'll make my bed. And what kind of bed?
I hope you have a bed sheet for me.
Without a bed sheet it's not possible.
Or have you ever seen a bed without a bed sheet?
That's good. I'll go and get one.
I saw it from the beginning. It's a strange child.
Hurry up, Grandfather!
You have to get used to it. We have plenty of time up here.
That may be true, but today we all have to go to bed for the first time.
Hooray!
And this one doesn't have any.
It seems that we can't do it without help.
What are you doing now?
I understand.
A little better, isn't it?
Yes.
Soft, wonderfully soft.
So you can do that.
Attention!
You wanted to have it, didn't you?
Yes, partly, but there's something missing.
Most beds have bed sheets, but also bed covers.
That will be difficult. I'm not equipped for guests.
That doesn't matter. Then we'll just take more straw for it.
- It's enough. - Wait, I have an idea.
Do you think you can sleep in there as well as in a sleeping bag?
We'll see.
Now I know what you mean, Grandfather.
Beautiful.
Do you think it will work?
But yes, why not? It's much nicer than I imagined it to be.
If only it was already night, Grandfather, so I could go to bed.
Do you think you can see the stars?
Yes, if you look through the hatch.
If there are no clouds in the sky, then you can see a thousand and a thousand
stars.
Do you think so?
Do you think so, grandfather? I can hear the birds singing in the trees in the
morning.
You will hear the birds and also the wind when it ripples in your window.
Do you really think so?
I know everything very well.
The wind ripples in your window. Sometimes very quietly, sometimes a little
loudly.
But then don't be afraid of it. That's just the way it is to say good day.
The wind can tell a lot. It comes from far away. So listen to it, Heidi.
You don't believe how many stories he knows.
Do you really mean it?
So you didn't mean it honestly.
Of course I meant it honestly.
Then I'm relieved.
Nice.
But why did you have to laugh just now?
Because I, old donkey, just realized that I like someone.
Then you'll definitely give me something to eat.
You're right to remind me of food.
It's time for us to cook something.
Now that was the feared Almöhi.
Heidi could, after she had met her grandfather,
no longer understand why everyone in the village was afraid of him.
Maybe just because he was different from the others?
The cheese is getting very soft. It looks strange, but it smells good.
It looks very cozy.
There is only one little thing on the table.
You forgot something for this.
Yes?
Do you mean this one?
Yes, that's good.
Such a big one.
But my hunger is also big.
Do children always eat while standing?
No.
Well, then it would be better if we covered it on the floor.
Better than nothing.
My first table of my own.
Please, a lot.
I bet I can do it without leaving anything behind.
Well, what did I say? All at once, without leaving anything behind.
The milk is from our own goats. You can't get anything fresher. Do you think you
can get more?
Of course. Who is that?
I totally forgot about him. Come, come, come.
What's your name?
This is Joseph.
Isn't he a little too big?
I mean, you can have five children for such a dog.
Here in the mountains we need such dogs, but you'll have to learn that.
Hello, Joseph.
But is this one big?
These dogs are called Bernadines.
Aunt Dede once had a dog, a very fat one with short legs.
He used to go for walks with me.
Wake up!
Excuse me, please.
Stay here, butterfly, stay here!
Then I'll put you in my arms.
What a pity!
Hm, there he is!
Now then!
Nothing again!
Wait, I'll catch you!
If only I could fly!
So will you finally wait now?
Haha, yes!
Come in and put on something warm!
In the evening it gets cold!
Shut up!
Grandfather?
What's that supposed to be, what you're doing there?
- You can guess three times, my child. - What do you mean?
Grandfather, you're building a chair for me, so I can sit at the table when we
want to eat together.
That's my shawl.
I hope you like it.
Oh, thank you very much.
Why shouldn't I like it?
Joseph, Joseph!
I have a shawl, I have a shawl, a shawl, a shawl of my own, all for myself.
He will only wake up when he gets something to eat.
Don't give him any trouble.
Attention!
For Heidi, everything was just wonderful. She was happy about her own bed, high
up in the room, about the butterflies, the meadows and the mountains. Heidi was
happy. For the first time in her life, she understood what it means to be at
home somewhere.
For heaven's sake, keep sleeping. I didn't want to. I'm sorry.
Did I hurt you?
Hey, I'll live with you from today.
If we become friends, you can save your bone. That's much more comfortable.
Joseph, I talked to you. Now open your eyes.
Where have you been all this time?
- What's your name? - The white one is Swenley and the brown one is Barry.
- Why are they licking? - He's got salt on his hands.
- Goats really like that. - Give me something too.
A whole handful of salt for you, Swenley.
- That tickles. - I couldn't stand it.
What is it, General? Don't you want to move on with your goats?
- Yes, oh, uh, what do you mean? - I'll be back tomorrow, Heidi.
Just tell me you don't know that there's goat milk, too. Here, take a look.
What? I'm supposed to drink that?
You've even had that before, today at the table.
I actually liked it quite a bit.
What's going on now?
Where's the wind coming from?
Hey, what did you say?
I was sent to the mountains, forever!
If you want to play, stay in the house, but be quiet.
Not that something happens outside.
Later they will take away my right to care for you.
Did you understand me?
Why is she up there? Is she afraid?
Heidi was certainly not afraid. She had only been on the island for one day and
it was as if she had spent her whole life here.
The hut, the wind, the moon over the mountains, Heidi had always dreamed of all
of this.
She didn't know anything about what she would experience, who and what she would
meet.
She had already met Peter and his goat herd, but she didn't know the names of
the flowers yet and the tabernacles.
There's your goat, Peter.
She knew so little about this world that was so new to her.
She knew nothing about the animals and the people who live here and she didn't
know, above all,
how quickly she would win her grandfather, the grey-haired old Almy, in love.
To be continued
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.