Where am I?
Yes, of course, I'm on the Alm, at my grandfather's.
Good Morning! Good Morning!
You can see all the way into the valley!
Peter!
Grandfather, good morning!
I'm already awake and dressed.
Did you sleep well, Grandfather?
You get up early, that's good.
I wake up early.
You're also here early with your goat herd, Peter.
- Are you always this early?
- If I don't oversleep.
- Do you oversleep often?
- Oh, there's something pulling on me.
Oh, that's just the little goat. You probably want to say good morning to me.
But that's nice of you.
You seem to like the goats. Why don't you go with Peter?
May I? You have nothing against it?
Why should I have anything against it?
Of course, you have to wash your face first.
- Will you wait?
- But yes.
- Thank you.
- Don't stand around like that. Come with me.
- Yes. - What is it? Come on.
- What is it? - What is it?
This is for you, so that you don't starve on the road, and make sure you give
some to Heidi.
- Can I go now? Is my face clean enough, grandfather?
- Yes, that's how I like your face.
- Do you think so? Is Joseph coming with us?
- I doubt that. Joseph, are you going with?
- Open your eyes.
- Then go now, you two. But be careful.
- Yes, we definitely will be.
On this day, Heidi climbed up to the meadow for the first time with Peter and
the herd of goats.
She had left her shoes at home. She wanted to be as free and carefree as the
goats.
They went through deep gorges, climbed up hill and then a bit back down.
And Heidi became, to Peter's great amazement, not tired for a moment.
She asked and blabbered, her mouth just didn't want to stand still.
She wanted to know about the clouds and hear the names of the mountains and
Heidi had to stop at every new flower to admire them.
Let's walk here. How beautiful.
Wait. Stay here. Stand still. Come here!
What's with all this silly jumping all of a sudden.
11. 18. 22. 105. 117. 5.
2. Very many.
1, 2, 3.. And where is Heidi?
Heidi! Where are you?
Heidi! Heidi!
Lost. Gone.
Disappeared.
Answer me.
Say something.
Why are you yelling?
Thank god. Just because. No reason. I'm just yelling because it's fun.
I thought you were calling for me.
Why didn't you answer if you heard me calling?
If something happens to you, the Almohi will shout at me until my ears burst.
Nothing will happen.
- You never know. What are you doing?
We have to go on.
Can you explain to me why you are tearing off the flowers?
I'm not tearing the flowers, I'm picking them.
And if you don't know why you do that, I'm very, very sorry for you.
If you were a goat, I'd say you'd eat them. But you're not one.
Goat.
I really have no idea what this is supposed to be. Explain it to me!
Maybe you are a goat after all, a beautiful one with horns.
Heidi, the baby goat
- So you know, I'm going to put all the flowers in my bed and
make it as beautiful as the flower meadow here.
Strange idea. Shall we go on now?
I'd love to.
What's the name of the pretty bird sitting on the branch?
No idea. Just a pretty bird.
Look, Peter.
What's the name of the animal that was just sitting on the tree?
That's impossible. You don't know that?
I've seen it somewhere before.
Peter, there! Quick! That's a rabbit!
What a pity.
Let's go on.
Why did you run away from me?
What do I know why? Come on, finally!
Are we in a hurry?
At some point we want to get to the top.
Look! An eagle is flying up there!
Apparently you don't know anything. That wasn't an eagle, that was a raven.
We're almost there! Come on, quick!
Come on!
Whoever gets to the rock mound first wins!
How beautiful
Is the white stuff snow?
-What else?
The sun never shines down there.
I know something better than to stare into the gorge.
Yes?
I just have to get my flowers safe first, then I'll join you.
I'll put them with the bag.
Wait, I thought you had thought up something we could play.
I was definitely not talking about playing.
You said you know something better than to stare into the gorge.
I know, and that's exactly what I'm doing right now.
Sleep?
What else?
Do you know something better than sleeping in the sun?
Sleep.
You lazy bug!
Do you know what you are, Peter?
You're terribly boring!
Fine with me.
You don't really want to sleep.
Now I know.
You're just pretending.
You want to prank me.
Peter!
You can't just sleep now.
The raven is coming back!
The other raven was smaller.
Help.
Heidi! Where are you, Heidi?
Say something!
Don't let go!
Quick, he's coming back!
Hold tight.
The big raven up there knocked me from the tree. Wait.
Stay still. I'll help.
Slowly.
Oh, that was close. You were supposed to stay close to me!
I wasn't that far away.
I want to know where the raven is flying.
That's not a raven, that's an eagle.
Oh, I don't care what it is.
It's not irrelevant! A raven wouldn't have thrown you from a tree, would it?
Ok fine, an eagle. I still don't know where it's flying to.
You don't even know.
Tell me, do you want to or can't you tell me where the raven is flying to?
I actually want to know if where you come from you also used to treat
the other children like you do me.
You speak with one as if they were the last piece of dirt.
Besides, it's an eagle!
Wow, he's sensitive.
That's your cheese! Why don't you eat it?
Don't be afraid, you're not going to get sick. Try it, Heidi!
Such a big piece...
Now he swallowed it wrong.
Milk.
Let me try. I'm thirsty.
You can't do this!
Move! Thanks!
I wanted to do it, too.
I understand.
Your eyes are as big as wagon wheels.
Take it already. I'm happy to give it to you.
-I can't eat as much as you. Well, take it.
-You're giving me some of your cheese?
-Yes.
-I don't need it. Take it.
-Thank you.
-Will you really not want it back?
-You can eat it.
What's the name of the little, colorful goat over there?
-It's called whatever it looks like.
Then the colorful one is her name.
And the old goat over there? -The old one, quite simply.
Oh, what? What's her name as a little goat? She can't have been old from the
start.
I don't know anymore. Everyone calls her the old one.
What does the colorful one want from the old one?
-You ask questions, of course play.
The most beautiful is Schnucki.
-You only imagine that. When they are small, they are all cute.
I find her especially pretty.
Did you understand what I said, because you are coming to me now?
Look, over there.
There are marmots.
There are marmots?
Where?
They are gone again.
Stop. Stay still. Come here.
Stay still, you stupid animal.
Wait, I'll help you.
Grab the other leg.
I can't reach. My arms are too short.
Wait.
Here. Take it. Good grass. Nice grass. It's tasty.
Take it already.
That tastes good.
It's a good thing that I'm here!
Yes, and it's a good thing that smarter goats also exist.
You'll never do that again.
Wait! Don't hit her!
How else am I supposed to teach her what she can and can't do?
No, please don't!
If you beat her I will never talk to you again!
We are to blame because we didn't pay attention!
Don't worry, Bunte. He is not to do anything to you.
Strange, but all of a sudden I don't want to beat her anymore!
I don't know why, but somehow I'm sorry for her.
You're getting reasonable.
Then you can tell me where the raven is flying to.
What's wrong?
Oh, I see. You still haven't thought of where they're flying to, have you?
It was an eagle.
I always get that mixed up.
From now on, no more goats will be beaten, promise?
We need to go home.
Can't we stay a little longer? I still haven't seen the marmots.
No. The herd has to be down in the village before the sun sets.
Why? Can't you deliver the goats later, or will no one want them then?
Yes, but I don't want them to break their legs.
Peter, Peter, come here quickly.
Everything suddenly looks red, like fire.
And the peaks are suddenly made of real gold, like royal crowns.
When the sun sets, it's always like that.
Then it colors everything glowing red.
Even I like that.
Look, Heidi! He's over there again!
Where?
In the sky, of course.
Oh, my raven.
I give up.
For Heidi, this first day she spent with Peter and the herd on the pasture was
like a fairytale.
She saw animals she had never heard of before.
And above all, she experienced for the first time the glow of the mountains in
the light of the setting sun.
Now it's over again. Do you think you can see it every evening here in the
mountains?
I would like to see it again.
Don't worry, you will. Sunsets happen almost every evening. Sometimes they are
even more beautiful.
Peter, you forgot something. You still haven't told me where it's flying to.
To it's nest.
Did you know that all this time?
Yes, I did.
And you didn't say anything?
Why?
Because you called our beautiful eagle ravens all this time.
Joseph, Grandfather. We're back!
Well, my child. You seem to have enjoyed it.
Your whole face is glowing.
Oh yes, grandfather. It was beautiful.
Goodbye, Heidi.
Goodbye. Until tomorrow. Pick me up.
Of course. Until then.
Grandfather, did you know that eagles throw people off the
mountains and ravens don't?
And that you can find flowers everywhere?
What's wrong with them, grandfather? Just look at them. What do they look like?
They were completely different.
You'll have wrapped them in your cloth all day long. Flowers need water. They
need sun, fresh air and water. Without all that, they'll wilt.
I'm sorry for them.
Why do I always do everything wrong?
Heidi was very sad about her flowers.
But after a few minutes, all sadness was gone.
In the evening, after the grandfather had set the table,
she talked and talked again like a waterfall.
She had to describe everything.
Every experience, every detail.
She told about the eagle, the marmots, about Peter, whom she forbade to beat the
goats, and in particular she described the glowing red sunset.
You don't even know how beautiful it is.
Yes, Heidi, I know how beautiful it is. That's why I live up here.
And I will never move down into the village, not for all the money in the world.
Here in the mountains I am free, as free as your eagle you told me about
earlier.
The grandfather was suddenly very serious. He thought of the eagle, thought of
his free, wild,
boundless life. He thought about how people admired him, but also pursued him.
Heidi was shocked. She suddenly realized that her grandfather, who the people
were gossiping about in the village, was very similar to the eagle.
You know what?
I'll stay with you from now on. I'll never go away. I always want to live
like you.
And one day I'll be just like you. Just the long beard you have, I don't want
that.
Heidi wanted to get rid of her grandfather's serious thoughts with her remark.
And she succeeded in that.
Are you angry?
No, why should I be angry? I'm sorry if I scared you.
I just had to think of something, but that has nothing to do with you, my child.
So a wonderful day ended for Heidi.
Of course, she tried to delay as long as possible the time when the inevitable
bedtime would take place.
In this she was no different from all other children.
But in the end it was time.
She climbed up in her room and was already asleep when her grandfather was
tucking her in.
And she dreamed that night of goats, rocks, mountains and marmots.
The next morning Heidi got up with the sun, and no sooner than she had gotten up,
she was already confusing everything.
On this day she found Piep, and from that hour on there was nothing
else for her.
Piep had fallen out of the nest during a thunderstorm, and Heidi held and cared
for him so long until he became strong and healthy again.
The whole lovely long day she caught flies and mosquitos for him and sometimes
even snails and skinks.
No matter how much she was disgusted by all the little animal stuff she had to
catch, nothing was too much for Piep.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.