Heidi lived at the Almeuil for three days and every new day was as exciting for
her as the previous one.
Every morning she stood up with the sun, greeted the birds as if they were her
very personal friends and then she waited impatiently for Peter.
"Just look at this Heidi, she's even bringing in the goats. Open your eyes.
You're hopeless."
There was once a goat in the sky.
Oh, something like that. Now she has simply dissolved.
Tell me, are you actually never hungry?
I don't have time to eat.
Me neither.
Oh, if you don't have time, then I'll eat for you.
Don't worry about that. I can eat alone.
But that's a nice flower.
Snuggie, come here. It must taste very good.
Do you think the flower tastes as good as it looks?
What's going on now?
Hold my hat!
We have to see how we get out of here. It's too dangerous up here. Let's go.
But why? Because I think we want to eat something now.
That's not a storm!
- It's just a wind! - Not even then you'll get on my nerves!
You'll get a nice kiss if you go on like this! Even the goats hide in front of
the rain!
All right, if you mean it, I'll hide too, but I don't care!
Let's see who's there first!
- Hans! - It's okay, you don't have to be afraid, we're well-prepared here, and
he's on his way.
I'll tell you something. - What is it? - You know what? I'm hungry like a bear,
I could eat your whole forest.
- You're hungry? - Yes, and how? - How can you think of food now? - What a pity.
Heidi would never have thought that her beloved mountains would have another
face.
Not a friendly and lovely one, full of sun, flowers, scent and birds chirping,
but a cruel and dangerous one.
A face that can make you afraid.
And that's it.
You have to get out of here. It's all over.
It can go into the mountains so fast.
You don't have to be afraid anymore.
Do you really mean it?
The sun is shining again.
If you only told me that, I wouldn't have believed it.
I don't.
A bird?
Oh, there's a bird over there.
Look at me. He's sick. Poor little bird.
Maybe there's a nest up there and he fell out during the storm.
You know what? I'll just put him back in.
No, no, no. That's out of the question.
Why not?
Because there's something wrong with his wing and I have to take care of it.
We'll give it to the grandfather.
He'll be grateful.
Why not?
He has enough with his goats. How can he take care of a bird?
Then I'll breed him myself.
He's already been bred.
Then I'll take care of him and raise him.
That's way too small. You'll never do that in life.
And yet...
Leave the bird here!
I won't leave it!
I'll prove to you that I can do it.
But Heidi...
You can't go home alone!
It has to be something really exciting!
Are you afraid of the thunderstorm?
Didn't you know that you shouldn't touch young birds?
Yes, but I think he broke the wing.
It won't be easy to feed him.
But why not? We have enough.
Well, if you do something to him, then you can experience something.
He understood me. He certainly doesn't dare to approach him.
How do you want to help him?
I don't know yet, but somehow it has to be done.
Tell him.
- He's much weaker than I thought. - Do you think we can't do anything with him?
- I don't know. - But it has to be done.
It's such a pretty, cute little bird.
- Something's definitely going to fall on you, grandfather. - Well, then get to
work.
- You have to look for insects, Heidi. Small mosquitoes, for example. - As many
as you want.
- The main thing is, we'll make it. - Oh, stop. Don't you need a nest?
This is enough for the beginning. - A soup bowl?
It doesn't matter to him. He doesn't know it's a soup bowl.
Such a big annoyance from such a small bird.
And one more.
One more.
And one more, so you can grow up.
Peter!
Now I'm curious what kind of face he's making. He's going to burst into rage.
Look, Snuggie, we have a new guest in the house.
Snuggie! Still insulted?
Wait, Peter! Look, he's taking his food! Grandfather thinks if he keeps going
like this, he'll grow up!
I don't give a damn about your stupid bird!
Then I don't give a damn about you either!
What did he do to the bird? He didn't do anything to it!
What is it?
Nothing at all. Peter is just a little bit jealous.
But he doesn't need that at all. I don't understand that at all.
Come back, Peter. Don't act like a stupid boy and don't come here at once.
But I don't like to come. I don't even think about it.
First I'm happy and now it's this stupid bird. Suddenly I'm not good enough
anymore.
Peter, are the goats all right?
Do you know anything about the little one from the meadow?
Is she all right?
She can be.
Open your mouth, is something wrong with her?
How should I know?
Peter, do you want to play?
Nobody talks to me.
Give the old one something to eat.
Is she pale?
Wait, I'll play with you.
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know. That doesn't sound good.
Maybe we should take a look.
That's good.
I think it's hungry. It keeps closing its beak.
What do you think about having breakfast first?
First I have to see if I can find some insects.
I don't care.
Do you want to see the sack?
I'm not interested in what you've collected in your sack.
I'll say it anyway. All insects.
All insects?
You don't believe how much you have to collect.
Time-disappearance.
That doesn't matter to me.
The main thing is that he gets somehow full.
He eats all the time.
I think so. But I know a better way.
Just let him fly. Then he can collect his own ants and eat whatever he wants.
That could be good for you right now. So that you know it.
You can leave it to me.
Schnucki, now I'm going to run after him quickly, otherwise he'll get mad at you
too.
Now run! Come on, jump quickly!
Heidi couldn't understand what was going on with Peter.
He was always so nice.
He hadn't even asked her once if she wanted to accompany him today.
But I don't have any time right now anyway.
Are you even more hungry?
No, I don't understand what you're trying to say.
Do you want grasshoppers today?
Joseph! Peep, grasshoppers!
This weird thing seems to taste good.
I'm sorry, but we have a bird.
Now you have eaten it away.
Does it even taste good?
She will have tasted it.
You think so?
Why shouldn't he have an appetite for snails?
Maybe he also has an appetite for birds.
Joseph, here!
It doesn't come into question at all. That's what you thought.
Grandfather, you absolutely have to build a cage.
I assume you want your bird to have a cage.
Exactly. Otherwise Joseph will eat him.
Joseph?
At least he ate a snail.
Now you're scared.
Don't worry about it.
Don't worry. I'll take care of you.
He won't come to you, Peep-Matz.
What do you think? How do you feel in your new house?
Take good care of yourself.
When the dog comes, just knock over the fence.
You're still alive?
Hm, there's your hat on the ladder.
I think you fell off the ladder all by yourself.
Joseph didn't want to.
Joseph!
Now he's asleep again.
I know it now, Joseph. You wanted to save him.
I thought you wanted to eat him.
Joseph, please don't be mean to me.
You're a sweet dog, Joseph.
Even though you're so big that you have to be afraid of you.
Why are you leaving now?
It's a pity, but thank you very much
It took a long time, but finally Heidi understood how kind and good-natured this
Bernadina was
From this moment on, Joseph was her good friend, like her grandfather and like
Peter
Even though Peter has become a bit strange in his opinion lately
Heidi didn't know yet how fast her little bird would grow
She didn't have the slightest idea how and when she could mate with Peter
All she knew was that she was happy here on the Alp
That she liked the goats, the meadows, the mountains, all her new friends very,
very much
But sometimes very unexpected things happen
Beautiful and less beautiful
But how Heidi is doing up there on the Alp
we want to tell you the next time in a new story