Peter didn't play with the other boys on the village road anymore.
He went up to the mountains with his goats like every morning.
A few days ago, getting up early was a bit annoying for him.
But since there was Heidi, he could hardly wait to get to the alps.
Oh, it's unbearably hot again today.
Please be so kind and give the alp the letter when you pass by, yes?
But don't lose it on the way.
A letter for the old one?
Yes, be careful.
But do me a favor, don't open the letter.
I can see it at the tip of your nose that you're curious,
but the affairs of other people don't concern you.
But when you get it out, you can tell me.
Well then, live well.
Try a little higher. You see, it's already working.
Always open and close, open and close.
But Piep, how can you just stand there like that? Josef, come with us!
Heidi, leave the bird alone. If he's old enough, he'll fly by himself.
Come on.
Well, can't he fly wonderfully?
Josef!
If he goes on like this, I can let him go soon.
Then he can fly away with the other birds.
But he will fly best of all.
Certainly, but now he should be quite big and strong once.
Give your bird a little peace, Heidi.
Do you think you need a little peace, Pete Matz?
Or do we want to continue with the flight lesson?
No, Heidi still wants something from you. She has a bird now. Stay!
Come here. I taught Pete to fly yesterday. Go, fly!
Did you see?
She doesn't need you anymore.
We won't wait any longer.
But why aren't you waiting for us?
I'll show it to him again!
If I catch him, I'll make him...
Now I didn't give the letter to Alm-Öhi out of anger.
I don't care about this letter.
Let them see how they can get a letter on their own.
- Why alone? - Who's going with us?
Piep. Piep is with me.
Piep has to see the mountains. We only need an escort.
Can I take Käse with me?
There are your friends up there. Why don't you fly to them and show them what
you've already learned?
You can do it just as well as they can. At least try it once.
So what did I tell you? You just have to dare.
You have to try to get up.
Then come on. I know it's hard.
Don't be sad. In a few days it will be much better.
We both can do it.
Mr. Peep, say good day to him.
Come on, let me catch him. Don't be so stupid.
Peep has never flown such a long distance before.
You know what, Peter? I think he likes you.
Why didn't you tell me you were coming?
Do you have a problem?
I couldn't guess you wanted to come.
Why are you in such a bad mood?
What is it?
There you have your letter. That's why you came. And Billy didn't agree. I
wanted to keep it.
What am I supposed to do with it?
Read it. And now take it and bring it to your grandfather.
I don't understand anything.
Well, if you don't want to, then I'll hand over the letter on the way back
myself.
Sometimes you understand terribly slowly.
Now I know what you mean. You're hungry again. I already thought about it.
There, get it out.
I asked my grandfather for a cheese for you.
Cheese?
Of course, what did you think?
Do you think I forgot what you like?
Yes, I thought so.
Actually, he's very nice.
Sometimes you don't understand very quickly.
Peter was very happy that Heidi came to him all by herself.
Not because he was hungry, as Heidi said.
He liked her.
For him, Heidi was something different than the boys and girls from the village.
She shared her love for the animals, the mountains and the flowers.
For him, Heidi had become a friend that he didn't want to lose anymore.
If only I could fly with you.
Flying must be beautiful.
Also Heidi liked Peter.
And she was happy that he finally spoke to her again.
She had never understood that Peter was jealous of her little bird.
Jealousy and envy were foreign to her.
She also felt much too comfortable with her grandfather in the mountains to
think about it.
Heidi was very, very happy for the first time in her life.
And I taught it to him all by myself.
Or bees, or mice, or something like that.
I have two feathers.
Eat, Fick.
Dear Peter.
You chased him away. Without you, Peep would have been caught.
Oh, your stomach is growling.
That's no wonder, isn't it? With all the excitement.
Why don't you think about it?
I'm always thinking about food!
Heinz!
I want to tell you one of the three things! 我想告诉你三件事!
I say water, I'm thirsty! 我说水,我肚子疼!
Can you tell me how she taught you to fly when she doesn't even know the
simplest rules of the game? 你能告诉我她教你飞机的技巧吗?
Do you even know that you're a kid? 你知道你小孩吗?
Then let's run around the bed! I know the rules of the game! 让我们跑到游戏中!
我知道这些游戏的规则!
I know the rules of the game!
Kids can't just get lost in the air!
Maybe there's a mountain ghost here!
Peter made big accusations. He had been distracted by the first real flight of
the little bird and did not pay attention to his herd of goats.
Unfortunately, we have to go over there. Hopefully, you are not dizzy at all.
If you can do that, I can do that too.
Be careful, okay?
Of course!
Now it's going to get foggy. Come on, quick! - Slowly!
I don't like it at all. The fog is getting denser.
We should go home and get Grandfather. Maybe he can help.
Did you hear any noise?
No, nothing.
Where are you going now?
Can't you shut up for a moment?
But why?
I was so scared.
What is that?
Those are your bells. You have to be very close.
I think we've finally found them.
Really?
Please don't run away again. Please don't run away again. I was so scared of
you.
I dropped a Stone of March.
I can imagine that.
And of course you have no idea how we were trembling around you.
You just run away and stick salt from the rocks.
Oh no, not that either.
Is something wrong?
Either we got lost or the transition is gone.
That's no wonder with the fog.
- Maybe we have to go that way. - Maybe, maybe not. I don't know myself either.
But you don't know yourself anywhere else. How are we supposed to find our way
home now?
Maybe we'll find our way when we go the other way.
There's nothing else left for us, but there could be fields everywhere.
- Watch out where you're going. - Let's wait, Peter.
I think you're right.
At least the herd is safe here.
And this morning the sun shone so beautifully.
That's normal, Sonnenbergen. The weather changes quickly here.
We have no reason at all to be happy.
There's someone!
That's...
That can only be Joseph! That's how Joseph sounds!
Yeah, we're in a hurry, but we don't have four legs like you do!
And I couldn't stand him in the beginning because he's so big!
There are the stones and the goats are still there!
I thought I'd have to look for the right one.
We got lost! I'm so glad you're here, I was so terribly scared!
It's all right, my child.
I always thought you were more sensible.
Why in the world would you have to climb around in the fog?
It was the goat's fault, they ran away and we had to look for them, didn't we?
And besides, a stupid falcon would have eaten my bird for one hare.
That seems to have been an exciting day.
If Peter hadn't been there, then Piep wouldn't be alive now and we wouldn't have
found the goats either.
I see, I understand. And as far as I know Peter, he doesn't have anything other
than a bear's hunger at the moment.
Not only Peter, me too. Did you notice that we haven't eaten anything today?
Yes.
Why are you still waiting?
Now I'm so old and I've never seen anyone eat so much in such a short time.
I'll at least pat your back so you don't choke.
Peter eats at least twice as fast as he thinks.
What?
She has no right to say something like that about me.
I'm just sometimes a bit forgetful.
Like today, for example.
Today?
I've forgotten the letter.
And this one?
Thank you, Peter. I hope you like it.
Sleep well, Joseph. Good night. Good night, Grandfather. And thank you very
much.
Good night, my child. And let's dream tonight of something that will be fun.
Yes, I will try my best. Sleep well.
I have found a very good position in Frankfurt.
The city is big and exciting.
I experience something new every day.
If only Heidi could go to school here.
Why aren't you asleep yet?
What's wrong with you?
It's so, so, so, so beautiful when you have a grandfather.
This child.
In the few days she spent with him, she became such an essential part of his
life that he didn't want to know anything about letters he wrote from the city,
as she wrote to Dieter.
He loved the little girl so much that he couldn't imagine a life without the
child.
Heidi didn't know anything about what her grandfather was doing.
She brought the goats to the pasture with Peter day after day and discovered
something new every time.
Everything was full of excitement and adventure for her.
She had no idea about any letters or secret plans of her aunt Dete.
She certainly wouldn't have taken her seriously.
For Heidi it was obvious that she wanted to stay up here in the mountains
forever.
But we'll tell you about that in our next story.