We don't seem to be there for you at all.
For us, you've completely blown yourself up.
That's not mean.
He has a girlfriend now.
Do you mean the strange little girl up there at the almshouse?
That's exactly what I mean. The strange little girl.
She's not strange at all.
Of course she is.
Everyone who has an affair with the old man up there is not quite normal.
She is normal.
Everyone can say that.
I want to swear that your girlfriend has the same long beard as the old man.
No, she doesn't have a beard.
And at some point you want to have a full beard too.
You think so?
You haven't seen her lately, Peter. How's the little girl?
Good.
Why don't you bring her down to the village?
She likes it up there. What's she doing here?
She likes it?
I won't let go of my strange feeling.
There can't be anything to do with right things up there.
You've already woken up.
Are you alright?
And tell me later what you say!
- You could have waited! - Are you awake already?
Yes, of course! Why not?
Give me the bucket!
Why?
Let me milk the two today!
Peter can always milk them!
Peter is a goat herder, he learned it!
And? I'm a goat herder!
- Since when? - Since this morning! I'll prove it to you!
Bucket!
The bucket!
So, here we go!
Something like this is certainly quite simple!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
She doesn't have any milk at all!
Yes, she has milk, quite a lot even!
I think you've been a goat herder since this morning, who knows everything.
Maybe she doesn't want to be milked this morning.
She wants to, but she's not a master yet.
Not a milking master either.
That's not how hard it can be to milk. I'll learn it.
That can only lie in the bucket.
I want to make it!
Oh, I could do it!
Ouch!
Can't you stand still when I'm milking you?
- That's not nice of you. - I'm sorry, I didn't mean to yell at you, Bärli.
- What does she mean? - She's jealous, she wants to be mulled.
- You think so? - Yes, they both like you very much.
What's wrong with you? Leave me alone, leave me alone!
What's going on? Help me! Take her away!
Finally, Bärli. Now it's enough. Back to the bucket.
Finally.
A strange goat here, because she's happy when the goats are gone.
If only I knew how you do that!
So Heidi went up to the meadow with Peter like every morning
And like every morning, this day seemed to her to be even more beautiful than
yesterday
Come!
And how did you like my first goat whistle?
I didn't hear a whistle at all.
No? Stop it!
I think something's wrong with my fingers. I think something's wrong with my
fingers.
While Heidi was trying to prove to her friend Peter that she could become a good
goat herder, the Almöhi was preparing to go down into the village
Twice a year he went down the road to sell the bowls and spoons that he cut out
of wood during the long winter months
And to trade the goat cheese that he made from the milk of Swanley and Bearley
for butter
Come on, Joseph, get up!
Your movements are doing well.
And then he stays there.
- What do you think I'm thinking? - Since when can you read your mind?
- It's already afternoon. Na na na afternoon. Na na na afternoon. Na na na
afternoon. Na na na afternoon. - Come back down to earth!
- Well done! - But you still haven't said what I was thinking.
- I'm whistling! - If you want.
Now you'll experience something!
If I can't whistle, I'll just drive them away!
Three? Why did I only get three?
That's not unfair of you!
Why? I think you want to be the goat all day long.
I do, but I can't do it with the counting.
Then let it be.
No!
Let it go, give it a shot, Lea!
Let me go!
He never allowed me to do that. You'll just find out now.
No, definitely not!
You can't even whistle properly on your finger. How are you going to milk goats
there?
One thing has nothing to do with the other. You just have to explain to me how
to do it.
I don't even think about that. You said you can do it.
Fine, whatever you want. Then I'll eat everything alone in the future.
No, that's not possible. - Why not?
Because you always notice so much that it's enough for two.
Then say please and help me.
What do you say to that?
I haven't seen him in half an eternity.
You used to be very good friends with his son.
Why don't you go over there and say hello?
I don't even think about it.
Alma, come quickly to the window. Down there goes this disgusting Almy.
Is he alone or is the child with him?
Alone, of course.
Too bad, I would have liked to see the little one again.
I'm sure he won't give you anything to eat.
You'll never believe that.
No, you can't believe that either.
What does he want here?
Yes, who are we to welcome to our church?
Good day, priest. How are you?
Why don't you step in for a moment and visit your neighbor's house?
Did you expect him to come to church?
He hasn't been seen in there for years.
He actually left the child alone in the mountains.
I told you that she was making a mistake.
You can't just leave a little child to an old man.
Yes, yes, young and old don't get along.
Yes, that's true.
No, the almshouse is there.
Haven't seen you in a long time.
How do you always do it? What do the mountains do?
As always, do you like the same bread?
Yes.
Go and get it quickly.
They say you have a little girl up there now.
Yes, Heidi.
What is she doing, the poor little one?
That's not enough, there's one more missing.
What? There are only three breads.
But I always gave you that much for the cheese.
I live up there alone in the mountains, but that's why I still haven't lost my
soul.
Do you want to say that we're cheating on you? Say something!
Oh yes, I remember that. We've raised the prices since the last time we were in
Durflea.
You can see how long you haven't been down here.
If you two pretend that you can cheat on me, then you're mistaken.
Do you want to say we're cheating?
You guessed it. That's exactly what I wanted to say.
I warn you, Almöhn, take it back immediately.
Everyone here in Dörfli knows that we're honorable people.
Even my father was a baker here.
I've always understood that.
The word "honorable" that you take into account has always suited him.
So, that's it for today.
I have the stupid feeling that we have gone too far this time.
We have been deceived in him.
So it happened that the Alm-Öhi, only because he had been annoyed by the baker,
went to the city of Mayenfeld for the first time in many years.
He couldn't say how long he wasn't down here anymore.
But, and that surprised him, nothing had changed here in the meantime.
What's wrong with you, Peter? Did you hurt yourself?
I have such a terrible stomachache.
That too! What am I going to do now?
That's counterfeit! You ate all the cheese on your own!
But it tasted so good!
You can't have a stomachache now! We have to bring the goats back to the
village!
Peter, get up! Get yourself together!
Why are you crying like that? Nothing happened, did it?
You know what? I don't have a stomachache anymore.
I think I have a stomachache because I was so scared.
Oh, it's gone again, Peter.
When did you learn that?
I can whistle. I can whistle just as well as a...
What does he want in the village? I'm sure he exchanges cheese for bread.
Do you do that sometimes?
Hello, Peter. Is Heidi already in the hut?
I delivered her, like every night.
That's good. I don't want her running around in the evening.
Don't do that.
He was actually in the village.
I'd like to surprise my grandfather. He doesn't know that I'm a shepherd since
today.
It works!
I have a surprise for you!
I have to show you something! You will be amazed when you see it!
Come! Over there! Come with me! I show it to you!
Peter showed it to me!
You can whistle? I don't believe that!
I already thought you wouldn't believe me!
But you will be amazed! Listen carefully!
Do you believe it now?
Can you whistle too?
Whoever is up here winning has to be able to whistle!
Then whistle!
Whistle again!
You don't have to listen to so much music, my child, if this is supposed to be
the most beautiful music in the world.
It could be.
It certainly is.
How does our goat like this?
Did you bring it with you?
This is a sugar luch. I've never had one before.
Then it's about time.
It tastes very good.
It tastes wonderful.
But we're not quite there before dinner.
I'll try.
Grandfather, it's nice here.
Once again, a day had passed when Heidi was happy all around.
The new world up here in the mountains, which she was curious about at first,
and which she was also a little afraid of, had become her world.
Here in the little hut, she was at home.
Since Heidi was there, of course, something has changed for the Almöhi.
He continued to do his field work and take care of the goats.
But in the house, he tried to see Heidi after the right one very soon.
Of course, she still went to the pasture with Peter every day.
But with all the fun of the new adventures she experienced, she never forgot her
duties as a housewife.
And she took these duties very seriously.
But we want to tell you about this in our next story.