Heidi had been living in the alp for three months now in the mountain hut and in
these three months she had become the adventurous Heidi out of the pale little
girl she once was
She had now got used to life here on the alp
She could even, and she was very proud of it, milk the fingers of pipes and
goats
You have made great progress, you can even land
Now all we need is milk
Milk?
Stop eating, I want to milk you
Look at the face Peter is making, he still doesn't believe I can do it
I never thought you would learn so fast
Do you come to help me? Or do you want some milk too, Pete?
Do you want something to eat?
I'll be blown away and you just sit still. Don't do anything there and eat
cheese.
I didn't eat the cheese. I held it down so it wouldn't be blown away either.
Then at least look at the big clouds back there. We're getting rain.
Oh, they're much too fast. The clouds are raining somewhere else.
And the wind? What about it?
It's not dangerous either. It always gets so strong in autumn.
So you have to get used to it. Summer is over.
If you think I have to get used to it...
Then I have to try to get used to it.
Wind?
But the view is very beautiful.
Let's eat something.
But it took a long time for him to get down there.
Why do you always run? Go slow.
That's not possible!
The day is way too short.
If I go slow, I'll only experience half of it.
I see.
But of course. You know what?
You know what, Grandfather? I almost got blown away today.
We sat quietly on the meadow and wanted to eat.
A very strong wind came.
And it threw me over.
Hopefully not in the vicinity of the cliff.
Why don't you let me milk the goat?
Do you think you can do that?
Of course. You'll see.
It's better than I thought.
Peter didn't think I could do it either.
Heidi, please don't go with Peter to the pasture from tomorrow.
Why?
Look, the autumn storms are getting stronger and more dangerous day by day.
Today you thought it was all a funny game.
But tomorrow it can be bitterly serious.
You are small and the autumn storms are very strong.
But then I can hold on somewhere.
Nothing will happen to me for sure. Please let me go.
I flew like an eagle today.
I leaned against the wind and it drove me.
And then I got faster and faster and then a cloud came and I hid in it.
You could have crashed.
I was so fast that I would have jumped over it, but Peter stopped me.
So fast, that's enough. I'm already done.
Heidi, it's too dangerous. You'll stay here from tomorrow.
But that, but no, but...
Good morning, Piepmatz! Where were you yesterday afternoon?
Good morning!
Father, have you noticed that I can go with you today?
There are no big clouds in the sky and it doesn't hurt!
Heidi, I haven't changed my mind. It's not raining yet because it's still early.
I'm sure it's not raining.
Are you ready? Can we go?
I'm not allowed to go with you.
I'm sorry, Snuggie.
Grandfather forbade it yesterday.
Unfortunately.
Why is that?
He says the storms in autumn are too dangerous for me.
Goodbye, Snuggie.
Take care.
Go, go to your father.
She doesn't want to.
That's how it is, good boy.
Run fast.
I know, I don't want to.
I don't want to.
Grandfather, please let me go with Tina. They all don't want to go without me.
They're used to me. I've always been there.
I'm definitely not going today.
Once and for all, you stay here.
Come with me, Heidi. We'll light a fire and then we'll make cheese together.
We'll make the cheese ourselves?
That'll be fun. I've never seen that before.
I'm sorry, Peter, but you have to see that I can't come with you today.
Goodbye. We'll see each other on the way back.
I can get angry, but Peter is still much louder.
He's a hothead, he always was.
And what a guy!
And all of this because Heidi isn't coming with us today.
As a little boy, weren't you allowed to go to the pasture too?
All of a sudden, it started to rain.
The wind is so strong that it knocked on the door.
You were right, all of a sudden it was stormy.
Do you understand what I mean now?
Yes, but I would still like to go to the alps.
Listen to how that roars.
Those are our roosters.
Soon Peter won't be able to get up either.
Do you think it's dangerous for him and the goats today?
I'll go check it out.
Heidi often stood under the tall fir trees and listened to the rustle of the
branches.
She kept believing she could understand words and thought the fir wanted to talk
to her.
Until now, Heidi had always heard friendly words, but today the fir spoke to her
in a completely different way.
Heidi, come in. The wind is too cold.
Grandfather wants us to come in.
Tell me, are you talking to yourself or are you talking to the trees?
Neither of them. Peep must be hidden somewhere in the tree.
You and your bird. He won't come for sure. He will have hidden somewhere in
front of the wind.
He always comes when I call him.
Not today, Heidi.
The wind is too strong and too dangerous for him.
He can't handle his little birds.
You think so?
Then it doesn't make sense for me to wait.
Don't you have to warm them up and stir them?
Oh, don't worry, my child.
I'm already here.
Didn't you bring me a mixing spoon?
No.
Why would you need a spoon?
But didn't you say we'd do it together?
Just looking at it is boring.
See, now I can help you.
I stand on the shimmy very well.
Only the spoon is missing.
Why don't you give me a spoon?
How should I know which one I can't take?
You won't do it right.
Why? Every little child can stir in the milk.
I'll prove it to you. Give me your stick, please.
The milk will get very hot.
I know. I'm careful.
Yes, I can see that.
Ouch! What is it? Did you burn yourself? No, no, it just splashed.
So I can do it.
Stir evenly.
I know.
If you promise me to keep stirring and not stop, I can take care of the hay in
the meantime.
A lot has to be done today and you don't seem to need my help at all.
I really don't need you.
Are you the grandfather?
Probably not.
Who's there?
Then don't.
Somehow strange.
Where did you come from?
Don't yell at me right now.
I'm glad you're here.
But where are the others?
Tell me, Schnucki, did you run away from the herd?
You can't have run all the way from the alp to here by yourself
if you had broken a leg!
Oh, Schnucki, Schnucki, what a lovely little animal you are!
That's what I thought!
Wait!
No!
Possible, but the albino here said not to do it when she runs away.
I'm sorry. I didn't want that, Grandfather, I really didn't.
- What now? - There's nothing we can do.
We'll start from the beginning tomorrow.
I shouldn't have let it happen. It was way too hard for a little girl.
It's not that bad, either. Don't be so sad.
We'll milk the goats tomorrow and start over.
Heidi?
On this day, Heidi was very, very unhappy for the first time.
She had burned the milk and Peter had beaten her favorite goat, Schnucki,
although she had thrown herself in between to help.
Heidi felt helpless and useless.
She stood long under her tarp and hoped to hear a single comforting word.
But the branches rustled, dodged the wind and did not speak to her.
If only Heidi had known how she could tell her grandfather that it was not she,
but Schnucki, who was to blame for the burnt milk.
Without him being just as angry with Schnucki as Peter was.
I know what I'm doing now!
I didn't let the milk burn because I was too small, but because I paid attention
to a goat.
Unfortunately, I don't remember the name anymore.
So that's how it is.
She was in danger and I thought goats are more important than cheese.
You're not quite wrong.
At least you can have goats without cheese, but no cheese without goats.
The bill is almost up.
Was it nice on the pasture today?
No! You're not supposed to bite into my skirt!
I don't understand anything anymore.
Goodbye!
When Heidi got up the next morning, the fire was already burning in the living
room and over the fire there was already a bowl of fresh milk. Heidi was allowed
to help as much as she wanted, but this time the grandfather stayed close to her
to make sure that she would not let the milk burn again, to help a certain goat
whose name she could not say.
Tell me, are we going to make cheese again today, grandfather?
Many days in a row, the two of them processed the fresh milk of their goats into
large round cheese wheels.
And Heidi took her role as "cheese helper", as she called herself, very
seriously.
She cleaned and wiped and stirred, and again and again she reported to her tree
how many cheeses she had already produced.
She even forgot, out of enthusiasm, Peter, the goats and the pasture.
The days were getting shorter and shorter, the leaves were discolored, it was
autumn.
For Heidi it was time to say goodbye to a dear friend.
Piep joined a flock of birds to fly to the south.
And Heidi was distressed.
Peter tried to distract her with a new bird.
But Heidi wouldn't be Heidi if she had calmed down so quickly.
Again and again she wanted to know when and how she could see her Piep again.
But the hope that the next spring would bring back the singing birds was only a
weak consolation for her.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.