The summer was nearing its end, the first cold autumn winds colored the leaves
and on the mountain tops individual snow caps announced the winter.
Babe, where did you hide?
Have you seen Piep? He didn't wake me up this morning.
If you have no idea where he is, I haven't seen him this morning.
Peter? Have you seen my bird anywhere?
No.
Neither have you.
Why should I have seen him?
Piep didn't wake me up this morning for the first time.
Oh, you must have slept so hard today that he didn't wake you up.
He must have tried. Don't worry.
You don't look sad.
I can't find Piep anymore.
I see.
He comes here every morning. Do you think Falke might have caught him?
No, I don't think so. There must be a very simple explanation for that.
Why don't you play with it? You can build something with it.
Try it. It'll get you thinking differently.
I'll build a house with it. Thank you.
What do you have?
I think I heard a beep.
A beep?
Oh, what a pity. That's not a beep.
So it's gone.
Finally! You don't believe what kind of fear I had for you.
Because you weren't there, I fell asleep for the first time today.
Oh, what did I do to you?
Peep! Where are you flying to, Peep?
I don't understand. What's going on?
Come on!
Wake up!
What are you saying?
What is it?
I don't understand.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
I'm afraid I'll have to send Josef back.
Josef!
Joseph, why are you here?
Pee flew away this morning and I don't know why.
Why? I don't know what I did wrong.
He met other birds and they took him with them.
You're probably always tired.
Come with me, we're going back to the grandfather.
Tell me, did you run away from Peter again?
Snuggie! Don't yell at her like that!
She deserved it.
Why?
That's why.
I can't stand that she runs away without interruption.
She heard me.
Well, usually she runs away for no reason.
Just because she wants to.
You're going home pretty early today.
I know.
Do you want to come with me today?
No.
I can't.
Tomorrow is our birthday.
Our little bird flew away, Peter.
I don't believe that. He'll come back at some point. No excitement.
What do you mean, no excitement?
Piep was my best friend and now he's gone.
If he was your best friend, he'll come back.
You're mean!
Can't you just leave me alone?
Yes, if you don't give me anything to eat.
Don't you ever think of anything else?
Sometimes I'm thirsty.
Stop it!
You're really getting on your nerves.
Do you think your bird flew away forever?
Just off and away?
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Well, Heidi, have you found your little bird?
You have to understand your bird, Heidi.
What should one be able to understand?
I didn't do anything to him.
Summer is over, we only have autumn.
I know that, but it has nothing to do with the fact that Pete doesn't like me
anymore and has flown away.
Heidi, Heidi, how much more do you have to learn?
Of course autumn has something to do with your bird.
It's getting colder day by day.
Is it too cold for you?
Some birds can't survive in winter.
If snow and ice cover the ground here,
they won't find the food they need.
They have to starve and freeze here.
That's why they join up with large bird flocks
and fly to the south.
I understand what you mean, but do you think they'll come back?
Yes.
Hopefully.
If you're right, they'll come back in the spring, when the sun is warm again.
Tell me, Grandfather, what I've always wanted to ask you.
How is it that some birds live alone?
They're alone.
Falken live alone. And you live alone too.
You know what? You're like the Falken.
I was once alone like the Falken.
You must have forgotten that you're with me now.
Since then, I'm not alone anymore.
And besides, Joseph is still here.
Do you see it now? I'm not a falcon at all. I have you and Joseph with me.
Yes, we are three together with you.
And if we add Schwerinli and Berli, then our world is almost overfilled.
Sometimes Peter also visits us.
Then we are even six.
So many.
It won't get boring with us in winter. When will it snow?
You seem to have to learn something else. Patience.
I know, but you don't believe how difficult this is.
- She was so angry at me yesterday. - Nonsense, she's in the cabin, come on.
Did she say that I'm allowed to come?
- Tell me, General Ziegen, since when are you a coward? - I don't know.
Then you can take care of your goats.
All the best and a nice greeting!
I should say hello to Peter. Didn't you hear that he was there?
What's going on with you?
I suddenly don't like him anymore.
Oh yes, just like that, out of the blue?
Come with me, we'll go for a walk. I know a very nice spot.
Yes? Did you...
You have to stay here in the mountains this year.
Of course, we don't have a spring anymore.
This stupid Heidi should see where she gets her bird from.
I've never been here.
I don't know this forest at all.
Peter has never come here with me.
Because Peter doesn't know everything.
Where are we going?
Further and deeper into the forest
to the hazelnut bushes.
Are we going to pick them up?
You guessed it. That's why we're going there.
And that's why we have the rucksacks with us.
Does Peter know where the hazelnut bushes are?
No.
And he doesn't have to
because with his appetite he'll eat them all.
It worked!
I'll show you!
Stop!
Stop it!
You'll see!
Eat your grass!
Stop, stay here!
Stop!
Snuggly, leave my seeds!
No, watch out!
You're right!
It's actually your food.
What happened to my food?
You and the animals...
...I'll show you!
What happened?
No, look!
You and the animals...
...I'll show you!
No, look!
What happened?
Eat your grass, Schnucki! That's better for you! 吃你的草, Schnucki! 这比较好!
A bird! 一个小鸟!
Why are you flying away? 为什么跑掉了?
Not again! 再也不!
Oh, what a pity! 哦,可惜!
Look, this time I've even collected a whole pair of shirts.
There are so many of them here.
Do you think we can all wear them later?
My backpack is big, a lot fits in there.
A few fit in my backpack too.
Give me some, so you don't have to wear them all by yourself.
We have a long way to go.
Grandfather, what is that?
There's something hanging over there.
Over there, in the bush.
I'll go and get it.
I like this place.
There's so much to eat here.
Pick as much as you want.
They look delicious.
I'll pick them all.
Maybe Peter will open his eyes when I tell him about it tomorrow.
You should be able to see for yourself.
Yes?
The main thing is that it tastes good.
We can wash the face again.
That's one of a kind.
Too bad.
Did a bird fly by? I didn't want that. I wanted to catch a small bird. Then the
trap would have been enough.
Dear Joseph, good dog. Peter, good day.
- Good day, Heidi. - Good day.
I brought something with me.
I know, it's not as cute as your old bird.
But I caught it on my own.
But maybe you'll like it.
Look.
Peter.
Show me.
How cute.
Thank you, Peter.
I like it very much.
You think so?
That makes me happy.
Well, see you tomorrow.
One moment, Peter.
Yes?
Please, grandfather, keep it for me.
I picked it myself.
On my own.
All of them? So many at once?
That's not even everything.
Wait.
Take as many as you want. We have enough of them.
Open your bag.
May I really take you, Oehi?
And then I really wanted to tell you about yesterday. I'm sorry.
Me too, somehow.
So see you tomorrow!
Yes, we can definitely see each other tomorrow, Peter!
Goodbye!
Show him to me, Grandfather!
What a pretty little bird!
He feels so soft and warm and has such nice, smooth feathers.
What are you going to do with him?
Do you want to keep him or should I build a cage?
A cage?
You know, we have autumn.
Would you say that this bird also wants to fly in the south?
Yes, Heidi.
Yes, but...
He would stay in a cage. But I don't want to have a bird in a cage. Birds have
to be able to fly freely.
I'll let you free, little bird. Maybe you'll be able to pet us.
Have a good time.
Goodbye.
Heidi could not forget her little bird so quickly, but after a few weeks it
snowed in the mountains for the first time and that was a whole new exciting
experience for Heidi again.
Snow in the mountains. They snowed all the way to the roof and the almoehi had
to come up with everything possible to pass the time to the impatient Heidi.
When the sun finally came up behind the clouds again,
he showed his guard how to feed the deer,
and sometimes Peter also came to them through the snow.
But we'll tell you about that in our next story.