Autumn was nearing its end. Winter stood in front of the door. When Heidi went
to the fountain in the morning to wash herself, it was mostly bitter cold
Cold
Rub well, that's healthy
I can't help myself. I think the summer is better.
You won't be blown away.
It was so cold this morning, too. I almost got blown away.
How?
My nose is almost gone.
I think I'm blue everywhere.
And I'm rumbling. That's healthy.
Who says that?
Since when is freezing healthy?
Since today.
Snowflakes.
The first snow. It's snowing.
It's snowing, it's snowing, it's snowing.
I missed that, fortunately.
- Heidi? - Grandfather, come outside!
- Come with me, it started snowing! - Shit, I missed a starfish and not just
snow.
Look at that, white, fat flocks.
- So our winter begins. - Peter!
Soft white snowflakes!
They look like little white cotton stars.
It's snowing! It's snowing! It's snowing!
It's snowing! Even the window is snowed!
Minnie! Has something happened?
Yes, of course something has happened!
Haven't you seen that there is snow everywhere?
Everything is white, as white as a new bedcloth!
Even on my bed there is snow!
It has snowed. I will cover the hatch somehow.
But why? It is nice to sleep in a bed made of snow.
Even on top of the trees.
Come back to the house, Heidi. You're going to catch a cold.
Do the tree hats have snow so they don't freeze?
You should put on a hat too.
The trees are rustling.
The trees don't talk, I know that.
And yet I think sometimes they want to tell me something.
Do you think you can understand what they say, grandfather?
I can try.
But listen carefully.
No, I don't hear anything. But maybe I'm too old to hear trees talking.
What? Too old? Do you hear anything? I didn't even notice that.
I still have as good ears as a rabbit.
But they're not that long.
Come with me, Joseph. I'll show you something. Come.
How can you get out, Joseph?
Did you scare me, Joseph?
At least you're awake now!
Heidi, come into the hut now. The snow is too wet.
I'm not cold at all and the snow is not wet either.
Come in now anyway.
Oh no, why?
Peter hasn't come with his goat herder today.
He won't come. When it snows, the goats have to stay down.
They'll only come up to us again next spring.
You mean Peter won't come and visit us for the whole winter?
He'll stay down in the valley?
Grandfather, come quickly, it's over there.
Where is something? Show me.
Come here to me, then you can see it better.
Good.
It's a deer. He'll be looking for something edible.
Why don't we feed him when he's hungry?
It doesn't make any sense at the moment. These wild animals are very shy and run
away immediately when you approach them.
We're going to lay hay for him tonight. He can pick it up tomorrow morning.
The snow can't even get close to him. He stands under the tree like under a
roof. The branches protect him.
Shouldn't I get him some hay?
No, only later.
But I think he's taking it from me.
You think?
Well, if you're so sure about that, give it a try.
No, I have something to eat for you.
You don't have to be afraid, I won't do anything to you.
So he ran away after all.
Yes, that's him.
I wouldn't have done anything to him.
Heidi, when will you finally learn to have a little more patience?
Especially in dealing with animals, you need a lot of patience.
Put your hay where the deer was standing,
back there under the tree, and then wait.
Yes, I'll do that.
It's still a little dry there.
There he is.
Enjoy your meal.
Come on.
He hid behind another tree.
Now I'm curious.
It tastes good. And he didn't wait as long as I thought.
It snowed for many days. The sky was covered with thick snow clouds and you
could hardly see the roof a few steps away from the hut.
Heidi didn't mind. She had discovered a new occupation.
Every day she went to the big tall tree she always thought he would talk to her
and planted hay and grains for the animals in the forest.
For Heidi, the snow-capped mountains had their own special magic.
That's what you get for the others!
He ate my hand off!
I held his bowl, and he ate it all at once!
You've been patient.
I've got a new friend!
That's beautiful.
I've got a fre*
Grandfather, can you make it a little bit more similar? Can you make it a little
bit more similar?
Give it to me, I can try. Give it to me, I can try.
The main thing is that he gets an earring.
A head and four legs.
Looks more like a goat's butt.
Is it very heavy?
Because you like animals so much.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you!
This is the most beautiful day of my life!
I got a wood animal!
Don't you like your wood animal anymore?
Yes, but your Steinbock reminded me of the goat herd, and Schnucki, and Peter.
If only it was spring again, so I could see them all again.
The winter in the mountains is very lonely, my child. I know that well.
No, I'm not lonely. You and Joseph, you're here.
And my animals out in the forest.
So either the wind rolled at the door or there is someone out there.
At least it knocked very clearly at the door.
Maybe your deer will come to visit you, or the snowman you built yesterday
outside.
There, again.
Do you hear?
So I didn't get confused. There's actually someone in front of the door.
That can only be your snowman. Who should visit us up here in the middle of
winter?
In the hut he immediately smiles, the poor snowman.
Before I send him out, you should look at him first.
Oh, you're frozen stiff.
Come, sit down on the fire, Peter, to get up.
And slowly your nose will get a normal color again.
Since I know you, Peter, I know what you think.
What are you two still waiting for? Get started.
I'd love to.
The milk is hot, that's good.
Cheese tastes best with olive oil.
You can't go out with the goats any more. What are you doing all day?
If Peter has something to eat, you can't expect an answer from him.
Then you tell me.
You could come on your own. We're going to school.
Voluntarily? I didn't know you liked going to school.
Now you've swallowed yourself too.
Do you have to scare me like that?
Tell me, how is it at school? What does it look like?
The school looks like a house.
I see. And what do the people look like when they go to school?
Wait a minute. Let me think.
Well, they look...
Somehow, you know, they look like people.
Peter could not start too much with the school, he found it terribly boring and
he hardly gave himself the trouble to hide it.
Strangely, in the meadows in the summer, when he was out with his goats, he
always knew how to do the right thing, but here at school everything went wrong
with him.
If it doesn't want to go into the head, it has to go on it.
Heidi would certainly talk more there than all the teachers of the school
together.
I think it's very funny to go to school.
If only it were funny.
It's nice with you, up here in the hut, I like it there.
That makes me happy, Peter.
Did you get enough to eat with us?
No, I can always eat more, that's just the way it is.
I believe you, Peter, you'll never say that in your life.
What can I do about it?
Goodbye, Peter. That was a big surprise for me.
If you want, I can come back next Sunday.
On Sundays we're free from school.
Oh, please, yes. He wants to come back.
I'm looking forward to you, Peter.
I'll come for sure.
Nice.
Take care.
That was a beautiful day.
Heidi!
I almost forgot. My grandmother invited you to come to us once.
Me?
Yes, of course, you. Who else? Can you come?
Heidi didn't know what to say. She had never been invited.
Until now, she had never come up with the idea that anyone in the world, except
grandfather of course, would like to have her with them.
What's wrong with you? Have you lost your language?
Do you really mean that?
Or do you say "when I arrive at your place, April, April"?
Do you really mean it?
Can I say that you're coming?
But of course!
Good, then I'll pick you up!
That's your day today!
I wasn't invited. I'm allowed to visit someone.
Maybe there's even a homemade cake.
You haven't said anything yet?
Aren't you happy with me at all?
Can't I go, Grandfather?
Why don't you answer, Grandfather?
I thought about it.
I don't think I'll let you go alone with Peter. I'll take you with me.
Can I go? You don't say no.
Hooray! Hooray!
I hope it stops snowing soon.
The Alp Oehi couldn't share Heidi's joy.
He knew Peter's grandmother and he raised the same old roll against her as
against all the inhabitants of Dörfli.
Heidi knew nothing of all this. She just waited for it to finally stop snowing.
But it snowed and snowed for many days and many nights. Heidi became more and
more impatient, but then, one day, it was finally time.
When Heidi got up in the morning, it had stopped snowing. The heavy snow clouds
had disappeared, the sky was as blue as Heidi knew it from the summer, and the
sun was shining on the ice.
Heidi was finally able to paddle into the valley with her grandfather on the
sled and accept Peter's invitation.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.