Heidi dreamed every night of her visit to Dörfli, and every morning she woke up,
she was looking forward to it.
Good morning Heidi, did you fall out of your bed this morning?
When are we leaving?
I don't know what you mean, where do you want to go?
You don't know anymore? We're going down into the valley today.
Today? That's way too dangerous.
It was snowing and snowing, every day and every night.
Heidi became more and more impatient.
She tried to spend the time with all kinds of work.
She still fed her deer every day.
But she was only half-hearted.
Heidi finally wanted to go down into the valley.
Still? It will never stop.
Snow, snow, snow.
At some point it will stop again.
And then it was finally time. The heavy snow clouds disappeared.
The sky was again as blue as Heidi knew it from the summer and the sun glittered
on the ice.
Finally! It's not snowing anymore!
It's clear again!
Come on, Grandfather, come with me!
- Are we going down here? - No, Hattie, not today, maybe tomorrow.
But you said yourself, if it stops snowing, then we can go.
We would sink to the ice in the snow, it is still much too loose and much too
high.
I have eaten everything, except for the last crumb.
Then we can go now.
Where do we want to go?
You have to go three times.
To the valley?
Yes, to the valley. So come on, get up.
But pull yourself together, it's cold.
Of course, I am also the big waltz.
Hide it, you haven't seen it yet.
Are we both going to fit in there?
If you make yourself small.
Apparently your man will have to put you on, so come on.
It's nice and warm in here.
We can go now.
Hold on tight, so you don't fall down.
It's steep downhill.
Of course, I won't fall down, don't worry.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Does Peter live in there?
Yes.
But it's not nice here.
Before it gets dark, you'll be back home, understand?
But you're not coming in with me?
No, you're invited.
Hmm, that's right.
Peter?
are you ready, dad?
I'm from the Alps, Oei. Peter was recently with us and he invited me.
He said they wanted that.
Aha.
Today I could finally come.
So you're the little girl who wants to be a goat herder.
I'm glad you came, you're holy.
Did Peter tell you about the goat herder?
Yes, he often told me about it.
What beautiful warm hands you have, my child.
What is that?
Doesn't that bother you at all?
If you don't fix your window sill right away, he'll fall down for sure.
He's only hanging on a single thin nail.
I know, my child, I know.
He's been knocking for a long time, so terrible.
But what am I supposed to do?
Go and nail it. That's quite easy.
The house is already very old.
Here he knocks and knocks on all corners.
Maybe you can do something.
Look at him.
That's not possible.
I would like to look at him.
But I'm blind, Heidi.
Why don't you say anything, Heidi?
Did Peter forget to tell you
what's going on with his grandmother?
Yes.
I don't see anything anymore, but I hear every sound.
At night I often lie awake and listen.
And when the wind is howling around the hut and it's whistling everywhere,
then I sometimes get scared.
But that can't stay that way.
You have to do something about it.
It's all bad.
You get used to it over time.
It's all half as bad.
Sometimes I want to be able to see.
Then come...
Just go outside with me. Maybe you can see there. The sun is shining there.
No, no, Heidi. I can't see anything outside either.
No? Oh...
If a person is blind, Heidi, then he can't see anywhere. Not outside either.
That's not true.
Come with me anyway. You can't always sit here. It's really nice and warm
outside. Come on, I can show it to you. You have to come with me. You'll
definitely like it. I know it.
For me, it's better if I stay here in the hut, Heidi. I haven't been outside for
so many years, my child.
Then you're going out for the first time today.
How can a nice girl like you get so angry?
Sorry.
Don't worry Heidi, when I was a little girl, I was always angry too.
If I didn't like something, I always stepped on it with my feet.
You too?
You said that you can't see anything, but you also said that you can hear
everything.
So why don't you come outside with me in the snow and listen to the winter?
Why are you shaking your head back and forth? Don't you want to go outside at
all?
What a sweet little girl you are.
I can understand my Peter very well, that he likes you so much, but it doesn't
make any sense, Heidi. Leave me alone.
You can't do adventures with an old woman like me. It's too late.
Let me sit here on my spinning wheel, Heidi. That's the best thing for me.
Little Heidi.
What is good, Heidi?
Nothing is good. No, I don't want to.
Can't you really do anything to help you?
Can't you do anything so you can see again?
Nothing, Heidi.
Heidi, you can't imagine how many beautiful pictures I've seen in my long life.
And all these pictures live in me and I remember them.
Heidi was so happy to visit Peter's hut.
And now everything was completely different from what she had imagined.
Sometimes it's very hard to see something.
I've come up with something.
When I come home tonight, I will describe everything exactly to my grandfather.
From you and your clattering window shop.
Then he will come down to you in the morning and repair the hut.
If I ask him to, he will do it.
And then you don't have to be afraid anymore when the wind blows.
That's a very good idea.
You are a very, very nice girl, Heidi.
I'm glad you came.
Thank you very much.
Come in, Brigitte. We had a very surprising visit today.
That's Heidi, you know, the little one who's been living at the Almöhe since
last summer.
That's Heidi? She looks a bit like her mother.
She looked the same as a little girl. Are you doing well at the Almöhe, my
child?
Yes, I am.
He could have seen himself again in the village.
He wasn't here either.
He left the little girl at the door and then he left again.
Or did you come down all alone?
But no, the grandfather brought me on the sled.
That's unbelievable.
Our Almöhe was supposed to be on a sled with you?
We were so fast that the birds were not even faster than our sled.
Yes?
I don't believe that. The child has to go crazy. The moose and your sled, that
doesn't fit.
I know the old grasshopper. He can't even say hello anymore for years.
The grandfather is not a grasshopper! And if he doesn't say hello to someone,
then he has a reason for it!
He must have changed. Peter told me recently that he would be like an exchange
student, not to be recognized again.
An exchange student?
Peter said your grandfather would be very nice to you. He would like to have
you.
Yes, he did.
So, if that's true, then the world will turn around in a different way.
I only believe it when I've seen it.
Believe it.
Why don't you tell us about what's going on up there?
We'd like to know how you're doing and what you're doing.
I don't know where to start.
Just tell us everything that comes to your mind.
Well, I always get up really early in the morning and then I eat a huge mountain
of food for breakfast.
It's just wonderful that I can be with my grandfather.
I'm happy for you that you like it.
It's impossible to invent everything.
There has to be something real about it.
Strange.
She doesn't believe it.
Do you believe me at least or can't you imagine it?
Hello!
Peter!
Yes, tell me.
Where are you staying so long?
In the stupid school, of course. Where else?
How was your day at school today, Peter?
Is there anything to tell us?
Were you there today?
Yes, twice.
Did your answers to the questions you were asked
turn out to be the same as always,
or did you expect something different today?
At least half of it.
I knew something.
Yes, yes, I understand.
You didn't expect what you knew
from the teacher.
And of course you can't do anything about it that the teacher is so stupid and
doesn't know what you know.
Maybe he really can't do anything about it. Why are you so angry with him?
Oh, I'm just disappointed. Peter will soon be 12 years old and he still can't
read.
Brigitte, please give me the book.
It's a beautiful book. It's full of stories and poems.
And I finally want Peter to learn to read, to read it to me.
Unfortunately, I can no longer read by myself.
It's very difficult. Be careful that you don't drop it, Heidi.
It's my only book. I won't get another one.
Peter, you read it to me one year ago for the last time.
Try again. Maybe it's better now.
It's not better. It's even worse.
Then don't.
Soon the sun will set. Don't you have to get up slowly?
Yes, it's actually getting a little dark outside. I didn't even notice how late
it was.
Yes, the time has also passed quickly.
I would be very happy, my child, if you would come to visit me again soon.
Then come when I'm free from school. If you tell me when that is.
Thank you very much for letting me come today. I liked it very, very much here.
I'm looking forward to it, too, my child. Goodbye.
- Heidi? - Yes? Did I forget something?
- Didn't you bring a warm scarf? - No, I didn't have one with me.
You can't go without a scarf. It's too cold outside.
- Peter, tie mine to the child. - Thank you.
When I come to visit next time, I'll bring him back.
- Not so fast! - Come on, I can do it again.
Peter, take Heidi home and make sure nothing happens to her.
- It's always very smooth in the evening. - I will.
We're already careful.
Goodbye. See you soon. - Goodbye, Heidi.
Goodbye, Brigitte. - The old one.
Grandfather!
You look happy. It seems to have been fun. - Yes, it has.
Peter, you can take the scarf back with you. - Thank you.
Live well, Peter.
Oh, ruck! Tell your grandmother a nice greeting.
Yes, I will. - Live well!
You don't think that's possible.
I think I'm dreaming. What I saw out there can't be true.
Why are you so upset? - He picked her up.
That's good. So it's true.
Peter was right. He really likes the girl.
The almsman said I should say hello.
You should say hello to him? The child has changed him.
Yes, the little one knows how to deal with people.
You just have to like her, hopefully she'll come back soon.
Tomorrow morning we have to go down to the grandmother again and then we have to
take a hammer with us and a lot of nails.
You have to repair her window shops, you can do that.
I can and will not forbid you to visit these people, Heidi. But I don't want to
have anything to do with them.
Why? I don't believe that.
What has she done to you?
Who?
She can't even go to the house.
Grandfather, what do you have?
I don't know.
I've been wondering all this time, now it's time to wake up.
-Greetings, grandmother! -Heidi.
Why are you holding your head? Does it hurt?
Oh, come on, Heidi, get me into safety.
The hut is about to collapse. Oh dear, oh dear, that I have to experience that.
Oh, what? Have you already forgotten, grandmother?
I promised you yesterday that I would come down with my grandfather again.
My God, where are we going when the hut collapses?
-Greetings, grandmother! -Greetings, grandmother!
I can't hear anything. The noise is coming from the grandfather in my window
shop.
The Almö. Brigitte, did you hear what the child said?
The Almö came down there to repair my window shop.
I heard that.
Yes, that's what it sounds like when someone hits wood with a hammer.
Now everything will be fine again.
Now I finally don't have to hear this terrible squeaking all day and all night.
Do you hear the knocking, Brigitte?
Yes, of course I hear it.
Good morning, Almehuy. We are very grateful to you for this.
We would be very happy if you came in for a cup of milk to warm you up, Almehuy.
It is very kind of you to have come to help us, Almehuy. Thank you very much.
You've talked enough. Go back in.
I'm repairing the hut because the child asked me to, and for no other reason.
What are you still standing around for?
I understand.
He didn't want to talk to anyone.
Peter's grandmother was as happy and satisfied this evening as she has been for
many, many years.
The next day it snowed again and neither Heidi could go down into the valley to
visit Peter, nor could Peter climb up to meet Heidi.
Only when the weather got better, the two saw each other again and they had an
experience that Heidi could not forget so quickly.
Many days she thought of nothing else but her animals, which she thought were in
danger and finally she managed to convince the alp Oehi to go out into the
snowstorm to help.
But we want to tell you about this and the new adventures that Heidi experienced
in our next story.