♪
♪ Heidi ♪
♪ Deine Welt sind die Berge ♪
♪ Denn hier oben bist du zu Haus ♪
♪ Dunkle Tannen ♪
♪ Grüne Wiesen im Sonnenschein ♪
♪ Heidi ♪
♪ Brauchst du zum Glücklichsein ♪
♪ Halala-Eddie ♪
Ay, ay, ay, holly, holly, holly
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back again
It has been snowing for days.
Meters high snow covered the rocks and meadows and made it impossible for Heidi
to climb down into the valley to visit Peter's grandmother.
Every morning she wiped the ice flowers off the window and hoped that the sun
would finally rise again.
But she and her grandfather had to wait a long time for that.
The next day
What happened?
Don't worry, it's me.
It's still snowing like out of a bucket.
I thought it would be the child who visits me.
As soon as it stops snowing, she'll come.
You seem to like her very much, Heidi.
I do. She's so cheerful.
When it finally stops snowing...
Oh no, so that I can go outside again.
What am I supposed to play?
Dogs have good noses, don't they?
Does it smell good when the weather changes again?
You could open your eyes if I talk to you.
You've been living here for so long, grandfather.
Do you know when it stops snowing?
No. How should I know?
It's different every year.
Where is nobody? Have you ever tried to ask Schnee himself?
Yes, for years I did, if it didn't want to stop snowing.
And?
No matter how loud I called, he never thought to answer.
Did you just say the truth or do you want to take me on your arm?
Why don't you ask Schnee?
There's nothing to laugh about. That's exactly what I'm going to do now.
Snow...
A rabbit!
I'll be right back. I have to go outside quickly.
Have you been waiting for a long time? I completely forgot about you.
Take a look, for you.
Well, does it taste good?
Don't worry, there are also a few corns in it. Come down!
Grandfather, it stopped snowing!
It stopped snowing and under the big tree there are a lot of white rabbits!
Do you think I can go visit the grandmother again now?
I'm getting dressed.
No, not yet. We will have a snowstorm today.
But it stopped snowing.
Do not be disappointed.
Winter is hard in the mountains, Heidi.
When it snows here, it snows long.
Sometimes many days, sometimes even many weeks.
But you can see the sun.
But you can also see the clouds that tell us that we will soon get a snowstorm.
You will get to know all that.
The weather is not good. Look at the mountains.
They look like you could grab them with your stretched arm.
Then I have to warm the bunnies.
Please let me down from my arm.
I'll be right back. It won't take long.
You, a snowstorm in the mountains, Heidi, is dangerous.
Please hurry up. It can start soon.
Yes, I'll do that.
I'll be right back.
I'm sorry for you. You have to go home quickly.
Grandfather said we'd get a snowstorm soon.
What was that?
What's going on?
A dog!
Come here!
Do it right away, you disgusting dog!
Joseph! Joseph! Come back!
That's enough! He won't dare to come here again!
Thank you, Joseph! You did a good thing!
Now you are sure. Nothing can happen to him. The dog is gone.
You tickle me when you lick. Did the dog hurt you?
Here Eberhard! Here!
The dog has stung a deer.
Go to the side, that's our deer.
Now do it, that's dangerous. Why are you standing there as if you had hit the
roots?
Go away!
I'm not going!
Nothing else will remain here, so go now, do it!
Our dog has stung it, it belongs to us.
No!
If you do what we tell you, then I have something for you.
You can keep that!
Now get out of the way or you'll get to know me!
No! Do what they say!
Go!
Then I can't help you anymore. I've never seen anything as stubborn as this.
If you want to shoot the deer, you have to shoot me first!
Heidi, you don't know what you're saying! They're really doing it!
Then they should!
Stop with the nonsense! Can't you ever give up in life?!
The boy knows what he's talking about!
Come here, Mr. Heidi! Just one step to the side!
No, I don't think about it at all! I stay where I am! This deer is my friend!
That's enough for me! Go to the side or I'll shoot!
They're not doing that!
Heidi, no!
-No! -Should I count to three?
One!
-Baaah!
-Well then...
She doesn't seem to be afraid of guns at all.
-Oh, I don't know what else we can do now.
I think we'd better give up Eberhard.
Let's go.
-Oh, that's a nice idea.
Don't move, we're taking a break.
-Ah, I'll be right there.
-Run fast, but look for a dense bush, okay?
I have to be your friend? That wasn't very nice of you.
You know very well that I earn money in winter...
Go away and be careful!
Did you understand what I just said?
I'm not for it when it came to me. I didn't choose it as a friend.
Always the same with your animals.
Apparently they are all your friends.
Couldn't you give something up for me?
No, I couldn't do that!
Oh man...
May we come in? A break would be good for us. It's cold outside.
We should stop for today. It doesn't make any sense anymore.
No, we were talking about deers in the village.
I'll only give up if I get one in front of the gun.
Not before.
God bless you, Peter.
God bless you. Are the two of them really in your hut?
Close your eyes, then you can see them.
And you two should come in now.
You're welcome. It's cold.
There's two. There's another one.
Oh, that looks pretty good. We could do something too, the two of us.
We'd like to pay for it. What do you want, old man?
There's not enough there for everyone.
What? But there's still enough cheese piled up back there.
I said there's not enough there.
They said it in the village.
Hold on, children, and let it taste good.
Thank you, Grandfather, it will surely taste good.
I'm hungry.
I need the chair.
Yes?
Didn't you understand me?
Yes, that's good.
You're right, down in the village. The old man is really crazy.
I first thought it was nonsense.
That's no wonder. He's been living here alone for years.
That's how it is.
Come on, boy, we want to go on.
A little faster. We don't pay you to sit around and eat.
We have to catch at least one deer.
I'll be right there. I just want to eat it.
We'll wait outside.
Maybe we should forget about the deer and go to Steinböcke.
What? But there's going to be a snowstorm.
You have to go home. The grandfather said so.
A snowstorm in the mountains is very dangerous.
You have to be safe right away, right?
Yes, that's right.
It can only last a few hours, and then it starts.
What did I tell you?
With the old man, it doesn't really tickle in the head anymore.
The sun is shining outside, and he's talking about the snowstorm.
Maybe you'll be like that in the mountains.
Disgusting!
I think so, too.
Stand up!
We've already told you that you won't be paid for sitting around.
Should I break your legs?
For my sake!
I can't go on with it anymore! I'll stay!
Can you forget your payment?
Good-bye!
We can't just let them go!
Stay here! Don't go on on your own!
If the grandfather says there's going to be a snow storm,
then there really is going to be one!
It's too dangerous!
Now you seem to be fantasizing too, little one.
Then look at how close the mountains are. The weather doesn't last long anymore.
Yes, yes, that's good, little one.
I can see him! He's running over there!
I think you've shot him lightly!
Cut him off!
Come here! Here's a trail of sweat!
The man is sea, he makes us trouble, but why is it snowing again?
Georg!
Yes, we have to turn around. If it continues to snow, we will soon no longer see
the hand in front of the eyes.
Strange.
We can not give up now, I have almost caught the Steinbock.
The dog has him.
I do not know right, I do not like the weather at all.
Where are you hurrying?
Tell me, should we turn around? I can't see anything anymore.
Why turn around? I think we've been on our way home the whole time.
What are you waiting for? The storm won't stop so quickly.
What a waste!
What's going on for so many hours? I know that.
Tell me, are you scared because you look so shocked?
No, but the hunters haven't come back yet.
Hopefully they can hide out there somewhere.
Stop breaking their heads over the two of them.
They didn't deserve it any other way.
It has nothing to do with it. It's dangerous out there.
You've said it many times, but they didn't want to hear it.
They should see how they're being made out there.
They should show how clever they are.
They should see how clever they are.
That's not the right way. We have to go the other way.
What? You've been saying that for two hours.
Give me some rest and follow me.
My piece of wood will be the tip now. Don't move.
What are the hunters doing now?
I'm sorry, but I have to think about the two of them all the time.
Too bad. This time he will definitely stay standing.
If they run away, they will freeze.
And they have run away, I know that.
If they had found the right way, they would have come by our hut again.
Then finally stop. There are other ways down into the valley.
The stupid thing is, slowly it will be time for me to go too.
Be careful, please don't run away.
Don't worry, this is not my first snowstorm.
Up here I know myself, after all, I grew up in the mountains.
Still, I have a very stupid feeling.
Oh, what?
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Aren't you afraid that something will happen to the two hunters?
Where are you going?
Please stay with Heidi for a moment until I'm back.
Yes, that's fine. I'd love to.
I can go home a little later.
Where are you going now?
I want to see the two hunters again.
Oh, thank you, Grandfather.
I'll find them.
Joseph, come on.
You lazy bug.
Get in motion.
Be careful, Grandfather. Please.
Hello! Hello! Hey!
Oh, it's cold outside.
Come on, you two, into the water!
The goats must have been too cold in the stable.
They should have warmed up in the fire.
And then we will milk the two.
Hopefully you both had at least a successful hunt.
Thank God you're here.
If you fall asleep now, you'll freeze.
Come to your senses at last.
The two of them are back where they belong.
If the grandfather comes home, he'll be happy about it.
Help!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Don't you think the grandfather will stay away for a long time?
Nothing will happen to him, will it?
I don't know.
That's Joseph's grave!
You think so?
But of course!
-Almi! -Grandfather!
Yes, they're coming over there!
-Grandfather! -He found the two jellies!
Hurrah!
Grandfather, you're finally here!
I was so afraid of you!
Go slowly, Grandfather!
I'll come and help you!
We also set a pot of milk on fire for you!
In which hole did they bury the two of them?
Was it dangerous for you? Did you get off the road because it took so long?
No, I had Joseph.
Everything went well, don't be afraid, my child.
I'm so happy. If hunters come again, we won't let them go.
Peter spent the night on the hut and when the sun rose the next morning, he and
Heidi roamed down into the valley
Goodbye grandfather, until tonight
The two hunters stayed at the Almöhi for a while to get rid of their fright
Almöhi, I'm sorry, we've been pretty stupid
We behaved like little children
Children behave more reasonably, they listen
I'm not used to it from you, you're all like that, you believe you belong to the
world
If Heidi hadn't been there, the Alp Öhi wouldn't have looked for the two of them
But that's why he didn't have a bad conscience for a long time
He couldn't do anything with these Steters, who make the mountain world insecure
with their guns at the weekend
He just didn't like them and he didn't keep it a secret
He knew that he couldn't forbid them to hunt when they had a hunting license
But he himself didn't want to have anything to do with it
Grandmother, we're here!
When the sun was shining, Heidi had a lot of fun in the snow.
She wandered with Joseph through the white winter landscape and took a lot of
time to teach her beloved tree how to speak.
Even if she herself didn't really believe that she could do it.
She was on her feet all day to discover something new.
And on one of these streaks she saw the first signs of spring.
Of course she had to describe Peter's grandmother in every detail.
But that wasn't the smallest detail in her vivid description.
She told us about the flowers and the melting water, about the Alp Oehi and
about her animals.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.
To be continued