Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark pines
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Holadio
Thanks for watching
Like, Share and Subscribe
Joseph, what's going on?
- -
Hello, Joseph.
Now you've already thrown everything down for the second time!
Wait!
- -
Stop, Joseph! Wait!
I'll catch you! Now stay here!
Now I'll catch you!
That's what happens when you don't bark!
No! You can't catch me!
I won't give you any trouble!
Stop! Help!
This child!
I'll catch you!
No, Joseph! Stop!
Slowly!
Wait!
Hello, Joseph!
Stop licking my hand! You know it tickles!
Grandfather, come here!
Look at our tree!
That's...
Nice. It glitters everywhere and sparkles like a thousand stars.
And listen to how it roars.
He'll talk to me at some point.
Nice, Joseph.
So, what did I tell you?
He'll talk to us.
If you want to catch me, you have to come up with something, Joseph.
Come on, what are you waiting for?
Stop it, you two!
Come in! You haven't even had breakfast!
We have to go!
I'm coming! I have to wash my hands first!
Come on, Joseph!
Sven, don't be so shy about the water. You could take a swim.
It's not a big deal.
It's so cold.
Where are you going? Come here!
Oh, the snow.
The snow is melting.
Come here quickly! There's a flower here!
A flower.
Joseph, smell it. It smells like spring.
Now it's going to get warmer every day.
Have you ever seen such a beautiful flower?
Let's go and get Grandfather.
The first flower, the first flower!
Come with me, I have to show you something.
Come on!
Why are you so excited again now?
Look!
I think spring is coming.
That's it!
Tell me, have you ever seen such a beautiful flower?
That's what happens to us every time in spring.
Don't you like the flower? I think it's very beautiful.
Of course I like it.
With the first flower you always think it's the most beautiful.
I'm glad that the winter is over and spring is coming.
I will come here every day and see if she is doing well and if she has grown a
bit.
Hm? What is that?
It's thundering like in summer.
What's that?
There's an avalanche going down.
That's also a sign that it's going to be spring.
It was warm a few days ago.
First the snow starts melting
and then it slips off.
And what then?
First it's just a little snow.
Then it gets more and more snow
and finally an avalanche.
Avalanches are very dangerous.
So be careful whenever you hear this noise.
And now come.
Dangerous?
You know what, Joseph? We're just going to clear the avalanches.
We're going to clear the avalanches.
Heidi!
Peter is there! I have to...
I'll show him my flower right away.
First breakfast.
Sit back down on the table.
Your flower won't run away from you.
Very well.
Do you always sleep, Joseph?
Where did you get the flower?
You found a spring flower, Joseph.
That's the first one I get to see this year.
Good morning, Peter.
Good morning, Heidi. Look what I found.
Thank you, but that's...
Why did you tear the flower out?
I didn't do that.
What did I do wrong again?
I found it.
It's not my fault!
You tore it out! Say something!
Joseph?
I didn't fall in!
Is that all?
- What is it? - This dog.
Please, Peter, give me the flower.
- It needs water. - Oh, it's already completely wilted.
General Siegen, have you had enough breakfast this morning?
I have had breakfast.
But my stomach could bear something.
That would have surprised me if it were different.
I'm just always hungry.
No, come on.
When I was as old as you, I was always hungry too.
Thank you very much, Mr. Peter.
How can you get such pieces in your mouth at once?
So your mouth must be the biggest mouth in the world.
It's not that big.
Oh, there it is again.
It's thundering. There must be another avalanche going down the mountain.
Have you ever seen one?
Peter!
Stop it now!
But I'm not even full yet.
You'll never be full!
You can eat from morning till evening!
We're at least as fast as birds. We're flying!
We're flying!
Stop the cut, Peter! I saw something over there!
What did you say?
You should be on fire!
Wait a second, I'll be right back!
I've got something!
Oh, now you've plucked it. But that's why you yelled at me earlier.
That's only the second flower of spring.
You always come up with an answer.
I'm curious what Grandmother says.
We've arrived!
Is Heidi with us?
Of course I'm here.
Good day, Brigitte. How are you today?
I brought you something.
What did you bring me?
A flower. We found it in the snow.
That's right. It's finally spring.
How well it smells.
You made me very happy with that.
That's what I thought.
I knew you liked the flower.
Now it's going up again.
Heidi brought a snowflake.
The spring is coming.
Did you notice, Brigitte?
I don't have time to think about something like that anymore.
I know you always have a lot to do, Brigitte.
But for the first snowflake, you should be able to take some time.
You're right, Grandmother.
Thank you for that. You're pretty stupid.
I didn't want to hurt you, Heidi. It's very, very beautiful.
I don't think anyone else cares about me here.
Let's get out of here.
From me.
We have to go.
Goodbye, Grandmother. I'll be back very soon.
Don't come back as late as yesterday, Peter.
What kind of a lovely girl is this Heidi?
Stop! No, Heidi! You can't do that normally!
Why shouldn't I be able to do that? It's so easy.
You sit on it and control it with your feet.
Please, if it's that easy...
I'll show you. You'll be surprised how good I can do it.
And off we go!
Now we're getting faster! And now to the curve!
Watch out!
Peter, we're getting too fast!
Peter!
Ouch!
What do you say?
How did you drive?
Ohhhhhhh...
Ahhhh!
Ahahaha!
Watch out, without the tail!
Stop it!
Ouch!
No!
Hurray!
Hooray!
Watch out!
Ouch!
Ahhhh!
If you ask me again how you were driving, I'll scream!
How was I driving?
Well, you snails, where do you want to go so slowly?
You have to prove that you are faster!
Watch out!
If I catch you!
And if you catch us!
I'm curious about that!
That's it. The strange thing from the Alp.
What do you mean, the strange thing?
If you live with the old man, you have to be strange.
- You're stupid. - She's cheeky.
Even pretty cheeky.
- Tell me, is that right with you? - Leave her alone, I warn you!
You slug, what do you want?
Is it fun to play with girls?
Do you already wear a skirt and a nice hat?
And pretty white socks?
Girlfriend, girlfriend, girlfriend!
What does "girlfriend" mean?
Shut your mouth, you scoundrel!
Do you want me to beat you up?
Shut up!
Why are you so angry?
Is it Heidi or is it not her?
It's none of your business.
He only feels so strong because the girl is with him.
Usually he runs faster than his goats when it gets dangerous somewhere.
And you're overtaking me.
Oh dear, oh dear, oh dear.
Now he's about to start crying too, the poor little one.
Oh nonsense.
I would apologize at your place.
Only if we go around the bet.
Fine, we can do that.
If we win, then you apologize at our place.
Dismissed.
But don't make any hope yet. You'll never win.
We're the fastest anyway.
Don't drive on the tree.
Let me steer. If I sit in the front, then we'll make it.
Never!
- Don't you want to fight? - It's our business how we drive!
Then you don't want to win today at all!
Only beginners push!
The first one to reach the market place first wins.
The ride is going to be wild. Hold on tight, okay?
Yes.
Let's go!
One, two, three!
Oh, they're so slow!
Goodbye!
We haven't shown you what we're capable of!
Then don't think about it for too long!
Are you having a breakfast break or where are you staying for so long?
Now you have to come up with something and you're stuck!
We have to win!
Stop!
Goodbye!
That's how it's supposed to be!
We won!
Hurray!
Well, that's it then.
Heidi!
Up here!
You're right.
Hurry up!
I should have let you lie down.
You're alive, Peter.
I hope it didn't hurt.
Peter!
We won!
That doesn't matter.
A little bit, yes.
Where are you staying?
You wanted to win, didn't you?
If only they would fall into an ice-cold stream.
I want to know how Schnucke and the goats are doing.
Huh?
How did you come up with that?
I don't know either. I just came up with it.
Come on, let's go visit them, okay?
Today, where we've lost them, you're going to visit the goats?
You might have some ideas.
We'll visit the goats next time. We have to go back now.
We'll visit the goats next time.
It's starting to rain.
The bots are pitch black. We have to see that we can get into the forest as
quickly as possible.
Where are the two of them?
It's pouring out of the buckets! We have to hurry! Come on!
Heidi! Peter!
Peter! Heidi!
Head up, you're holding on.
My legs are made of lead.
Thanks for watching!
Thank you for your time.
Come on, Peter, over here!
There comes the old man!
Peter, quick!
Now we can't drive anymore. Our beautiful snow is gone.
Where does so much water come from all of a sudden?
So you're asking questions.
But where does the water come from when the snow melts?
The winter couldn't resist the spring anymore.
From day to day it got warmer and the air was full of the bird's chirping.
Where the snow had already melted, the first grass tips appeared.
And spring flowers started to bloom everywhere.
Soon the last drop of snow would have disappeared too.
Heidi continued to feed her deer, even though they had been able to find their
own food for a long time.
The next day
The two are as happy as we are about the spring.
Heidi experienced her first spring up here in the mountains.
She stood up every morning with the sun to not lose a second of the day.
For her, one experience was more exciting than the other.
She was overworked and overjoyed.
Like in summer, Peter came up to the meadows again with the goat herd.
And together they spent unwavering days in the meadow.
Heidi met her favorite goat Schnucki again.
And calculated whether none of her friends were missing.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world is the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.