Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark fir trees
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Holadio
Peter, wake up!
Hurry up!
Yes, I'm coming!
Tomorrow!
Is it true that you got a few more goats this year?
Yes!
There I am again!
Hello Peter!
Peter, so you're leaving this year as well?
-Morning, Peter! -Good morning!
-This time I'm taking the white one with me. -Yes, that's good.
Hello, Schnucki, you haven't grown up yet.
Finally, I don't have to go to school.
I don't have to go to school.
Good morning!
Since when have you been...
Slowly it will be time for you to get up, you sleeping hat.
Here comes Peter with the goat herd.
Good morning, Joseph, get up!
Good morning, Svenli, good morning, Berli.
No, not again, no!
Why do you have to be so wild?
Let it be!
You also know that it goes back to the pasture.
Berli, Berli!
Fuck!
You can jump better than me!
The bells!
Down there Peter and his herd are coming up the slope!
Peter!
Heidi!
Faster than running!
Oh yes!
I roll and roll and roll and roll and roll!
I roll and roll and roll!
Heidi, stop it now!
Don't be so over-tired, Heidi!
If you hit your head...
Now you can't go to the meadow with me!
Mhm.
Peter! Heidi!
Finally! The goat herd!
There's my Schnucki again!
Schnuckilein!
Dear Snooki, I wanted to come visit you in the winter, but unfortunately it
didn't work out.
Good day!
Well, how are you?
And you're back again!
No! Leave that alone!
Now we're all together again!
All summer long! I'm so happy!
Are you also looking forward to our meadows, Peter?
I can't even...
We have to wait until we finally go up.
Of course, and how?
Then let's all listen to each other well!
Come on!
Don't run so fast!
Stop! Wait!
Peter!
Good day, Mr. Oey!
So it's starting again now, General Ziegen?
Uh-huh.
Will you take that with you, Peter?
The saint has forgotten it. You know what.
Where are you staying?
Go on, Peter, and take good care of her.
In the meantime, I'm going down into the village to buy in.
Tell him that, please. I'll be back on time.
Yes, that's fine.
Thank you, Mr. Oey.
Like last summer, Heidi went up to the meadow with Peter and the herd of goats.
Heidi loved this ascent. She had been waiting for it for so long.
There, Peter, look! There are two squirrels up there!
A bird swarm!
The first birds are coming!
I don't know if Piep is here.
Hello Piepmatz!
Oh, what? Why is he supposed to be there?
Peep, do you not know me anymore? It's me, Heidi!
Tell me, is there a bird among you called Peep and sometimes Peepmatz?
He must be there. He looks exactly like you.
I'm Heidi.
Do you know him?
Tell him that I haven't forgotten him and that I'm waiting for him.
Search for him for me! Fly away!
Ask everywhere, please!
Heidi firmly believed that she would see the little bird she had raised last
summer again one day.
Exactly! You'll find him for sure! You have to find him!
They will find him and they will tell him about me and then he will come back.
Just like I said, he came back.
If he came back, he should be here somewhere. I don't see him.
Of course the others have to inform him first.
Inform him?
Of course, how should he know?
You know what? You're just right!
You're just right!
Hahaha!
Juhu!
Yes!
Hahaha!
Juhu!
I won!
Hahaha!
Even the little flag is there,
where it always stood.
Are you sick or why are you lying on the floor?
As healthy as today!
I haven't seen you for a long time!
Peter, wake up! There's an eagle flying up there!
It's big!
Wake up! When can you see an eagle?
Fly around here until Peter wakes up!
Oh, there's still snow here!
But that's cold! Ice cold!
There are two standing back there and they're paying attention!
But they're not just two!
Oh, they're morphing animals!
And I've already wondered what they were!
They were just as afraid of me as I was of them.
But there's still a lot of snow here.
The spring must have forgotten that.
What's going on down there?
That would be steep if I fell down there. A stonebuck!
That was wonderful! You can climb!
What a beautiful animal!
* Music *
*Sigh*
Heidi?
Just...
She was still here.
Heidi!
Heidi, where are you?
Where have you been?
Just tear it out.
Hurry up!
Tag!
You shouldn't run away. What if you crash?
Guess what I've got. A flower wreath.
I've got one for you too.
For me? Hmm. Nice.
Here, you can hang it around your neck.
No, no, thank you.
Why not? They've become beautiful.
I've wove them evenly.
No, that's not it.
Well.
There. The wreath fits you well.
The wreath, really. It fits you.
- Now I look like a phoenix. - Oh, really?
- Yes. - You look very good in it.
- Much better than before. - Maybe.
I like it quite a lot.
I still hope no one sees me in it.
What is she doing?
Here, Schnucki.
There, Perli. There's something for you.
- Tell me, what are you doing? - You can see it.
I hope you like it.
Take a look at this one!
You have to keep it!
But please don't eat it!
This is the most beautiful goat herd in the whole world!
Heidi was as overbearing as ever. She would have loved to have embraced the
whole world.
She jumped and sang and danced and wanted to jump higher than the goats.
The snow had not yet melted everywhere, but the summer had begun for her.
You might look stupid.
The weather is changing!
- Why is it so dark all of a sudden? - A thunderstorm!
Why is it so dark all of a sudden?
It stopped again!
Yeah, I saw it!
Peter, we suddenly have a little sheep.
It's very nice, but it doesn't belong to us.
It will have run away during the thunderstorm, that's all.
Who do you belong to, little sheep? Tell me!
Alma!
It must belong to another herd, and if there is a herd here, then there is also
a herd, and he will look for it.
He comes here, finds the sheep with us, and thinks, of course, we stole it from
him.
But we didn't steal it!
Alma! Give the sheep back to you!
It ran away in the rain.
What is it?
Come here, I'll show you how to run away!
It didn't do anything!
Stop it!
Don't interfere, it doesn't concern you at all!
It does concern me.
I'll show you the only thing you can put your nose into, you shameless beast
thief!
Or do you want to tell me you didn't steal it?
Of course I didn't steal it!
We can't do anything about it, it got lost in the thunderstorm, it came all by
itself!
I know what I see, and that's enough for me!
That's not enough at all, because it's just not true!
Does anyone have any more words?
Is the little one really messing with me?
Tell me, are you sure that you're not sick in the head?
Are you sure of yourself?
Stealing animals from other people and then being cheeky,
that fits both well together.
We didn't steal at all!
You're probably just as crazy as your grandfather.
If anyone here is crazy, then you see!
What?
Someone who hits a helpless animal with such a big nipple,
must be crazy!
That's not normal!
Say that again, huh?
What do you understand about goats and herds?
You can see right away that you belong to the circus!
Take your fingers away!
Let it go, it belongs to Peter!
Let's see!
You mean, old, disgusting man!
Don't be shy, or I'll forget about you!
Come here, you little brat!
I'll pay for that!
I'll catch you!
And now watch how you get out of here, you little brat!
I'll beat you so hard you'll never play again!
Are you crazy?
Let go of my arm, you little turtle!
Let go!
Stop it!
I'll show you, my son!
Ouch!
Let go of him!
Don't touch me!
He's supposed to bite you!
What? Who's that, Joseph?
It's a giant dog! It's at least three times as big as you!
With such a mouth!
It's standing back there!
Where? Where is your dog?
I don't see any.
There is no dog here!
You have lied!
Joseph, you heard me cry! I was here!
Help! Help! Help!
Joseph! My dear Joseph!
Alma!
Alma, get in motion and come at last!
Alma, go!
Go!
Now go to him. He won't dare to beat you anymore.
But the dog there, it should stay there!
But Joseph can't do anything to your dog. It looks like that.
The End
It's all right. Why are you so upset?
Grandfather! I'm so happy to be back home!
You're back again? Weren't you in the village?
You don't believe how Joseph helped me.
Was it dangerous?
Yes.
Then tell me, I'm curious.
Peter had an incredible fight earlier.
Yes, but what are you hiding there?
Guess.
That could be a hat.
I brought it for you.
My own hat.
I have a hat for myself.
I have to show it to Peter right away.
Where is it?
You haven't told me the story to the end yet.
How do you like my new hat?
Don't I look like a lady?
No, still like Heidi.
I don't care if you like it.
I like my hat and that's the main thing.
I like it, I like it, I like it.
Heidi had once again found a reason to jump around and show everyone how happy
she was
Of course she was incredibly proud of her hat
She walked around with it all evening and decided never to take it off again
Already the next morning Heidi stowed her hat carefully in the closet, to raise
it for special occasions.
She wanted to walk over the meadow with her goats undisturbed and not be
distracted by a hat in the many adventures she experienced with Peter.
Heidi began long conversations with her tree and sometimes she dreamed badly at
night.
She often had the feeling that something would happen in the near future that
she could not be happy about.
Everything was still as usual. She climbed around the mountains with Peter and
was sometimes a little naive, but still, something bothered her.
But we want to tell you about that in the next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back home.