Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio
Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Peter, faster! Where are you staying so long?
Heidi and Peter went up to their favorite pasture with the goats this morning
For Heidi everything seemed to be the same as always
She was happy and unharmed
Peter on the other hand was very worried
If I only knew how to teach her that again
Snooki, watch out! You're tearing a hole in your skirt! Watch out!
Snooki!
Is there really nothing else for you besides this goat?
And besides, I'm here to eat and not to play! You should know that!
What's wrong with you, Peter? You're not that angry!
Come on, tell me!
It doesn't concern you?
Of course it concerns me. I'm your girlfriend.
You're just making that up!
You're weird.
Peter was not angry, he was worried. He wanted to tell Heidi something and did
not know how.
This morning he had heard something down in Durflea.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Don't worry, Snuggie is not there yet.
Didn't anyone tell you that she won't come with us today?
Yes, why is that all of a sudden?
I already thought that you were scared when you heard it. You can imagine what
will happen. She is to be sold.
No! Why?
I don't know. I haven't heard anything.
She will come after all.
- Good morning. - Here we are.
Greetings, Peter.
Is it true that you want to sell Schnucki?
Yes.
Then you already know. I can't keep her anymore.
It's her last summer.
She grows and doesn't grow.
That doesn't matter.
It takes longer with her. She will grow.
I don't think so.
Don't eat and don't give milk.
Peter, back there on the rock, what is he looking for?
Peter, what have you found? Show me.
Some herbs. Please take them.
Let them fall.
I've got them. They smell really good.
And what are we going to do with the herbs now?
Now I don't understand you at all. What's going on with you?
First you yell at me because I play with Schnucki and then you climb up the
rocks yourself and harvest some herbs for her.
Come on, let's go eat.
What's wrong with you?
Did you have a bad night's sleep?
I never sleep well.
But still, you have something today.
You're as bad-tempered as ever. I don't even know you like that.
What does it matter to you how I am?
Peter, what's going on today?
Don't you want to tell me why you're in such a bad mood?
I have to tell you at some point.
What do you have to tell me?
Schnucki is being sold.
Sold? Our Schnucki?
Yes, our Schnucki is being sold to the butchers.
No, I don't believe that. I just don't believe that.
You can't allow that. We can't allow that.
We can't do anything.
They say she doesn't grow.
That's why she would never give me milk.
Believe me, it's pointless.
I won't let that happen. They can't do that.
Why won't you think of anything, Peter?
Why don't you think about it?
Snuggie is my favorite goat.
What do you think I'm doing? I don't care. I don't know what to do.
No, you can't do that. It can't be. It just can't be.
I like Snuggie so much. Doesn't it bother you at all?
Of course it does! Do you think I'm made of wood?
Poor Snuggie, poor Snuggie.
You're not allowed to do that.
You're not allowed to do that. I won't let you do that.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
They want to sell Schnucki to a butcher.
Why don't you say anything?
I told you that something was wrong with you.
You make a face like it's going to rain.
I just told you something. Did you really listen to me?
Schnucki is being killed and you're making a face like it's going to rain.
Yes, I'm doing that.
In the countryside, goats are kept to milk them and not to love them.
Goats have to give milk.
- No, no, no, no, no. - But, Heidi, it can't be changed.
We keep the goats to give them milk, and then we make cheese out of it.
And then we sell the cheese or exchange it.
- Where else should we live? - I don't care where we live!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Heidi, go to bed now. It's late.
Heidi, I talked to you.
You can't do anything to him, grandfather. You know everything else.
No, Heidi, not this time.
Schnucki doesn't belong to us and I don't have the right to interfere.
There are things you have to deal with.
Oh, calm down, Heidi.
I don't even think about calming myself down.
Sometimes you have to be able to make an exception.
Snooki, come here, come!
No, don't hit me!
No, don't! Stay here! Don't take me away!
No, no!
Schnucki!
It's my goat! Where are you taking it?
You can't do that! No!
Schnucki!
Schnucki, stay with me!
Heidi!
Come here, my child.
- They took her away. - No, no one was taken away yet.
You just had a bad dream, Heidi.
A strange man beat her and pulled her away.
Be quiet, child.
Possible. Maybe it was just a dream today.
But that's just the way it is.
- Drink this, then you'll feel better. - Thank you.
Should I get you another cup?
No, you can't do anything.
You really don't like it, grandfather?
Not even if you really think about it?
It can't be!
There's only one way to help.
We have to improve the milk.
Is that possible?
I can't promise you anything, but we'll try.
What do we have to do? Tell me!
Feed her if she doesn't want to eat.
You think she'll take it?
Yes.
She'll definitely take it from you. She likes you and she trusts you.
But look for the best herbs and the freshest grass for her.
Peter picked herbs.
That's good. Yes, Peter understands what goats are.
The herbs that grow the most are the best.
I know what you mean. You mean the herbs with the wide leaves that smell so
good.
They grow so high that the goats don't even get close to them.
Leave the grass to Peter.
I don't want you to fall off in the end.
Peter grew up here in the mountains. He almost looks better than the Gems.
Now go to sleep, but we'll do it somehow.
I was right, wasn't I? If you really think about it, something always comes to
mind.
We can only hope that it was the right thing to do.
Oh yes, I think so, for sure. And now I can finally go to sleep.
Good night and thank you very much.
The next morning Heidi told Peter everything that she and the grandfather had
discussed the evening before
And the two children decided to help Snooki
There's one growing up there, that's exactly what the grandfather wanted
That's way too steep!
Oh what? That's not steep at all
Stay here, you'll fall down
Heidi of course didn't ask the grandfather to climb on his own
She wanted to help Snooki
And what Heidi had put in her head, she didn't give up so quickly
So, I knew it! Now you're stuck! You have to hold on to the left!
And how do I know where the left is?
There, of course! On the side where the herbs grow!
I can't reach it! My arm is too short!
Why don't you help me? Hurry up!
How?
I don't know! Let me think of something!
Fine, I'll come! But it's the last time!
I don't know!
Now be careful!
Slowly! Watch out!
What the hell do you think you're doing?
Can't you listen to what other people say?
That didn't sound that steep.
You don't believe what I found back there.
Well, what do you say?
Nothing.
Is something wrong?
These are others.
These are the right ones.
* Music *
Heidi and Peter worked hard. The whole long day they climbed around the rocks
and picked fresh herbs for Schnucki
In the evening, when the sun went down, Heidi was so tired that she could hardly
put one foot in front of the other
But still she was very, very happy. She was firmly convinced that she could save
Schnucki with Peter's help
The end
What is it, Heidi?
Are you suddenly sick?
I'm just tired, that's all.
Where's Schnucki? She's gone, I can't see her anymore.
There she is.
Thank God.
Thank you.
You look very tired. She probably didn't take a break today, did she?
You know her. She won't rest until she's picked up the last grain.
Take good care of her.
I think I'll give you Joseph from tomorrow.
He'll make sure nothing happens to you.
Good. That'll help me a bit.
I'll pick you up tomorrow.
Heidi!
I don't see her.
She seems to have exaggerated again, as always.
See you tomorrow.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
The moose obeyed his promise and gave Joseph the next day.
That was a great help for Peter.
He knew that under Joseph's protection his herd of goats was safe.
And so he could look for the herbs with Heidi in peace.
Look, there are a lot of them.
Come on, Schnucki, quick!
There's none left, you have to eat them all.
That's very nice.
Peter, did you hurt yourself?
What? Say something, Peter!
Is it very bad, Peter? Does it hurt?
You've found some too.
You think I'm just a fun-climber?
Here, Snuggie, for you.
Thank you.
But you're bleeding on your knee. Does it hurt?
No, not at all.
The main thing is that it tastes good. The knee is not bad.
What you always think of...
I learned that from the dogs. They always do that.
Come with me, Snuggie, come!
Heidi and Peter had decided to help Snuggie and they were not tired of looking
for fresh herbs and feeding Snuggie with them.
And every time the alpine ewe climbed the mountains to hit wood, he did not
leave the little goat either.
Thank you, grandfather. Here, Snuggie, this is for you. Here, eat.
So it went on for many days. But then it started to rain all of a sudden and she
didn't want to stop again.
Heidi was very worried. Who would give Snuggie the herbs she needed to grow and
become strong?
Heidi, don't lose your mind. She's going to grow up, I know that.
Is that really true?
Yes, I think she's over the mountain.
That would be nice.
Grandfather!
Yes, what is it?
Give it to me. I'll carry it for you.
You know what? When I was stroking Schnucki, she felt a little bit fatter.
Oh, you see?
The summer was slowly coming to an end.
The days were getting colder, and it was already very often foggy.
Sometimes you could hardly see your hand in front of your eyes.
It was far too dangerous to do large climbs.
But they look so good. We have to get them.
No, we won't get them. They stay where they are.
It's far too small and far too high.
Come on, we'll turn around. It doesn't make sense.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
But Schnucki hasn't had any of the herbs for so long.
*Sigh*
There they are!
- Heidi! - Peter, help me!
Heidi, hold on! Hold on tight!
Hurry! I can't take it anymore!
Don't let go!
Just hold on one more moment!
I can't take it anymore! Hurry!
You have to, Ken! Here, take my hand!
It won't work!
Yes, it will!
Careful! Hold on tight!
I'm scared!
Don't let go!
I know!
Hold on tight!
You can do it!
Come on.
You're gonna make it, hi!
Come on!
Do it!
You don't want to lose me?
I'm gonna get you!
Come on!
Let go!
Don't let go!
If we didn't have it, then we wouldn't be so happy now
She had stung her foot and had scratches and blue spots everywhere
But Heidi didn't mind that the least
The main thing was that she could help Schnucki
The next day she was back on her feet and climbed the rocks up and down
And she didn't get tired of looking for fresh herbs for the little goat
The best was just good enough for Schnucki
And so she went deeper and deeper into the forest
She climbed the mountain higher and higher and discovered areas that she didn't
even know
Peter accompanied her every day and tried to be even more careful with his
careless girlfriend
But all the effort seemed to be for nothing
The news he brought from the village wasn't always good
But Heidi didn't give up hope
But we want to tell you about that in our next story
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back again
Thanks for watching!