♪
♪ Heidi ♪
♪ Your world are the mountains ♪
♪ Because up here you are at home ♪
♪ Dark bees ♪
♪ Green meadows in the sunshine ♪
♪ Heidi ♪
♪ You need to be happy ♪
♪ Hala-Edi ♪
Yes, yes, yes, it's already good. Slowly.
Run!
Mother!
Yes?
Have you already let the goat out?
You know that I want to take her away today.
Why are you doing this?
I can tell you that.
Yesterday evening she gave some milk for the first time.
I will keep her.
I do not believe that this has anything to say.
This is very likely pure coincidence.
She will come away tomorrow.
Does not come into question.
- How is she? - Better every day.
- Has she started giving milk? - Yes, for the first time last night.
- It's not that easy with her, is it? - Yes, you could say that.
There she is.
Come on, you'll come every day later.
Don't be so slow! We want...
Peter!
Yes?
Be so kind and wait.
What is it?
Unfortunately I don't have any good news.
He wants to bring Snooki to town tomorrow and sell her.
No!
Yes, I tried to talk to him but it didn't make any sense.
To be continued...
Dumb, all together they are so dumb that I would have to hurt them.
And you don't even know what it's all about.
One works from morning to evening.
Schnucki was to be sold.
All the efforts, worries and dangers of the last few days were for nothing.
That morning Peter had to get up to everything, very, very hard.
That should even be enough for Peter's hunger.
We want to climb up even further today.
There will certainly be much better herbs growing up there than down here with
us.
But be careful. It's going to be very windy now.
Yes, yes, certainly. We are always careful.
Do you promise me that you will call Peter today?
If he says it will be too dangerous, then that's true.
Do you actually listen to him?
But yes, of course. I understood everything. I have to go now.
Goodbye. See you tonight. Good morning, Peter.
Which goat is coming into my arms?
Have you already given milk, Schnucki?
Peter!
Good morning, Heidi.
Good morning, Peter!
Oh, yes.
Have you already taken it?
Let's see.
- What's going on? - I can barely lift her, she's much heavier than yesterday.
- Peter, good morning. - Did you see that?
Heidi said he wanted to go higher today, I don't like that at all.
Me neither, but we're not going anywhere today anyway.
- What does that mean? - Do you know a better place down there?
No, I don't know a better place down there, and if I did, we wouldn't need it at
all.
What do you mean? Are you afraid of that little wind?
It doesn't make any sense. They want to sell Snuggie tomorrow.
No!
They want to sell Snuggie tomorrow.
Show me that you're a good goat-hunter.
A goat loves all its goats, not just one.
Come with me.
Leave me alone.
It won't help.
Come on.
Leave me alone. I don't want to.
Stop crying. It won't help.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Didn't you notice that she's already grown up?
Stop!
What is it?
No, no, no, I'm not going any further!
Come on, we're going further!
We can't do anything!
I just can't understand. Schnucki has gotten much bigger.
Lady, calm down. I can't do anything about it.
If I was rich, I'd buy a doll for us, but I don't have any money.
What am I supposed to do?
Stop this constant crying. It won't help us any more.
But it helps me. When I cry, I can think better.
Maybe I'll remember something.
I really don't know what else could come to mind.
Come on, Heidi, let's go on. We can't do anything for a moment.
I won't go on. I'll stay here until I think of something.
I'll stay here until I think of something.
No. No, it's up to me.
Something just happened.
Hurray.
Don't die.
I'll jump higher than you.
Look out.
There!
I'll jump in circles and around.
And round and around and around and around and around.
One and two.
You insisted on catching it.
Watch out.
It's coming into my arms.
Ouch.
Ouch, ouch! - You can't get in there!
Don't bother! I'm faster!
Now you'll have to run after me again!
They'll make eye contact!
They'll be stunned! What do you think, Peter?
We'll show them!
Say something!
Put your hands on me!
Look at the two of them!
And if it doesn't work out...
You haven't eaten a piece yet.
Say something at least.
I don't know what to say. And I'm not hungry.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Peter, look! There! And over there! It's all full!
Yes!
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
Yes, what is it?
What if he forbids us? Maybe he doesn't want them.
Where do we want to bring them then? I'm scared.
Yes? Do you think he'll do that? I don't think so.
Joseph, be quiet today. There won't be a single call.
And you're not allowed to complain.
You're not going to keep it a secret, are you?
Yes, why not? Maybe you'll notice something better?
We have to win some time, don't we?
Yes, but...
Don't make such a face. I don't want to steal them at all.
I'll just borrow them.
Come, Snooki.
That can't be good.
Hey, wait for me!
You can't do that in secret!
We need the help of everyone!
And what should we do if he forbids it, you fool?
When it comes out, you'll owe me everything.
Well, then you'll owe me everything.
It's still better than selling Snuggie.
You could at least think for a second what will come out of me!
You were agreeable with that.
I don't understand why you're acting like that all of a sudden.
Oh, she's got a fat head.
I'm just annoyed that I can't think of what to say fast enough.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
My grandfather can't hear you.
Heidi?
Yes?
- Do you have a fight with Peter? - No, yes, yes, no.
Do you have a fight or not?
How should I understand that?
Come on, tell me.
What's the matter with you, Joseph?
Did he do something?
No, it's all right. He's just tired.
Heidi, will you tell me something?
It won't be a big deal.
Where do you want to go? What's the matter?
Schwendi and Berli ate a lot today.
That makes me happy. They'll give him a lot of milk tonight.
I'll give him something else. It'll do him good.
Schwendi, Berli, come here.
I'll give you something else.
Snooki?
You don't want to tell me, do you? You've lost Schnucki on the way.
Do you expect me to believe that? Answer me!
Have you lost your tongue or have you been frightened by your own lies?
Get in motion and bring Schnucki back here, or do I have to break your legs
first, my son?
No!
Very well, then get out with your tongue.
Where did you leave the goat? Did you hide it?
No.
She's at the almery.
Heidi kept her upstairs. She wants to feed her some more.
- It's my goat! - Everybody knows that.
You don't, apparently.
Otherwise you would have brought her back with you.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Heidi, I hope you know that we can't keep Schnucki.
Keep quiet.
Stay here.
Now let's see if we can do that, too.
Like this.
Can you hear me, Snooki? It's working.
When you're done, please come in.
Look, Snooki, you can be proud.
Very good.
Grandfather! Grandfather!
Would you like to try a sip of this milk?
Tell me, Maria.
A big sip, yes?
Very, very good. The milk tastes excellent, really.
As good as any other goat's milk?
Hooray! We did it! We did it!
Snuggie gives milk!
Really wonderful goat's milk that tastes good!
Good morning, Peter! Hurry up! I have to tell you something!
I have a surprise for you!
What is it?
Is someone coming with Peter?
Leave the talking to me. I know how to deal with him.
Nurmut, do you still think what you did was right?
Really?
I'd rather disappear for a moment.
There.
I want to know what you did to my goat.
I know you're here.
Or should I knock on the door?
You thief!
Why aren't you saying anything?
He was talking in the hut.
Come in.
You don't let anyone else in your hut.
What's the point?
I want to talk to you.
Why?
Well.
Schnucki is with me, and she's very well taken care of.
Very well taken care of? And you promise to protect her!
What do you want? What's that supposed to be?
Here, drink.
Who knows what that thing is?
That's just goat's milk. Try it.
Goat's milk? I know how goat's milk tastes.
How do you like the milk? Does it taste worse than other goat's milk?
No, not at all. You can be proud of your goat.
I have nothing to do with it.
If someone here has the right to be proud, then you have it.
The milk is from your own goat,
from the goat you want to sell to the butcher.
And the kids wanted to prove that to you.
That's why Snooki hid here with me.
But fools can't see what they have on such a goat.
Don't call me that!
You think you're particularly smart.
If someone here is a fool, then you are!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
What do you think you're doing? You don't expect me to believe that this girl is
Snuggie's!
I just figured out that I could talk to you like to a reasonable person.
What? Don't put your nose in my business!
It's all my fault! Grandfather can't do anything about it! He didn't even want
to!
I hid Snuggie from them because I didn't want them to sell her to the butcher.
That's all!
What are you saying?
It's all my fault!
All summer long we've been looking for fresh herbs for her to give her good
milk.
And she gives good milk and she's grown up.
But Schnucki is my goat. She belongs to me. Who told you to do that?
Nobody told us. Peter and I did it on our own because we both love Schnucki
very, very much.
She's the most beautiful goat in the world. And she's also my girlfriend.
Huh? Girlfriend?
Yes, she's my girlfriend, and I'd really like to show her how to give milk.
There's no one who gives such good milk.
How am I supposed to show it to you if you don't come with me?
No, I don't want to believe that.
You can see it.
Yes, but I don't believe what I see.
Here. Please, try the milk.
Not much, but very good.
Why don't you drink? Is there something with the milk?
Huh? No.
Here.
Good.
- What did I say? Not much, but very good. - Yes.
Peter, why didn't you tell me about it down in the village?
I asked you often enough what's going on with the goat.
It didn't work. Every time I wanted to tell you, you yelled at me.
- I wanted to. - But you never let me say anything!
Please, please, please don't sell it, Schnucki. It's so lovely and so small.
Please, please don't. We'll give it a lot of trouble.
It grows and becomes huge and gives more milk than all other goats.
Hm, I don't know. What can you say about that? You seem to really like these
goats.
Why don't you just say yes?
Yes, very well. You should show what you can do.
I'll give you one year to make a real goat out of Schnucki.
Yes, hurray! Thank you!
Well, I congratulate you.
Peter, Schnucki, we have to celebrate that. Come on, quickly!
Yes, I'm coming!
Come on, Joseph!
Come on!
At the end he was as soft as butter
It is understandable that Heidi and Peter didn't know what to do anymore
They jumped and ran and roamed all day
And even Joseph, who likes to sleep so much, couldn't sit still
They had a whole year to take care of Schnucki and take care of him
And without them having to say it, they both decided...
...to look for all the herbs that were necessary to turn Snooki into a good
milking goat.
And if they had to climb even higher, even further, they wanted to do
everything.
The summer ended quickly. The first snow fell.
And for Heidi the long waiting time for sun and heavy snow began again.
Every morning she was happy that Peter picked her up with the sled and brought
her down into the valley.
She liked to drive down, because down in the village she could meet old
acquaintances.
There were many surprises for her, sometimes good, sometimes less good.
In the village it was never boring for Heidi.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
"Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains. Heidi, Heidi, because up here you
are at home. Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home."
Thanks for watching!