Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark
Trees
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Summer passed. It became autumn and winter.
And one morning the first thick snowflakes fell.
It snowed all day and all night.
And when Heidi got up the next morning, everything was white.
Like the year before, she went out regularly to feed the wild animals.
She had not forgotten her friends from last winter.
* Music *
Heidi, why are you digging such a deep hole?
That's a secret. I can't tell you yet.
It's hot.
Shit, that should be deep enough now.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Oh, that's good. You can't see anything at all.
Nobody will notice anything.
Actually, I really want to know what you're actually doing there.
You'll see that soon.
Joseph, come! Joseph!
Here I am, over here on the hill. Come here!
Come on, one more time! Come closer! Come on!
What is it?
You know what? You're stupid!
Terrible boring!
Let's see if we can get you to run after all!
Watch out, Joseph! Catch!
You're even more boring than I thought!
He'll look right through you. Joseph is smarter than you think.
He's not smart at all. He just has a good nose.
Good! There comes your father.
Good day! Hurry up!
I hope it works this time. Peter won't notice anything.
I'll give him a kiss.
I'm excited to see what kind of face he'll make.
I've got a surprise for you!
Really? Show it to me!
What kind of one?
Huh? I can't see her. Where is she?
You have to look for her.
Why do you suddenly look so disappointed?
I don't see her.
I'm not disappointed. I just thought you were curious and weren't just standing
around.
I saw a pebble. You would have liked that one.
No, a pebble down here?
Do you think it's still somewhere?
Come on, let's go look for it.
Oh no!
Yes, that's right. Anyone who digs a pit falls into it himself.
Was that a surprise?
Will you come with us? We can go with the sleigh.
Oh yes. May I, Grandfather? Yes?
Yes, of course. Why not?
Thank you. But I have something.
The teacher put the letter in my pocket earlier.
He said I should definitely hand it over.
Goodbye!
Stay at home before it gets dark!
It was an important letter, the letter from the schoolteacher from Dörfli.
He had calculated how old Heidi would have to be by now and now wrote to the
Alm-Öhi that it was time to send Heidi to school so that she could read and
write.
* Music *
That's way too slow. Can you go faster? Or should I go faster?
Don't be afraid. I'm going to the curve.
There's the child again, our Heidi. I recognize her voice.
No, don't throw snowballs!
Leave it!
She sounds so happy.
7, 9, 10! I'm coming! I know where you are!
Is that a beautiful bell? There it is!
Found it! You're on it! You, Peter?
Who heard the bell?
Oh, my father should have heard it.
He also heard it once, just like me today.
Do you think we can start something with you?
Maybe we can hang it around our Snooki next summer.
Look!
What do you think if we hang the bell around his neck?
That's even more fun!
Come on!
Why are you holding on?
We're way too far away.
That doesn't matter. We have to go back before it gets dark.
And over there is Dörfli. The bells are ringing.
Yes, the bells.
You know what? I've got an idea.
What do you think about going all the way down there and visiting Snuggie?
Nothing.
Why do you always hear the same answer when someone asks you something?
Because you always ask the same stupid questions, of course.
We can't go there now.
If you come home too late, you won't be allowed to come with us tomorrow.
I want to see her.
It will be fine.
She's in the barn and sleeping. So come now.
No, I'm not coming with you. You're coming with me.
Heidi! Wait for me!
- Get out! - You're nicer than I thought. Thank you!
What was that?
Wasn't that Heidi?
Of course it was.
Wasn't Peter there?
What do they want in the middle of the winter?
We're here.
This is your stable?
Do you think she'll recognize us again?
Why not?
Come on, let's go in!
It's dark.
But he scared me!
Heidi! I found her!
Yes?
Where?
Schnucki, how are you?
Schnuckilein, how are you?
Schnuckilein!
You seem to be doing well. You won't be treated badly. You look good.
But you haven't really grown up yet.
Do you give at least a lot of milk?
Let me see.
You look good.
Will you promise to grow when we see each other again in spring?
Don't lick me.
I think you'll never get used to that.
You know I don't like it when it tickles.
You're probably disappointed because I didn't bring you anything.
We have to go home. It's getting dark.
Come on.
Hello. Do you remember me?
Of course, Heidi. How could I forget you?
Who deserves this pleasant surprise? Me or my goat?
We just wanted to see how Schnucki is doing.
Did you see that? She is healthy and cheerful and gives good milk.
I can only thank you for that.
Will you keep her?
Don't ask such stupid questions.
Goodbye. I have to go now.
Please take good care of her.
But of course. Now don't worry. I'll take care of her.
As always.
A snowball fight.
Yes! Yes!
I'll take part in that. I can do that, too!
Oh, no offense!
Throw it away!
You won't get it!
I'm gonna kill you.
No.
What?
Throw it! Throw it!
There! Ow!
Throw it!
You can't hit it!
Yes! Ow!
That's what you thought!
Hit it!
Yes!
Now mine!
Wait, I'm coming!
You have to be faster!
That wasn't anything!
And again!
I'm with you!
Ow!
A bomb!
Yes!
One!
What does she want?
Heidi, come with me. It's late!
Why don't you go on?
Are you frozen or what?
Are you Heidi from the Alp?
Yes, of course I am.
Why don't you go to school when you're already down here?
Why me?
The teacher gave you a letter. Tell me, did you lose it somewhere?
No, I didn't lose it.
He gave you the letter, but what am I supposed to do in school?
Listen to yourself.
What?
Have you ever been to a school?
No, unfortunately not.
Why unfortunately? You can be happy that you didn't have to go to school yet.
Did you know what was in the letter?
No, it was sealed.
Grandfather didn't even tell me that I was allowed to go to school.
That's no wonder. That's not normal.
That's mean.
I'm sorry.
Take it back!
Why should he? Everyone says so.
He lives up in the mountains and it's not normal.
That's no wonder.
He lives up there all alone and doesn't want anything to do with anyone.
That's how it is.
You have no idea.
Doesn't she look strange, too?
Heidi, show us the alphabet, will you?
If you tell me what it is, I'd love to.
She doesn't even know what the alphabet is!
Is the alphabet something funny?
The alphabet?
Well, if you've never heard the alphabet,
then we'll teach you two.
Be quiet! Attention!
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, L, M, N, O, F, Q, R, S
Stop! Stop! Stop!
You might be a teacher!
You're making mistakes!
Why do you need something like that?
That's not possible!
Tell me!
You don't seem to know anything.
It's about time you came to school.
At least I can milk goats.
And that's better than all of us together.
Everyone in our village can milk goats.
I can whistle, too.
- I can do that too! - I've never seen such a stupid thing like you!
You should be let go!
- Come with me! - You really need the school!
Why are they so close to me?
Why did they laugh at me then? Did I do something to them or did I do something
wrong?
Oh, what? No one has to go to school. They only tell you boring things. Believe
me.
Wait a minute.
So, now everything is fine. Now you can teach me the alphabet. Start with it.
What? I should teach you the alphabet?
Yes.
I don't know.
Then don't be so slow. Start.
A, B, C, D.
E, F, G, F, G, F, G, A, B, C, D, E, F, G, G, G.
How does it go on? Don't you know?
G, F, G, M.
Oh, why? No one needs the alphabet.
The goats have never asked us for it, have they?
So I'm not the only one who doesn't know it yet.
Come on, let's go home.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Where are the two of them?
But what is he doing?
Is there something new in the village that I don't know yet?
Yes, you can say that. The teacher wrote a letter to the Almühi.
He could have saved himself, he doesn't read.
This time he will have to read whether he likes it or not.
He doesn't care.
No.
You make me curious. What did he write?
Do you know what's in it?
I know. He's supposed to send Heidi to school, but he's going to come up with an
excuse again.
My son says she can't even read the alphabet.
Is that a possibility?
I'm convinced that she can't even distinguish right from left.
Well, you know what that leads to.
That's not going to end well, because I haven't seen her in the church on Sunday
either.
You can't blame the child for that.
She doesn't go to church herself. How should the little girl know?
You have to be careful that she doesn't even bathe on Saturdays.
My son is bathed every Saturday and scrubbed with soap, whether he wants to or
not.
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know. Maybe she even has lice.
That could be good, but I don't think so.
My son saw her today and said she was a very pretty girl.
He didn't see lice.
The more important it is that she goes to school.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, but the old man doesn't want to listen to us.
He hasn't greeted me a single time.
Recently I even waved to him.
Exactly, that looks like him.
He looks through you as if you were air.
Grandfather, I'm back!
Finally!
I was down in the village and visited Schnucki.
- There I am! - You're late, I just put on my coat and wanted to look for you.
I was at Schnucki's.
She's fine and she shouldn't be sold anymore.
Oh, I'm glad to hear that.
Yes, and imagine, she's still giving milk.
That's good for me.
My hands are freezing cold. Show me the letter.
Down in the village, they say, the teacher has written that I can also come to
school now.
So they told you about it?
Was that wrong? Why are you so angry all of a sudden?
Why didn't you tell me anything about school?
Because I don't think it's right.
Have you never been to school?
Yes, that's true, but this school is down in the village, and that's something
else.
But there's no other one, and I have to go to school.
You don't.
That's enough, I don't want to hear any more of that.
Why?
It's a waste of time to go to school.
They teach the children how to write and read, but they also spoil them.
They forget to teach the children that there is something more important for
people than letters and numbers.
They look at our world in books and no longer know how beautiful it really is.
But you still know.
I don't know.
Then you bring me the writing and reading. It's enough for both of us when you
were in school.
I'll make us something to eat. You've been in the fresh air all day.
Good, I'm hungry.
When Heidi then sat at the dinner table with her grandfather, she had long
forgotten the plan to go to school
She told in detail about what she had experienced, about Snooki, about the milk
that Snooki gave and about the snowball battle of course
She didn't read anything in her report, not even that she was laughed at by the
village boys and that Peter couldn't read the alphabet
She told about the big sled and the cow bell and claimed that they would have
been faster than the wind
The End
When the snow melted and it became spring, Heidi and Joseph ran across the
meadows every day and looked for new adventures.
And on one of these trains they both experienced a surprise.
Watch out, he's flying far!
A stranger man came up to them, whom Heidi had never seen before.
What did he want up here?
He was friendly to her and spoke for a long time with the grandfather. Heidi was
not allowed to be there when the two were having a conversation, but the
grandfather was very serious.
But we want to tell you about this in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world is the mountains, Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are
at home, Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.
Thank you for watching.