This is a work of fiction. Any resemblance to real persons, living or dead, is
coincidental and unintentional.
It is a work of fiction. Any resemblance to real persons, living or dead, is
Up here you are at home. Dark firs, green meadows in the sunshine. Heidi, Heidi,
you need to be happy.
I'll hold you up high. Heidi, Heidi, come home. Find your happiness. Come back
again.
Do you remember? Peter brought a letter and in the letter it said that Heidi
would be old enough to go to school.
But the grandfather didn't want to know anything about it.
During the long winter Heidi forgot the letter and the plan to go to school.
And when the first snow melted and it was slowly spring, Heidi didn't even have
the fun of reading from the alp again.
She couldn't keep anything in the hut any longer. Heidi wanted to go outside.
She wanted to see and hear and smell spring.
* Music *
It already smells like spring.
- Did you talk to the trees again? - Yes, but there was always no answer.
Do you know that you can hear the spring? The wind sounds different and there
are a lot more birds.
I know. You can hear the spring, you can feel the spring and you can smell the
spring.
But you don't make a spring visit.
Yes, with the grandmother. Joseph, we'll make a visit.
To be continued
The snow looks good, doesn't it?
You know, you can make a nice, solid snowball out of it.
Watch out! He's flying far!
And he's flying even farther! And he's flying even farther!
Hey!
I really didn't know that someone was coming.
That's good, my child. I agree with the assumption that you are Heidi.
Who else could you be?
You're right, I am Heidi.
You see, my child, I could rely on my knowledge of people again.
Is your grandfather at home?
Grandfather! Grandfather!
I have a surprise for you. We have a visitor.
Oh?
Greetings, God. Am I late?
Good day. Why don't you come in?
May I offer you this chair? We don't have a chair here.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
The ascent is also getting steeper and steeper.
That's deceiving.
Of course, it could also be because I'm getting older.
That should just be a little bit of me.
Let's leave that. Let's get down to business.
You must already know why I'm here.
I want to talk to you about Heidi.
Heidi.
Please leave us alone for a moment. I'm going out to play again.
Uh-huh. I'll do that.
We sent you a letter. And in the letter it said that you should send her to
school, but she was not there for a single day.
I, as the shepherd of my sheep, ask you: How do you want to prepare her for her
way of life?
It is not enough to give a child food and clothing, one is also responsible for
his soul.
That's cute!
Grandfather has a very important visit today.
Heidi stays with me and I don't want to hear anything from the school.
You seem to be a little unruly, my son. You should go inside.
I am very ruled.
I gave Heidi a home and made her a happy person.
She grows with me with the goats, the birds and nature.
She is free and happy, and no school can teach her that.
Sit down! Sit down!
No! Lay down!
Heidi is a human being and not one of your milk goats. She needs something more
to be happy than just grass.
I know you. I know that I can't force you, but you should at least think again.
I don't want to judge whether you are doing well or bad. I didn't come to take
her away from you.
I'm here to talk to you about it. Others know other means and ways to bring you
to reason.
Then they should come.
Brother, brother.
How have I earned that? Why in all the world are you only so infinitely
stubborn?
Will you never accept reason in life? Why are you making it so difficult for me?
I just want your best. You have come a long way in the world.
You should have a little more insight. Dear Lord in heaven,
stand by me so that I don't say anything that I regret afterwards.
The descent is very steep and you are not the youngest.
Heidi didn't know what the two were talking about in the hut.
She was happy and unharmed as always and enjoyed the last snow that she could
find.
If I let you climb down the mountain every day for four hours, even I'll get
tired of it.
Hurry up, Joseph, or you won't catch me.
The goal is too small and too weak. That's impossible. No!
The two men argued with each other for many hours.
None of them wanted to give in. None of them was optimistic.
Come on, these smart people, and take the child away from me.
I'll know how to defend myself.
Neighbor, neighbor, if you knew how brave I am, believe me, you will do a great
sin to this child.
As I can see from the many games, you like to hate the child and do everything
for her.
Why don't you just go with us to Dörfli? That would solve our problems.
We would have solved two problems.
Heidi would come to school and I would finally be able to greet you again in the
church.
I could have been on my way home a long time ago, but you don't have any mercy
with your poor fellow human beings.
No.
I can't live down there in the village.
And Heidi can't either.
We belong here, in this little hut.
That's the way it is.
Down there in the village, it's too narrow and too small for a man like me.
Well...
I can't do anything with the people who live there.
I'm sorry.
I hate you and you hate me.
And that will always be the case.
You think I'm crazy.
But that doesn't matter to me anymore.
I've met them.
Every single one of them.
I'm sorry, they don't understand.
And what's worse, no heart.
You judge too strictly, my brother. It may sometimes have the appearance, you
must not forget, they say, not for nothing, in a raw shell often rests a soft
core.
Believe me, but if you come to them, they will come to you.
You were the one who turned away from them. Have you ever had a friendly word
for them?
Believe me, you take the first step, my brother, and they will come to you and
take you with open arms.
Be careful, Almöhi, you are the wiser one.
For only those who can be weak can show their true strength, and you are strong.
Give me your hand in friendship.
Believe me, I know the people.
I know what is good for you and for Heidi.
Take the child with you down to our village.
I thank you for the time you have sacrificed and I know how to appreciate what
you want to do for us.
But unfortunately I have to renounce. Neither Heidi nor I will send you into the
village.
I will not send you to your school.
Neighbor, neighbor, you are making a mistake.
Is the conversation over?
Aren't you staying with us for lunch?
Tell me, my child, don't you sometimes feel very lonely here with your
grandfather alone?
No, not a little bit.
Why are you looking at me like that all of a sudden?
Oh, nothing, nothing special.
Goodbye, little one, take care.
Goodbye!
We will!
So, Grandfather, now he's gone. Tell me.
Was it something nice for us or not so nice?
Well?
So it wasn't that nice.
Grandfather?
How can you just call the goats now?
If you don't want to say it on your own, can I guess it?
Yes? I'll just try it now.
He wanted to sell us a new goat, a five-legged one.
You have to say something too.
That's no fun. If one is running, the other has to say hot or cold.
It's none of your business.
But why not?
1, 0, 9, 11, 7, Heaven, Hell, 9...
If you don't want to talk to me, you should let it go. One, two...
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
And he talked to the old man like to a sick horse, and what should I tell you,
completely senseless.
So he doesn't send her to school?
Yes, exactly.
That looks like him. The teacher climbs the mountain to talk to him, and what do
you do?
You just reject him.
You know what? Before he went up to his inn, he even walked door to door with
our teacher.
Yes, that's right.
What will happen to the child if he doesn't let it go to school? You can't just
watch it like that.
Yes, exactly.
I totally agree with you. We'll have to come up with something, and then he has
to do it.
The only question is what we should come up with. I can't think of anything at
times like this.
There's a car.
My luggage is downstairs. Now I don't have to walk that far.
The rest is for you. Thank you.
Thank you too.
She's from the city.
You can see that.
Did you see what she was wearing?
I only know that from the newspaper.
Me too.
It works.
Who can it be?
Did you invite someone else that I don't know anything about?
Maybe it's the priest who's still coming.
Good day, Aunt Barbel. May I come in?
- Dete, that can't be true. - No, no, no.
And you're here too, as you used to be.
Indeed, Dete, let me look at you, my child.
I'm so happy to see you.
- This feather of the abode. - Welcome.
- I'm glad you're here. - Thank you.
- You look wonderful. - Thank you.
Let me hug you, too, Dete.
I haven't seen you in so long, my child.
You've become a fine lady, right out of town.
How is it here in the village? Is everything still as it was not so long ago?
Dete, the young girl from the village, had changed a lot.
A lot of time had passed since she had entrusted her niece Heidi, the daughter-
in-law of the Almöhi.
She didn't like it, but she had no other choice.
Here in the village she found no work. The only place she was offered was in
Frankfurt.
And what was she supposed to do alone in the big city with Heidi?
Now she was back.
I interrupted you. When I arrived, you had just talked to each other.
Yes, yes, exactly. And everything is your fault.
If you hadn't necessarily had to go through your head back then, we would have
had a lot less trouble today.
And who knows what it's good for you to have come today?
Again, I can't follow you.
What am I to blame for? What have I done? I haven't been here all these years.
If you had given us some advice back then, Heidi wouldn't have had to go through
all this.
Go through? What do you mean, Heidi? Is she sick? Or is she injured?
No, she's not. She's not sick, but she's injured.
Is he treating her badly?
No, he loves her warmly and tenderly.
But that's the way it is. He doesn't want to hand her over. He won't let her go
to school.
He won't let her go to school?
She doesn't even know the alphabet, and she can't count either.
She's already eight years old. How is that supposed to go on with her?
She doesn't even know where right and left is.
We've even sent the pastor to him.
I understand. You see, he's still exactly the same as he used to be.
It's a wonder that he even gives the child something to eat.
She's supposed to have become so nice and pretty.
Do you have a cup of coffee for me?
I will then tell you something that you still have to keep for yourself.
I think your worries are over from today.
What?
Tell me, does that have anything to do with you and the child?
first a cup of coffee and then I'll tell you all about it
but first sit down at the table
but what?
Tete, don't make it so exciting
tell us right now
no, no, no, eat the coffee
she has a long journey behind her and will be tired
of course, how can you be so heartless?
I even like to make the coffee
nice
if you know how happy I was at home
we are lucky, there was still something in the kitchen
hopefully you saw if it's still warm
it will be
don't we have a piece of cake for the celebration of the day?
no, unfortunately not, then I'll have a good time
subscribe to the channel
* Music *
Grandfather, may I visit Peter's grandmother today?
I'm thinking about it.
One, two, three, go!
One, two, three...
1, 2, 3, 4, 7, 12, 5, 6, 8, stop.
1, 2, 3, 4, 7, 8, stop.
Twelve, fifteen, twenty-eight, one, two, three, four, seven, nine, a hundred,
twelve.
Good day, Heidi. How are you?
Don't you recognize me anymore, Heidi?
Yes, of course. You are Aunt Dete.
How tall you are!
You are heavier too. Let me take a look at you. You look good and you've got
nice red cheeks. How nice.
Tell me, are you doing well, my child? - Yes.
Is your grandfather at home? - Yes, of course. He's in the hut. I'll go and tell
him.
No, Heidi, wait. - Why?
Just like that. - It's better for you if you wait outside.
Or not. Let me think about it.
No, you can stay with us. It's a surprise for you.
Yes, of course.
Grandfather, we've got visitors again. Tell us who they are.
Good day, Almöhi.
Why are you laughing? What's so funny?
You wiped the floor with your long skirt.
It's good for cleaning.
What?
That's okay. My skirt isn't that important right now.
I brought good news for you.
We can use good news.
Now I almost forgot that I brought you something from the city.
Here, sweets for you.
Thank you.
Look at me.
I brought you tobacco. I hope you like the taste.
I want to thank you. You were very good to Heidi.
You can see how happy she was here.
Heidi, let us in for a moment, okay?
Yes, of course.
So you still haven't given up on me.
I had no other choice then.
You were the only one I could trust.
I knew you could handle children.
I think you thought I'd give them to you and then forget, but that's not true.
I haven't forgotten them for a minute. I've had to think of them every day and
every night.
I know it was hard for you, but now I'm finally so far that I can help you.
I know it took a long time, but now I've finally come to pick them up.
What did you say?
I'll take them with me.
I'll take them with me to Frankfurt.
One for you, and one for me.
From now on, Heidi had to start a completely different life.
She had to say goodbye to her beloved mountains.
Dete took her with her without really understanding what had happened to her.
And Peter and Joseph no longer understood the world.
Heidi was curious about the big city of Frankfurt,
and she had to find a way to get out of it.
But the farewell of her friends was incredibly difficult for her.
When would they all see each other again?
Joseph, the faithful Bernardine, her beloved mountains, the children down in the
village, the little church, the colorful houses, and above all, when would she
see her grandfather again?
Peter, in any case, had a huge rage over everyone who had taken away Heidi from
him.
But we want to tell you about this in our next story.
♪ Heidi, Heidi, your world is the mountains. Heidi, Heidi, because up here you
are at home. Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home. ♪
Thanks for watching!