Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
It was a wonderful spring day, the sun was shining, it was warm and Heidi could
stay outside all day long and pick flowers for the first time.
Heidi had all the reasons to be happy and content, but something was going on
today that was strange, that bothered her.
First the priest was there and then suddenly Aunt Dete came. What did Aunt Dete
want?
She hadn't been up here on the alp for three years and Heidi had almost
forgotten her.
And why did her grandfather send her out to play?
It wasn't very easy for you, I know.
But what was I supposed to do?
I had no other choice. You were the only one I could trust.
You can handle children.
You also know how it was, Almöhe.
I didn't find a job in Dörfli at the time.
The only job I was given was in Frankfurt.
And where was I supposed to go with her? I was also a stranger.
I didn't know where I was supposed to go.
You're not making it easy for me.
You can be happy, I'll take her with me now.
It took a long time, but now I'm finally so far that I know how I can take care
of her.
You want to take her with you?
Yes, I'll take her with me.
I really have a very good message for you.
Heidi has a possibility that only one in a thousand children has.
Oh, what am I talking about, one in a hundred thousand children.
In Frankfurt there is a family, the Sesemann family.
Mr. Sesemann is the richest man in town.
And Mr. Sesemann has a daughter, and the daughter's name is Clara.
Mr. Sesemann loves his daughter, but this daughter is crippled.
And now they are looking for a little, nice, lovely girl
who will spend time with Clara and give private school lessons.
Heidi is taken in the house like a second daughter.
I know it. I work for Sesemann's relatives.
When I heard about it for the first time, I didn't want to believe it, but the
housekeeper, Mrs. Rottenmeier, confirmed it to me personally.
You don't believe how beautiful the house is that Heidi is supposed to come
into.
It's a big old Frankfurt house with many windows and a heavy front door.
And in this house Clara sits in the wheelchair all day long and can't go outside
because she can't walk.
Mr. Sesemann does everything for his daughter, but he is very often traveling.
And your mother doesn't have Clara anymore.
The poor thing.
Mr. Sesemann takes every wish from her eyes.
He even brought a private teacher into the house for her.
He brings Clara everything she needs to know.
She has more toys than all the children in our village.
But she is sad all day. She never laughs.
And that's why Mr. Sesemann and Mrs. Rottenmeier asked me if I didn't know a
playmate for Clara.
Of course I immediately thought of Heidi.
I told everything about Heidi that I knew.
I described exactly how happy she is and how clever she is and how quickly she
understands.
But believe me, that wasn't that easy.
Mrs. Rottenmeier is hard to please. She is very, very strict.
But she is good with Clara. You have to let her be.
Well, and you know the rest. I came here.
You have to let her be.
Yes, that's exactly what I knew.
You were surprised by my good news.
I'm so proud and so happy.
And what else do you have to say to me?
You think I just figured it out.
Oh, you're wrong.
I wonder all the time that you don't talk to me and don't show a little bit of
joy.
Well, you've always been wordy.
Nevertheless, it's strange.
Everyone else would jump into the air for joy with such a message.
Nice.
Now tell this message to those who want to jump into the air.
Now listen to me. Heidi is now eight years old. She can't do anything and she
doesn't know anything.
She can neither read, nor write, nor can the child calculate.
And down in the village they told me you won't even allow her to go to school.
That's all my business. What's good for Heidi, I know better than you all
together.
Do you understand me? She stays here.
Heidi is the child of my deceased sister and I am responsible for her happiness.
If you want to go to court with me, then do it, but what do you think who will
win, huh?
Every single resident in Dörfli will speak for me.
And you can believe me, they're already looking forward to it.
She has to go to school. How are they ever going to get along in life if you're
not there anymore?
I just don't understand you. I only want the best for Heidi and you act as if I
were doing something bad here.
But please, as you wish, let her come to court for a dispute.
Are you finally finished or do you still want something new?
I'm going!
You don't believe how much I still remember.
As long as I'm here and talk to you, you will unfortunately have to listen to me
whether you want it or not.
The last time you chased me away from here like a rowdy dog.
But now, thank God, I no longer have to be treated like that by you.
I have become a lady in the meantime.
And you will probably know how to treat women.
Do you still not want to talk?
Well, if that's the case...
If you don't want to answer me, then other people have to come here and they'll
know how to force you.
I'm sorry, but you didn't want it any other way.
Now that's enough for me. Stop it!
Well, take them with you, but never bring them back here again in your life.
Then I'll teach you what you have to know about life if you're so smart.
But if you talk about the stupid things you say about yourself,
and you understand the albino feather on your hat,
then I'd rather not know anything about it.
Do you understand me?
Yes.
Let Heidi decide for herself.
She's old enough. She knows what she wants.
I know her. She won't want to go.
I wouldn't be so sure at your place, who knows who you've dealt with.
Oh, God, how stupid you are.
We'll see who's the stupid one of us.
- Are you ready? - Can you tell me what you've talked about?
Yes.
- And? - I asked your Oehi if you could travel with me, and he allowed it.
- How? - We're going to Frankfurt together.
- But I don't want to go away. - But you do.
Frankfurt is a big city, you'll like it, there's a lot to see.
- But I don't want to see it! - Yes, you do.
I know you mean it, but I don't want to go with you.
Heidi, you don't even know if you want to go with me.
Put on your hat and come.
Look, I came all the way here to get you, and now you disappoint me like this.
But it's beautiful here. I like it here.
In Frankfurt you like it much better.
There you will be able to read every wish from your eyes.
And you certainly have many wishes.
Every little girl wishes something that she would like very much.
No.
No, I don't wish anything at all. I want to stay here.
Heidi, you don't know what you're saying.
I can't come with you. I have to take care of Schnucki.
And besides, we have spring now. I can't go away.
Come again in the winter. Grandfather and I will go together.
It shouldn't be forever, Heidi. Come with me and I'll take a look at you.
If you don't like it, you can go home right away.
I don't like it!
Besides, I can't drive because I promised to visit Peter's grandmother.
She gets sad when I don't come. I go to her almost every day.
But you can also visit her from Frankfurt.
And then you bring her many presents.
- What? - What you want.
Is there soft white bread in Frankfurt?
She sometimes said she can't bite the black bread with her teeth anymore.
But she has no money to buy herself white bread.
You can buy yourself a whole suitcase full of white bread.
Heidi remembered very well the afternoon when the grandmother had to put the
bread aside again because it was already so old and hard.
Her grandmother was so sorry at the time, but she also didn't know how to help
her.
She would have liked to have given her own bread, but that was also hard.
The thought of driving the grandmother to the city of Frankfurt to buy soft
rolls began to appeal to her.
Yes, tell me, can I be back tonight?
Today?
But I promised you, you can go home right away if you want.
Do you think I can bring something to my grandfather?
Yes, why not?
We will definitely find something for him too.
Tobacco!
Come on, we have to hurry.
So be nice and put on your coat, okay?
Yes, and a goat pipe for Peter.
Of course.
Come on, hurry up, Aunt Dede.
I always have to be at home before it gets dark.
Come on, quick!
What is it?
Grandfather, I'm going with you to Frankfurt to buy some...
The best bread!
Goodbye! See you later!
Don't go away Heidi. Child, she promised you everything.
Come on, let's go.
Heidi, do you want to go to my grandmother's?
No, I'm going to Frankfurt.
That's a good joke.
That's not a joke at all. Aunt Dede will take me.
But Frankfurt is so far away.
It's not that far. I'm back tonight.
That's Peter.
Heidi, no!
Stay here! It's already late. We don't have time to talk to him.
But Peter is my best friend and I also want to go to his grandmother.
You can talk to them for many hours when you come back.
Let's go now!
No! Let me go! I want to tell Peter about the white rolls!
Stay! Please don't leave me alone!
Please don't pull yourself too hard!
Let me go!
Aunt Dede, please don't!
Help!
Gross!
Peter, you're scaring me to death.
Do you have to be so loud?
Peter, do you put the wood outside or should it stay on the table?
He seems to have to sit for a week, at least he makes such a face.
He should have deserved that.
Peter, what's wrong with you? Did you have a fight with the children?
No, I didn't!
But now I'm starting to worry about you.
Oh, what? It's about Heidi! She's so mean!
Dete took her with us to Frankfurt!
No!
Yes, I saw it!
Oh, she can't do that.
But maybe Heidi can't do anything about it.
Yes, she went with us and that's bad enough.
Dede, leave the child here.
Dede, leave her here.
Dede, Dede, bring Heidi back.
She is everything we have.
Dede, Dede, Dede.
- Peter's grandmother is calling for me. - Come on, we don't have time.
But she called me. I have to go to her. Did you forget that she's blind?
Oh, let me finally be in peace with this old grandmother.
- Yes, she's old, but very sweet. - One thing I want to tell you now.
If we want to get along in friendship, never yell at me again.
- I'm not yelling, but let me go. - I don't think about it.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Grandmother, please come back in. You are not to be seen anymore.
Come, I'll take you to your chair, yes? That's good.
She will come back. Don't worry, she'll come back for sure.
Calm down. Everything will be fine again.
Brigitte, I don't think you told her the truth.
I feel it, I just don't know why. Why did he let her go?
THE FOURTH DAY
And one and two and three and four and five and six and seven and eight and nine
and ten.
There's Heidi.
But that's funny.
Everything is funny with him.
Mom, come to the window.
There comes the date with Heidi.
No, not possible.
Well, Dete, you seem to have been really lucky.
Yes.
Oh, did he just give it to you like that?
Well, something like that.
She came along on her own.
No!
I only go with her because I want white rolls.
You can also get them and much more.
It's time that she is finally raised properly.
Goodbye.
No, no.
No, no! How do you find that?
Well, I can't imagine that she voluntarily gave it to her.
* Music *
Copyright subtitles: hr 2021
Oh dear God, hopefully Heidi will come back. I want to have the child again.
She's always so happy.
She'll come back. Calm down.
She's gone. I love her so much. Every morning I was looking forward to her
coming.
To be continued
So!
I'll tell him my opinion now!
Please!
Open the door!
I know you're there! Open the door!
I know you're there!
Why are you running away? Come back, Peter, please.
I'm glad you're here.
Have you eaten lunch?
No, only half.
Then come.
Why is she gone?
Why did you send Heidi away from here?
She... She didn't do anything bad.
She wanted to. I didn't send her.
She wanted to go on her own?
No, I don't want to believe that.
It's true.
And she will never come back.
But...
Heidi goes to a city.
And the city changes the people.
They are destroyed there.
Heidi won't go anywhere, not even to this city!
Heidi will stay our Heidi all her life, won't she?
Yes, she will.
Peter!
!
That's a real mile!
Heidi!
If we don't hurry, I'll never be back tonight!
I can't walk faster in a long skirt. I've stumbled three times already.
Why do you have such a long skirt? In the village, women all wear short skirts.
Heidi ran down the mountain as fast as she could.
She was determined to buy white rolls for her grandmother and still be back for
dinner.
She knew that her grandfather wouldn't like it if she came home too late.
That's why she got a bit angry with Aunt Dete.
Why did she go so slowly?
Didn't she know that she, Heidi, had promised to come home before dark?
Heidi didn't dream that she would see her grandfather neither this evening nor
the next evening.
It took a very long time for her to realize how far the road to Frankfurt is.
At first she felt the train ride.
But then she had to think of her grandfather and she became infinitely sad.
What would he do without her? Would he come to her?
How would it go for him, alone up there in the mountains?
When would she see him and the grandmother and all her friends again?
Frankfurt, what should she do there?
Heidi thought about it and she made up her mind.
But we want to tell you about it in our next story.
Heide, Heide, your world are the mountains.
Heide, Heide, because up here you are at home.
Heide, Heide, come home.
Find your happiness, come back again.
To be continued