Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holala-edi, Holala-edi, Holala-edi, Holala-edi, Holala-edi, Holala-edi, Holala-
edi, Holala-edi
Holala-edi
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
On a beautiful spring day, Aunt Dete had climbed the Alps and had taken Heidi
with her
She wanted to take Heidi to Frankfurt, where she was to be taken in the house of
the wealthy merchant Sesemann as a playmate for the crippled daughter Clara
Heidi didn't know anything about the plan. She thought Frankfurt would be
somewhere nearby and she would be back on time for dinner
- That's the Frankfurt. - Wait here. I have to go shopping.
Oh, yes.
Do you have white rolls?
That's for you to eat.
Thank you.
And where are the rolls?
You can't get rolls here.
But you said so.
Well, come on.
No, I want to go home.
Grandfather said I should always be at home before it gets dark.
And it's going to be dark soon.
And I tell you, you're not coming.
Copyright WDR 2018
When are we in Frankfurt? It can't be any further.
My feet hurt so much.
Not for long. Now we're in Mayenfeld.
We're in Mayenfeld?
Yes.
You lied to me!
You said earlier I could...
I want to be back this evening!
Oh, did I really say that?
Yes, you did!
Then I just said it.
I must have been mistaken, Heidi. Now don't stand there forever.
But I also said that Frankfurt is a beautiful city that you like.
And that wasn't a lie.
I want to go home again!
Heidi! No, don't stand there!
I'm slowly running out of patience.
We'll take a train and drive to Frankfurt.
No, I don't want to!
I'm going to the hospital!
No, don't stand there!
I don't want to!
This is our train, Heidi. We have to hurry. Come on!
No, I'm not going with you in the train.
Oh, come on!
I'm not going! I'm not going!
Don't be like that! Stop screaming!
Stop it!
Go away!
Let me go! Grandfather is waiting! I want to go home!
What are these people doing?
We're finally taking you!
I really wanted that!
I don't care! Let me go! I want to go home!
Heidi!
I don't care! I want to go home!
I really wanted that! I want to go home!
I want to go home!
I do love you!
me too!
Heidi, I can imagine very well that you are sad now.
I can explain to you why I did that and maybe you'll understand me then.
I want you to be happy once.
Heidi.
I packed a cheese bread for you.
You must be hungry. Please take it, yes?
Heidi, you have to eat. The train ride is long.
And if I stay in Frankfurt for a few days and I don't like it, can I go back?
If you really don't like it.
At least you didn't lie when you said there were white rolls for the
grandmother.
Where I'm going to take you, there are white rolls for breakfast every morning.
Don't you want to bite into the cheese bread now?
No.
* Music *
Maybe it's not as bad in Frankfurt as you think. Maybe you do like it here.
You will have your own room and be able to learn with Clara every day.
- Learn to read? - Yes, and to calculate and write and much more.
You have your own teacher and he will teach you everything you need to know.
THE END
* Music *
I know what you're thinking, but your Heidi isn't in the village.
Uh-uh.
* Music *
I don't know, Brigitte, if we ever see each other again. Maybe she'll never come
back.
I wish I could tell you, Grandmother.
To be continued
Have you seen what kind of a face he makes?
Strange, I don't know. He's suddenly sorry for me.
I can't help myself either. Hopefully we didn't do him wrong.
No, he has his own fault.
Why is he running up there alone and doesn't let her go to school, huh?
Yes, you have to see that from this side.
Still.
I don't like his face at all.
He must have been very attached to the child.
* Music *
But my little one, how can you get so excited, it's already good.
My dear little one.
There she is.
Well?
But I was...
I was...
Frankfurt, station number one!
Here we are.
Why do you stand there? You're a little surprised about Frankfurt, aren't you?
Come on.
So now Heidi was in Frankfurt, in the city where she was supposed to live
against her will now.
Aunt Dede was right. Heidi was really surprised.
Never in her life would she have believed that there would be so many big and
quiet houses in a single city.
Heidi walked through the streets with an open mouth and open eyes and looked at
everything.
And again and again she asked herself: Do I like it now or do I not like it?
Do I want to stay here now or do I want to go back home right away?
But even before she arrived at the house of the Sesemann family with Aunt Dete,
Heidi knew that she wanted to go back.
Right in the morning she wanted to get on the train and drive home.
While Heidi was walking through the streets of Frankfurt, Clara Sesemann was
impatiently waiting for the arrival of the little girl,
that she should spend the time in the future.
Clara was the only daughter of the merchant Sesemann.
She was very sick and had to sit in the wheelchair all day.
It takes too long. Time doesn't want to pass. Maybe the clock has stopped.
They should have been here long ago. I don't understand.
Clara, Clara, you're slowly coming to me like a broken game clock.
You say the same thing all the time. Don't you notice anything new?
No.
I don't want to be impulsive, but can I disturb Miss Rottenmeier so late?
I have no idea.
I had promised Miss Rottenmeier to come by with the child.
Do you know if she's at home this afternoon?
Then ring Sebastian. He must be there. He knows exactly what to do.
Yes, if you think so. Thank you.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Heidi, come on, what is it?
Are you afraid?
You can't get out of the traffic jam anymore.
The Sesemann family is one of the richest families here in Frankfurt.
You will definitely like it. They are very nice.
May I stay here?
What can I do for you?
I would like to speak to Miss Rottenmeier. Do you know if she is at home?
Hmm...
That is difficult to answer.
Why?
Unfortunately, you have to ring one more time and ask Ms. Lanquinette.
Yes, please. What do you want, madame?
I would like to speak to Miss Rottenmeier.
My name is Dete. I have an appointment with Miss Rottenmeier.
If you would please tell her that I am here.
Very well.
Let's go back home
Don't talk stupid stuff, we can't go back, understand that at last
They are waiting
Oh thank you, that's very friendly of you
Go Heidi and behave yourself
Be always nice and polite and if someone asks you, you answer
And if you say good day, you make a nod and don't poke your nose
Thank you
Miss Dette is here.
So, there we are.
Yes.
This is Heidi, my niece.
Good day.
I told you about her.
We just arrived.
Aha!
- Where are you going? - Don't stand around like a nag. Say something.
- You shut up. There's only one person talking here. - Yes, of course. Excuse
me.
- If you happen to be able to speak, can you tell me your name? - Heidi.
- Erbarmung! What a name! That's not your real name.
What name did you get married to?
And if the bride is not too comfortable, then maybe she has the kindness to
share this name with you.
- I already told him. - How dare you!
Why are you talking to me like that?
Isn't the child smart in the head?
Or is it just rude, cheeky and loud?
She's just a little scared at the moment.
Maybe I can answer for her.
She's not used to such an environment.
She's neither cheeky nor rude.
She just always says exactly what she thinks.
Heidi has never lied, as far as I know.
Why are you touching me?
But of course Heidi also has a baptismal name, her name is Adelheid, she was
named after her mother, after my deceased sister Adelheid.
But we never called her that, that's why she doesn't know it. Heidi is shorter
and calls herself better.
Aha, I understand. A very good name.
Yes.
I can't help it, but didn't you misunderstand me, lady?
Misunderstood?
Yes, I was looking for a playmate in Clara's age. She's never twelve.
I said explicitly that I was looking for someone who could study with Clara.
Who is spiritually mature.
But that's for sure. Heidi understands very quickly. She's an eloquent, smart
child and very lively. I know, she's a little small, but that disappoints.
I don't know exactly. I think she's a little over ten or...
But I know. Grandfather said I'm eight years old.
Calm down. The child is only eight years old? How terrible.
Don't always say such stupid things.
Is it bad if you're eight?
Dede, she's four years younger than Clara. What should the two of them start
with each other?
But Heidi is especially clever for her age, really.
And which book have we used for our reading studies?
I've never had a book.
I think I'm going to get hit right now.
Did you mean to say that you can't read at all and can't write?
Peter can't read either, and he even went to school once.
You haven't even gone to school, you liar, my child.
Or are you saying the truth after all?
And something like that in our house?
Oh world, what's going to happen to you with so many uneducated people?
Have you ever learned anything in your life?
Well, you ask questions.
I can whistle on my fingers and watch out for the goats and even milk.
Calm down!
No wonder I have a headache. I'm just wondering why you brought this child here,
Dete.
Because Heidi is exactly like the girl you were looking for for Clara.
At least that's what they described her to me.
Never!
Oh yes, that's what they have. They were looking for a girl with a good
character.
She should be well raised, not lie, understand quickly and waste Clara's time.
And this description fits exactly with Heidi.
First of all, they should take better care of her. Then they'll see that I'm
right.
I'm sorry, I have to go. My master is waiting for me.
I'll come by in the next few days and see how she's doing.
Stop going and just leave the child here!
Get out of here!
Aunt Dete had left her alone in this strange big house with these strange girls
and with Miss Rottenmeier, who always said condolences.
Clara was very nice, but the others, how were they?
Heidi felt very, very lonely for the first time in her life.
There were so many people here in this big city, but she knew nobody except Aunt
Dete.
Frankfurt. How was Heidi supposed to see the mountains from here that she loved
so much?
The house, the big crown lights, all of that scared us.
The many forks and knives on the table, the white tablecloth, the admonitions
and explanations of Miss Rottenmeier.
Everything was unusual and new for Heidi.
There was Tinette, the maid, who always complained to Clara about the servant
Sebastian.
And of course there was Clara.
Whether Clara could ever become such a good friend as Peter?
Heidi thought about it and made a decision.
But we want to tell you about it in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges