♪
♪ Heidi ♪
♪ Your world are the mountains ♪
♪ Because up here you are at home ♪
♪ Dark ♪
♪ Bees ♪
♪ Green meadows in the sunshine ♪
♪ Heidi ♪
♪ You need to be happy ♪
♪ Halla Heidi, Halla Heidi ♪
♪ Halla Heidi, Halla Heidi, Halla Heidi ♪
♪ Holla rhy-yi-yi ♪
♪ Holla hyi-yahoo ♪
♪ Heidi ♪
♪ Heidi, Heidi ♪
♪ come home, find your happiness ♪
♪ please come back home ♪
Mrs. Dieter had given Heidi to the Sesemann family.
Mr. Sesemann was on a trip and was represented by Mrs. Rottenmeier when Heidi
arrived.
Mrs. Rottenmeier was the housekeeper and was responsible for Clara's well-being,
Mr. Sesemann's crippled daughter.
Although Mrs. Rottenmeier herself had wanted a playmate for Clara,
she seemed to have been very disappointed by Heidi.
The End
- Never! - Oh, yes, you have that.
You're looking for a girl with a good character.
She should be well-educated, not lie, understand quickly and waste Clara's time.
And this description fits exactly on Heidi.
You should deal with her better first, then you'll see that I'm right.
I'm sorry, I have to go. My master is waiting for me.
I'll come by in the next few days and see how she's doing.
Do you understand to leave the house without the child?
Stop your mouth!
Dete! Dete!
Wait!
Oh dear!
Aunt Dete!
If Aunt Dede leaves, I won't know how to get home.
She forgot to tell me.
You don't have to go home anymore.
Yes, I want to go back tomorrow.
I envy you.
You're doing really well.
You can go anywhere you want.
Yes, but that's nothing special. Everyone can do that.
I don't understand that.
My legs are paralyzed.
How bad.
Then you always have to sit in the chair with the wheels.
I'm sorry.
Do you want me to call you Adelheid?
No, my name is Heidi.
Aunt Dede invented Adelheid.
Heidi suits you much better anyway.
My name is Clara.
But that's true.
Your name suits you too.
Good day, Heidi.
Nice to have you here.
Good day, Clara.
Do you like it here in Frankfurt?
No.
Yes, but why not?
Because I want to go back home to my grandfather.
And if I can go, I'll take a lot of white rolls with me.
Don't you like it here because of Fr. Rottenmeier?
Oh, he didn't have to do anything for you.
She's always like that.
She can only scold.
If you want, I can teach you how to read.
It's not difficult at all.
I have many books that we can read. Maybe then everything is not so terribly
boring anymore.
I can always sit down.
You are the first girl that I see that can not read yet.
I mean, you are at least eight years old, then everyone can do it.
I do not.
That's right, but that's not possible. Everyone has to learn to read at some
point.
You too?
No! What a terrible person! Just bring me this child into the house and then
disappear again.
But I will not let that happen.
I will not let that happen.
Sebastian!
Yes?
Is dinner ready?
If I'm not mistaken, it's ready.
Then please make sure Clara comes to dinner.
Yes, will be taken care of.
Now tell me, do I have cream on the bake?
You look exactly like my friend Peter.
Do I have a doppelganger?
Oh!
Yes.
I don't want you to get involved with the servants.
That's not part of it.
Adelheid, what are you still waiting for? Please sit down.
A whole head full of white bread!
Adelheid!
Don't you have any table manners at all?
Since when do you climb on the table?
You'll get a bun when you wake up.
I didn't want it for myself.
I wanted to bring it to the grandmother.
No, no, no, no apologies.
Sit down properly and behave like a well-groomed little girl.
What did I just deserve that for?
In any case, you seem to have strange instincts.
You're on the chair, my dear child.
*sigh*
Thank you very much, Sebastian.
No need to thank me.
Grandmother, when you were little, did you also tie a bouquet of flowers?
Oh yes!
And what a beautiful one!
I'll hang the bouquet around the door and around the window.
Then it will look much more beautiful.
No, I'd rather have that one.
A white bun.
Can I have some of that too?
Yes.
I've got a plate again.
Now have some water, Heidi, or the plate will fall off.
Yes, thank you.
Oh, that must be the cap.
My dears.
It almost looks like you have to learn everything from the beginning.
You don't even seem to know the simplest rule of the table.
Number one: If you are served the meat, you lay it out like this.
Have you seen that now? It's very easy.
And then I noticed second that you talk too much with the staff.
Please just tell them if you want to have something from them.
They only use too much friendship. They need the strictness.
If you want something from Sebastian, just say "I want this and that" or "please
be so kind and bring me this and that" and no personal words, otherwise you do
nothing else than talk about it in the kitchen.
Let's come to Clara. Clara is being talked to by Miss Clara in this house, but
if she wants that in your case, she has to decide for herself.
Heidi should call me Clara.
Well, that would be regulated now.
Heidi should call me Peter.
Peter!
Oh, where am I?
Good morning, Grandfather!
Piep can fly!
We're already there!
We brought something for you. The very first spring flower.
That's very sweet. Give it to me.
Smell it. It smells like spring.
Then the winter is finally over.
Help! Be fast! Slow down!
I want to, but I can't!
Adelheid, do you even listen to me?
Adelheid, answer me!
I talked to you!
Don't you notice that she fell asleep?
That can't be true!
Oh, Snooki...
Do you wish, madam?
Bring this unheard child to bed immediately!
* Music *
Beep, beep, beep, beep! Come!
Ouch! Ouch!
Where am I?
Oh, in Frankfurt. What kind of room is that?
Hm, still. So I was just dreaming.
This room looks like a dark box.
Behind that could be the window, but why are they hanging it up?
I can do it!
I want to see if the sun is shining and if the tannins are rustling in front of
the house.
* Music *
I have to see if it's raining today.
Please come back home!
Thanks for watching and see you in the next video!
Snuggie, Joseph, Peter, Grandfather, I want to go home, where are you all?
Bärli, Schwänli, Grandmother, Peter, get me, please come and get me!
Grandfather, Peter, I'm here!
Catch me, I can't hold on anymore!
Peter, Snuggie, wait!
Ouch, my head!
I'm not in the mountains.
Disgust!
Now she's sitting on the floor again.
Don't you have enough chairs in the room?
And didn't you hear me knocking?
I knocked.
And when I knock, I expect an answer.
Yes.
Don't forget it again.
And now get up.
Your breakfast is served.
You're a little late today anyway.
You seem to be a little hard of hearing, my child.
I said you should get up.
Adelheid, do you want to just stand there? I'll let you go.
Adelheid, please show me some more obedience.
What's wrong with you?
Are you hard of hearing?
I told you to stand on your feet, Adelheid!
Adelheid!
I'm not Adelheid at all! I'm Heidi!
Your baptismal name is nobility and for this reason I will also call you
nobility.
Get used to it.
But my name is Heidi now.
That could suit you.
And now come.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Adelheid, your teacher will be here at 10 o'clock.
I hope that you will be in the study room on time and that you will behave well.
Clara, I expect from you that you will not be distracted.
I am very glad that you came, Heidi.
Now I am at least not alone as I used to be.
Adelheid!
Yes?
Please wait with Clara until the teacher comes.
But be kind and don't upset her.
Clara is very sick.
All the best.
What are you doing there at the window?
Do you want to climb out?
No, I just want to look out!
Didn't it hurt terribly?
No, it didn't hurt at all.
Where can I look out of this house?
Are the windows closed or too high for me?
Why do you want to look out?
I think I've never seen out of the window.
Don't you want to know what's outside?
Aren't you curious at all?
I've never been outside in my life.
I've been in this house since I was born.
I don't even know what I should be curious about.
Oh, no.
I have an idea. Why don't you ask Sebastian? He knows for sure. He knows his way
around.
Oh, yes, thank you. Sebastian looks like Peter. He knows for sure.
But be careful that Mrs. Rottenmeier doesn't catch you.
Yes, I'll do that.
Sebastian! Sebastian, wait!
Stay still, Sebastian!
What can I do for you?
Careful that Mr. Rottenmeier doesn't catch us!
I would have missed that.
I wish for this and that.
Could you do this and that for me?
Yes, of course.
But how am I supposed to understand that?
Do you wish for this or that?
Miss Rottenmeier said I should talk to you like this. And what Miss Rottenmeier
says, you have to do it too.
Yes, I know, Miss Rottenmeier. And what am I supposed to do for you, little
Miss?
Be careful! Please don't call me Miss all the time. My name is Heidi.
Yes, I know. But Miss Rottenmeier said I should do it, and you can't do anything
about it.
It doesn't matter either. I want to show you something up there.
Yes, I know. But Miss Rottenmeier said I should do it, and you can't do anything
about it.
I want to show you something up there.
What are you doing here?
I'm going to the bathroom.
A little moment, yes?
Oh, thank you.
That's much better.
Finally my window is open and I can see outside.
To be continued...
But where are the flowers?
And where are the meadows and the fir trees?
You can't see anything at all.
There are still houses and stones and streets here.
Heidi, are you satisfied? Can you move something?
But Miss Clara, should I push it for you?
Yes, good.
Would you like to go back to your mountains?
Do you love the mountains so much?
Oh, so you can't do anything about it.
I thought we could be friends, Heidi, but you can't stand it here in Frankfurt.
Should I tell Mr. Rottmeier to get your aunt?
Yes, please do that.
I think it's a shame. I like you. It would have been very funny...
...if I hadn't been able to get along with the two of us.
I like you too, but I think, you know...
Then I'm alone again.
Slowly I should have gotten used to it.
When I was little, my mother died.
And my father was on business trips all the time.
It was always full of Rottnmeier for me, you know?
It's so boring that I don't know how to stand it.
Always full of Rottnmeier.
I can't stand her eternal warmth anymore.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Clara, wait!
I thought about everything again.
I'll stay here.
Yes?
Yes, for at least a few more days.
For sure?
I'll stay here.
When I'm already in Frankfurt, I have to find the presents that I want to bring
home to the others.
Tobacco for the grandfather, a pipe for Peter and many white buns. A whole
suitcase full.
Heidi, I'm so happy.
Can you help me, Clara, that I get all the things when I want to go home?
Yes, of course, I'll do that.
Mrs. Clara!
Heidemarie!
Uh, Adelheid.
Heidemarie is not bad either.
I like Heidi better.
Do you know how we can call her?
No, how?
We just call her Mrs. Warmth.
Yes, we do.
He's been awake for half an hour. Oh, warm-up, my nerves can't stand it.
And this terrible child has messed it all up. And this noise. Discipline!
So Heidi had decided to stay in the Sesemann house.
She got along well with Clara, even with the schoolteacher,
if she only knew what he wanted from her.
At home in the mountains, she had never asked anyone about all the strange
things.
Heidi found the life here in this house sometimes very strange.
Everything was so difficult.
They made the simplest things wrong.
They locked birds in cages and were angry when they were released.
And even a rottmeyer, who always knew everything,
didn't want to see that birds fly better outside than inside.
And then there was the thing with the mice.
After all, mice are hungry too.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
♪ Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains. Heidi, Heidi, because up here you
are at home. Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home. ♪
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges