The mountains are the world
Heidi, Heidi
because up here you are at home
dark fir trees
green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
you need to be happy
come home
find your happiness
come back home
Heidi wanted Clara to stay in Frankfurt for a few days.
The sick girl was sorry for her.
And Heidi felt that Clara, despite the many servants, was very lonely.
So you are the little nobility from the mountains?
Don't be afraid of him.
My name is Heidi.
Oh, like that?
Her name is nobility. She just doesn't want to understand it because she's so
stubborn.
No normal child is called Heidi.
Besides, it's not your job, Miss Clara, to push the chair.
We have servants in the house for that. They can do something for their wages.
Why? It's fun for me.
Nonsense!
Excuse me, Mr. Candidate. You won't have it easy.
She has no manners at all.
She confuses us with the staff.
And I tell you, she has never read the Bible in her life.
Well, Heidi can't read, but she knows many other things.
Her name is nobility, remember that.
Go and wait in the study room. I have something to discuss with your teacher.
Fine, then we can talk.
Bring the children to the study room and close the door, please.
I'm terribly desperate. I fell in. What should I do?
Oh, what? It will be. All we need is time.
Best I start with the alphabet.
No, that would throw Mrs. Clara back.
Should she deal with the alphabet again now?
No, you have to go on where you are now.
That's impossible. I can't answer that.
Oh yes, if you put in the effort, then you can do it too.
Please, I know you, but you will surely come up with a solution.
Why are you stooping all the time?
I can't sit well on the chair.
Is it too hard for you?
No, no, too soft.
What kind of chairs did you sit on in the mountains?
Wooden chairs. Grandfather made a chair especially for me.
You could sit on it so well.
Yes, that's for you.
Mine?
Joseph, I have a chair! My first...
My own chair! Chair, chair, chair! What a beautiful chair!
If you tip over, we'll be scolded again. That's not a swing chair. Be careful.
Can't you move when you learn?
Yes, that's exactly how it is.
You have to sit still, listen to the teacher and be careful that you don't miss
anything.
Oh...
But the stupid thing is, if you sit still all the time, you usually get tired.
But you're going to hurt.
What?
I'm not allowed to walk when I'm tired?
No, for heaven's sake.
And that's what you call studying.
I really imagined something completely different from that.
I think that's too boring for me. I'm not taking part in that.
Don't you want to learn to read?
Joseph walks 20 times a day and Grandfather never shouts.
And who is this Joseph who walks 20 times a day?
A big, lovely dog, of course.
If you walk here, you have to swallow medicine right away.
I don't even know what to do with it. It's so bitter that you get sick right
away.
That's why go first when ...
Between the two of us, everything would probably be discussed.
We will continue in the school hour where we were standing yesterday.
Understood?
I suspect it will be a bit difficult for you at the beginning.
But it will be fine with a little effort.
We're here.
Here?
Here.
Let's find out what you can do at all.
The difficulties of German big and small writing do not exist for other
languages,
because they have gone over to the small writing of all words with the exception
of the name and the sentence at the beginning.
You always write the first word of a whole sentence in large.
This is how you write in the cow comes home the big.
We always had goats.
Second, you always write big after a double point. An example, instructions for
use, double point.
You take a spoonful of rizinus oil every two hours. In this case you write man,
of course, big. Third, you write all the main words big.
Heaven, earth, childhood, family, responsibility, stranger, dog, cat, chicken,
canary, bird, flowers, grasses, trees, wind, sun, mountains, water, land, sleep,
dream, happiness, spring, winter, snow, hare, deer, aunt, mother, father, uncle,
sister, brother, friend, grandfather.
The grandfather is there? Where? Don't run away, I'm coming.
Oh dear.
Manu!
Grandfather!
Grandfather, we're up here! 老大,我们在这里!
Oh no! Oh no! Oh no! 噢不!噢不!噢不!
The carpet, the ink, the diva, quick, quick! 快点,快点,快点!
To help, to help! 帮帮!帮帮!
Of course, as always, no one to help! 当然,无人帮帮!
Grandfather! 老大!
Now I have already dreamed again.
No trees and no mountains.
I am in Frankfurt, no grandfather and no Peter and no goats.
Oh, Deloitte!
Now I am curious what excuse you come up with again.
I thought the grandfather had come.
And I thought I could hear the wind and see the firs and the mountains and the
flowers.
Trees? Here in Frankfurt?
Uh-huh.
You're talking nonsense. We're not in the forest.
Come back in. We can't interrupt your class because of you.
Not so fast!
Take a look at what you've done, Adelheid.
I'm really sorry.
If you don't sit on the chair in the future, I'll tie you up, understood?
I can now see how I can get the stain off again, because you did it.
I'm really sorry. I can help him.
Leave your fingers out of it. I don't want to get in any more trouble.
Mrs. Clara is waiting in her room for you.
I should arrange that.
Yes?
You had dreamed of the mountains.
Do you still not like it here in Frankfurt?
No, I will never like it as much as at home.
I can't even imagine what it looks like there. Can you describe it?
Yes, I can try it, but it takes a lot of time, you know.
We have them.
Yes, but ...
His name is Hansi. I got him for his birthday.
Why did you lock Hansi in a cage?
What?
Birds want to fly free. That's why they have wings.
If I let him fly free, will he fly away?
I once had a bird that was allowed to fly anywhere. His name was Peep.
What? You can't keep a bird without a cage.
Yes, Peep did. I pulled him up and let him fly free.
That must have been very nice.
Oh yes, and how!
But the bird wasn't my only friend. I have so many friends in the mountains.
Really?
At least a hundred thousand.
Open a drawer.
They're not alive, but I like them very much.
She looks like you.
It's a sleeping doll. She can open and close her eyes.
She looks very lively.
I have a lot of nice things. Open the closet.
More dolls?
Are these all your clothes?
Yes, of course. Do you have as many clothes as me?
Me?
Is this your only dress? There's more in the closet.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Do all animals belong in the hut?
Yes, of course.
Grandfather also gave me one.
Wait, I'll get it.
What do you say to that?
Oh, I've never seen such a hat before.
Adelaide here? Without my explicit permission, you have nothing to look for
here.
She can't do anything about it. I wished that she came here.
Then you just wished something wrong.
This room will only be entered if I have given my consent to it.
Did I express myself clearly?
Yes.
Come.
Adelaide!
Mrs. Clara has to rest in the afternoon.
At this time you can do whatever you like.
But please don't put this disgusting hat on your head!
No!
Who knows if this hat has even been in the goat stable?
Horrible thought!
Give me my hat back! No!
I want my hat back!
Why is she so mean?
My hat, my own!
A hat, a hat, a hat, a hat, my hat, I have my own hat, a hat, a hat, a good one,
a good one.
Peacock, come back, look at my hat. Grandfather gave me a hat.
Slow down!
Thanks for watching and see you next time!
Do you want to fly back home into the mountains?
I would love to.
Come out!
You can fly home. I'm here now. Clara is not alone anymore. Come on, Peep Matt.
Don't be afraid.
That's good.
Peep, Matz.
Around and around in a circle.
And now I'll open the window for you.
Then you can fly outside.
What are you waiting for? The window is open. Come on, Piepmatz.
Greet Piepmatz from me when you should see him, okay?
Or come on.
Oh! Oh! Oh no! I move very calmly.
Stay still! Don't move! Don't scare my children!
Hansi, hurry!
Hansi, Hansi, Hansi, Hansi, Hansi, Hansi, Hansileute, Hansileute!
Oh dear, what is that?
It must be Heidi.
Why? If it goes on like this, I'll die!
The favorite bird of Mrs. Leibniz!
What are they doing there?
Are you going to get away from me, you nasty child?
No, stop!
I didn't want to do anything bad, my bird was allowed to...
You can fly anywhere you want, Hansi, I'm sorry, no bird wants to be in the
cage.
Oh, what? Oh, what? Oh, what? I'm sorry for your eternal apologies.
You'll be locked up for as long as you come to your senses, bastard.
Whoever doesn't want to hear must feel.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
It's cold in here.
icecold
It's very quiet without you.
Tinette, please go and get this terrible child out of the basement.
Yes, Mademoiselle Rottenmeier.
You may come out.
Mademoiselle Rottenmeier said you should come, Adelaide.
Now hurry up.
Oh, you're impossible.
Come with me.
What's wrong with her?
Mademoiselle, come quickly, quickly, quickly, this terrible child!
Stop screaming at this point!
What are you doing down there?
Adelheid, what are you doing there with your skirt?
Shut up!
You seem to have improved and want to show something.
Aren't they cute in Rottenmeier?
Yes.
Mice! Mice!
Real mice?
Don't let them fall! I'll hit you!
They don't do anything.
Look, they are so cute.
Look at them.
You're right, somewhere they are very cute.
They are nice, but rather take them away, yes?
If they stay away for so long, their mother thinks they have run away.
Well, if you think so.
Clara, why did they get so upset earlier?
Just like that.
Look how fast they are.
No one is picking them up anymore.
No more mice to be seen, Madame.
Are you sure? Maybe there is one left.
There is nowhere to find the smallest spark of a mouse.
Don't worry.
I will make sure that this is true.
All mice are on and off.
Take care of the tapes, Madame.
My poor nerves.
Another day like this and I have to change my job.
Poverty.
Screaming doesn't help at all.
You didn't do it any other way.
I'm cold.
The bird is back!
Yes, imagine it. It came back.
But I knew all along that it was coming back. It belongs here.
What happened? Why didn't you fly home to the mountains?
He feels better in his cage than somewhere out there.
Here he is at home. Out there he is strange.
No, no, no, I don't believe that.
But Heidi, not everyone is like you. The bird doesn't know your mountains at
all.
He is like me. He feels good here in this house because he hasn't met anything
else yet.
Never.
Oh yes, this bird is happy here with me.
You pulled up your bird, I pulled up this one.
But first you have to see how happy the birds are in the mountains when they can
fly freely over the meadows.
They flutter and fly high through the air, all the way up to the sky and higher
and higher and fly and fly and fly and fly and fly and fly.
Did I offend you?
Kids, dinner is ready!
Huh?
This time we have to hurry, otherwise we'll be scolded again.
Okay, let's go! Hold on tight!
You know what, Clara? I just thought of something.
One day I'll take you to the mountains and show you everything.
And when you've seen everything, then you'll know what I meant with the bird.
I promise you, you'll see it for sure. The flowers and the meadows and the grass
and the mountains.
The mountains are so beautiful, you can't even imagine that.
There are flowers and goats everywhere, their bells are ringing and the flowers
are smelling.
And at the top of the mountain there's sometimes snow even in the summer.
Believe me, Clara, I'll take you to Dörfli and then to our island.
Clara didn't know Heidi well enough to know that Heidi never forgot everything
she had in mind in life.
And when Heidi promised her friend Clara to show her beloved mountains, she kept
that promise.
And then one day she would show her the mountains.
But there was still a long way to go.
And Heidi still had many adventures to go on in the big city of Frankfurt, for
example the one with the little organ player from the corner of the house, which
she briefly invited to play Fräulein Rottenmeier.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains, Heidi, Heidi, because up here you
are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.
To be continued