Holadio
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Dark fir trees, green meadows in the sunshine.
Heidi, Heidi, you need to be happy.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness.
Come home.
Come back again.
Heidi lived for a week in the house of the Sesemann family in Frankfurt.
She was a lot with Clara together, took part in the lessons and learned to get
Mrs. Rottenmeier out of the way.
The others seemed as if Heidi had found her new life.
I just don't want to believe it. No bird likes to be locked up in a cage.
Hansi grew up in the cage.
Just like me. I've never come out of the house either. I'm here at home.
The next morning.
No reason to sigh.
I'm always sitting here in my room, but I've seen a lot anyway.
On maps and pictures.
I know all the animals from these pictures.
How cute.
Do you really like the kittens?
Yes, I like them very much.
Then I'll give it to you. You can keep it.
I can keep it? You'll give it to me?
Why not? But hide it from Mrs. Rottenmeier. She just can't stand animals.
That's why she got so excited when I brought the mice from the cellar with me.
I'd rather hide it well.
There was another picture I wanted to show you. Yes, that one. Does your house
look like that?
No. We don't have a house. We have a hut. A small hut made of wood with fir
trees in front of the door and a big fireplace in our living room.
Really? Yes.
And in front of the hut, right next to the door, is a wooden bench.
Phew, the stool is quite heavy.
The stool is the bench, on which I sit every morning.
And here sits the grandfather and notices the goats, Schwendi and Berli.
And sometimes I help him with it. I can notice.
Don't worry, Schwendi, I won't hurt you.
That's how good it is, good boy.
Schwendi always has a lot of milk.
Goat milk is healthy, you don't believe how good it tastes.
I'm thirsty.
What's going on now? Why are you screaming?
But that was Joseph!
Oh, of course!
Peter is coming with the goats! Joseph wanted to tell me that!
Peter, hurry up!
Stop! Watch out! You'll break your legs!
Schnucki, you shouldn't always run around like that.
That's Peter you're copying now.
Schnucki barks at him. He always comes running to me.
Holla, holla, off you go!
Again and again, Schnucki.
Is the mountain so steep?
Well, what do you think? You have to climb quite a bit before you get there.
So, now he's arrived.
Ah, good.
Peter always stands far away. He never dares to go into the hut.
Why?
He's afraid of my grandfather.
Good morning, goat general.
Good morning, good morning.
Good morning.
Yes, good morning, Almöhi.
Why Almöhi?
Oh, Mr. Peter and the people down in the village, they call my grandfather that.
Good morning, goat general.
Good morning, good morning, good morning.
Did you have breakfast today?
Yes, but not enough.
Hurray!
We live in the mountains.
We dance with the dwarfs.
We talk with the trees and fly in the dreams.
Hurray, hurray, hurray, hurray.
We don't live in Africa.
We live in the mountains and dance with the dwarfs.
Sing along, Klara. It always starts from the beginning.
We live in...
Ciao! I can't sing!
The Grandfather and Joseph!
Good morning, General Siegen.
Good morning, Admiral.
That's what they say every morning.
Did you have breakfast today?
Not enough.
Let's go! Hurry!
Peter!
Wait for me!
Peter, Snooki, Swenli, Berli.
Peter!
Wait!
Where is Peter?
Where is he?
Peter! Wait!
Oh, that was a nice game. That was fun. You can whistle.
Yes. Peter taught me. It's very easy.
That never works the first time. You have to practice a lot first.
Listen, he whistled with you.
Of course, that's what I could have thought. The nobility.
I just tried to teach Clara how to whistle on her fingers.
Calm down! How can you dare to let Clara whistle on her fingers?
It was my fault. I wanted Heidi to tell me everything about her mountains.
What about the mountains? What is there to say about that?
Put your noses in the school books.
But Heidi's story was nice. I liked it better than the boring books.
I know better stories.
Of the goats, and the dog, and the grandfather?
I want to hear all the stories you know.
Goats and dogs?
Yes, and wild goats, and sometimes even an eagle.
No, no, no!
But...
I wish that you stop wasting your time.
No more stories of this kind in this house, understood?
Miss Clara comes from a good house, and I will not let her education be ruined
by you.
Understood?
Yes.
I'm sorry, Heidi. You were scolded because of me.
But I wanted you to tell me.
I want to know what the grandfather is doing now.
And Peter and the blind grandmother.
Do you have a home in the mountains, Heidi?
If you look out the window, you can only see stones and houses.
Why don't you go up to the tower? There's a window and you can see out there.
Maybe you can see more than just houses from there.
And how do I get there? I don't even know where the tower is.
Always the stairs up, then you'll get there.
Thank you, Clara. Maybe I can see the mountains from there.
But be careful. Be careful that Mr. Rottenmeier doesn't catch you there.
I'll be careful. I don't want to be scolded again today.
Then please come back right away and tell me what you saw from up there.
Psst! Psst!
Pssst, the animal doesn't get me!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7...
Even higher!
8, 11, 13, 17...
1, 2, 3...
Thanks for watching!
Ow!
Help!
Don't tell anyone!
Do you really want that, Heini?
Yes.
What can you see from the other side?
I don't know what you mean.
Can you see the mountains from there?
The house is not high enough for that.
You probably have to climb to a higher building.
Good. But where do I find a house that is high enough, Sebastian?
Well, certainly a church tower would be sufficient.
Is there one in Frankfurt?
No city without a church tower.
At least I don't know one without one.
Please.
Um, there should also be a clock tower could also be enough, or the roof of the
park, or a flag mast, but I still miss that one.
But I think the church tower would be the best in your case.
But why...
Heidi, Heidi!
Oh dear, oh dear, oh dear.
Finally in the fresh air!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
It can't be Sebastian's idea.
There's apple on the table!
Where's the tower?
I saw him very clearly. He was there.
Strange.
Oh!
Well, what are you?
Why are you snoring?
Then, the devil must have heard you!
I like my music. I wish I had a music box like that.
Then pay something.
Why should I pay something?
Everyone has to pay.
You know what's funny? The church tower has disappeared.
So if you can laugh about it, I'm sorry.
Actually, I can't laugh about it either, but I'm looking for it so much.
What do you pay if I show you one?
I know where one is and I can take you there.
But then you have to pay me something.
Yes, that's good.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Do you want this?
What am I supposed to do with this dull picture? You can keep it.
Why don't you like it?
Good, then I can keep it. My friend Clara gave it to me.
Unfortunately, I don't have anything else.
No money?
No, I've never had any money in my hand.
Aha.
But I think Clara has a lot of money.
If I ask her, she'll definitely give you something.
Good. How much?
As much as you want, Clara, isn't that nice?
Come with me, I'll show you where it is.
I'll show you where it is.
It's closed.
We'll get in somehow.
Hello!
Is anybody there?
Such a big house can't be empty. Someone has to be there.
Don't bother, there's no one there.
At Pia's, there's no one there. Don't forget my money!
No!
Hopla!
Come on, Trant, you're bigger than me.
Leave it.
There's no one there anyway, and if there is, they won't let us in.
But if I ask, I just want to see down from the tower.
Why shouldn't I do that?
Oh, that can take some time.
Hopefully you won't forget my twenty pence.
I don't want any more.
How much? I didn't understand.
Exactly twenty pence.
Huh?
There must have been those lousy boys at the bell again.
Was that you?
Good day. May I climb on your tower? I want to see the mountains.
What do you want? That's impossible.
You call me out because you want to climb on my tower?
Has someone sent you?
So, you want to climb on my tower?
You are mistaken. I won't let you take me on your arm.
Go on, do it so you can come home. But quickly!
The world has not yet experienced that. Will climb the tower.
No! Stop! I would like to climb the tower so much!
Please! I would like to know if you can see mountains and meadows from there.
Here you can see houses.
Yes, tell me, do you mean that seriously?
Of course I mean that. There are only houses and streets here and there are
stones everywhere.
Yes, you know, the stairs are not that easy for such a little girl.
Oh, I can do that.
Hold on, you can't do it alone.
Yes, I don't need help.
Yes, I can do that.
But child, why are you running so fearfully?
Yes, tell me.
Why are you still standing? You're right, you just have to climb up the ladder.
Am I up then? Thank you!
For heaven's sake, not so fast, be careful!
Well, wait a minute, I'll help you.
So.
Yes, what do you say? Isn't that a nice view?
But where are the mountains?
I want to go down, thank you.
Oh, over there.
May I look down from this side?
Of course.
Where are the mountains, the meadows and the meadows?
You wanted to see the mountains, but they don't exist here in Frankfurt.
And no meadows, and no beech trees, and no flowers, and no birds, and no goats.
We don't have goats here, but we have flowers, meadows and beech trees in front
of the city, also very beautiful.
Yes.
Today it is a bit desolate, but on a clear day you can also see a few mountains.
Not as high as the Alps.
But the Taunus is also beautiful. In any case, it is enough for me to climb up.
Well, and our Main back there, is it nothing?
Not as beautiful as my mountains.
There is snow on the peaks, and the sun shines, and the firs smell.
If you look down from a mountain, you can see green meadows.
But you all don't understand that.
Sometimes there is an eagle in the sky, and when you are very quiet, you can see
the marmots and the storks.
Mrs. Rottenmeier doesn't even know what that is. I can't even tell her about it,
and neither can Peter and the goats.
How should the tower guard know what Heidi thought? He meant well with her. He
wanted to comfort her.
But how should he know that his little guest had a home-sickness, after the
rustle of the tall green fir trees, after the fresh scent of the mountain
meadows, and after an old grandfather who was alone somewhere in the mountains
and had just as much home-sickness after the little girl as the girl after him.
Come, child. We have to go down again. I have to lock the door.
To be continued
Come on, it's easier to get down than to get up.
So are you coming soon or not?
I told you I had to lock you up.
It took a while until Heidi discovered the kittens.
You don't have to tell it to you first.
You know them well enough to know that all sadness was gone.
Of course Heidi took the little cats home.
Surely something unthinkable of her.
The Mr. Candidate and Mrs. Rottenmeier with cats in a room?
Not to imagine what could happen there.
Of course Heidi tried to hide the cats.
But it's not that easy either.
Little, lively cats
can't be locked in a sewing box all day long
without being noticed.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains. Heidi, Heidi, because up here you
are at home. Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges