HALLELUJAH
The mountains are the world
Heidi, Heidi
Because up here you are at home
Dark fir trees
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
Do you need to be...
Find your happiness
Come back again
Do you remember? Heidi had secretly sneaked away to look at the mountains from a
high church tower.
But all she saw were houses, stones and, far behind, the Main.
She had climbed up the stairs to the observation deck with so much hope, but on
the way down she was sad and disappointed.
The tower guard tried to encourage her, but what did he know about Heimweh?
Here's what he told us.
I'm tired. I can't walk anymore.
Hush, be quiet.
Little kitten.
Well, do you like the kittens?
I once had a dog and two goats.
Josef, Schweli and Berli.
Why don't you take one?
May I keep a kitten?
Of course.
Thank you, I'll pick one, okay?
You're welcome.
You go out nicely.
Off with you.
Of course she doesn't want to give them away.
Cats.
Does it matter which one I take?
Or is there one that you would like to keep for yourself?
I'll eat it right away.
No, I'll take the dark one.
Or the white one.
Or...
...this one.
From here you can have them all.
I have to see how I'm going to get rid of them anyway.
Do you know the house of Sesemanns?
Everyone in town knows the house.
Then bring the cats there.
The house is so big, everyone fits in there.
Stop!
Children and little animals.
Little white kittens have white tits.
My kitten is so cute.
Let's go on.
This is the house of Sesemanns. We have finally arrived.
Goodbye! Don't forget the money!
No, but wait a moment!
The whole house is in bright excitement. Quick!
Hey, open the door!
I should climb up to the church tower.
Oh dear heaven, if you tell the old scarecrow that I brought you up to the idea,
I will be relieved.
That fits, scarecrow fits.
For God's sake, don't call her that.
Is that a cat or am I dreaming?
I completely forgot. What am I doing now? How do I hide the cat in front of Mrs.
Rottenmeier?
Come in.
Good evening.
Oh, Heidi.
I want to apologize, I'm late.
I know that by myself that you're late.
I didn't have to tell you that leaving the house is a bad habit
and no one to tell you anything about it.
And if you go out in the future, I would like to ask you to be back on time for
the meals.
I don't want to upset my nerves today.
It would make no sense.
You always notice that you don't...
Oh!
Adelheid,
if you intend to make fun of me,
then do it upstairs in your room.
I don't want to. I mean, I can't.
I...
There it is again.
Adelheid, go to your room.
But why?
Now I've had enough.
I'm at the end of my nerve power.
Disappear
and off to bed!
...without dinner!
I'm definitely not following her, Miss Rottenmeier.
It's a real cat.
She's very small and cute.
Help!
Tinette!
You thief!
Cameraman!
Tinette! Sebastian!
Get out of here!
She has a very soft...
Don't be afraid, Phil.
I've never pet an animal before.
Oh, she's as light as a feather.
She can't move at all.
I almost can't feel her. How cute!
How are you, little cat?
Mrs. Quirter.
I'm going to tell Mrs. Rottenmeier
that she can't take part in dinner
and that she wants to start without you.
And I'm going to take care of the cat.
It's my cat. Did you chase it away?
Order from Mrs. Rottenmeier.
The cat stays. She didn't do anything to anyone.
She's small. Without our help, she can't find anything to eat and is starving.
It can't be changed. Mrs. Rottenmeier wants it.
I know what. We'll just bring her up into the tower room.
She'll never dare to go in front of a rotten man.
Oh, yes, we'll do that. That would be great.
Fantastic. A fantastic...
And you, Sebastian, you'll make a warm place up there so she won't be afraid.
She means... she means...
Oh, please, Sebastian, please.
Well, well, well. If you ask me like that, then I can't help it, can I?
Hooray!
I'm relieved too. And you, Kätzchen, are you happy too?
Yes, I'm happy too.
The air is clean.
Be quiet. It will be fine, child.
Hopefully.
We'll take the basket. It will definitely be a good bed.
We just have to put something in it to make it soft.
I've already found something, but we should put it in the room over there.
There it is sunny and better for you.
Oh yes, thank you. Here it is pretty. The sun is shining.
And if she wants, she can see out of the window.
Sebastian, I think it's a beautiful room for a cat, isn't it?
Hopefully it's good enough.
But you have a nice bed, my little kitten.
Can you sleep in it?
She stays in it, she seems to like it.
This and that?
We have to give her a name.
Oh, I'm not particularly good at giving names, you know.
But I have a nice name for her.
What do you think, Mau Mau?
Is she sleeping well? Now we have a secret.
Nice. We must not tell anyone.
And especially not in front of the Rottenmeier.
It's your very, very dear cat. Don't you think so, Heidi?
I think so, too.
One moment, I'll be right done.
And what can I do for you?
Good morning.
Already on your feet?
Pssst.
What is it?
The breakfast for Mau Mau.
Ah, that's what you're worried about, don't worry.
This will taste good for you, and be careful, a rottenmeier.
Wait a moment.
My hat!
No, no, no, my hat is better lifted. You trust me, don't you?
Yes, you are dear, Sebastian.
Mau, Mau?
Mau, Mau!
Mau, Mau, good morning, Mau, Mau.
I asked for your breakfast.
No, no.
Don't you want to get out of there again?
Ah!
You don't do that, Momo!
Your tongue tickles like that of Spendy and Bearly.
But you can't know who that is yet.
That tastes good.
If you eat a lot...
Now you're a big star!
Oh, what did you do to your face?
Oh, that. Maumau scratched me.
That's just a scratch. It doesn't hurt at all.
Oh, Maumau can scratch?
All cats can scratch. That's why they have their claws.
Oh, such a small one?
Mademoiselle Clara!
Oh, there comes Nettie. She mustn't know.
Quickly, take her away!
Maumau! Maumau, come quickly!
This is no game!
Hurry up!
Be a lovely cat and come quickly, Maumau, come! 乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖乖
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Adelheid, in the house of Sesemann it is an unwritten law that you enter the
breakfast room at 8.05 a.m. and not a minute later. Do you understand me?
Yes.
And put your hands on the table as it should be. What did you do to your face,
scratcher?
That? I don't know. I fell out of bed this morning and scratched myself.
That doesn't hurt, that heals quickly.
Take your fingers off the wound. Tinette, get something to disinfect.
Yes.
She doesn't need that. A spit is the best thing to do.
Tinette, please do what I've just told you to do.
You'd better take her out with you right away.
Yes, madam. Come on.
And you'd better give her some anti-fever drops right away.
Yes, I'll do that right away, madam.
Are all the children who grew up in the mountains so careless?
What are we going to do with the child?
Yes, I'll be right there.
One moment, I'm coming.
Oh, what do you want here with us?
Good day.
Aha, I understand, but I can tell you that.
Bed and rest is forbidden in this house.
So make sure you get out of here, get out of here.
Does a little girl live here?
Two little girls live here.
Is one of the two Heidi?
Has she done something again?
So she lives here. I brought her here yesterday.
Then you just brought her here. And now watch out that you get away,
otherwise I'll forget and then it'll be terrible.
I'll get 20 pfennigs from her. She met me on the street yesterday
and promised the money when I showed her a high church tower.
And I did that too.
So, so, 20 pfennigs.
Showing a high tower, met on the street yesterday.
Well, then come on in, maybe we can do something for you.
Come on, Augustin.
Wait here for me and be quiet. I will now call you to Miss Clara.
And as soon as I ask you to come in, you start playing the organ, understood?
What do you think she will be happy about?
Yes, come in.
I regret many times that I have to interrupt the class, but a boy has just come
and wishes to speak to the Blessed Miss.
Oh, I'm getting a visitor. Yes, who is it?
It's a stranger.
Let him come in.
Gladly.
Miss Clara, I have to protest. We can't interrupt the class.
But why not? Now someone has come for the first time and wants to speak to me.
I've never had a visitor before.
Well, but just for a moment. Let him come in, okay?
You may come in now, and don't forget to play on your organ right away.
Come on, Augustin.
What do you mean? Do you want to stop?
But why? It's beautiful!
That should be beautiful? That?
It's nice that you came, little boy.
Oh, you know the boy?
Yes, I met him yesterday in town.
He showed me the way to the church tower.
Do you have time? Can you play something for me?
Yes!
Please play.
Clara, look at his feet!
What music? There's no music on the timetable for today.
And such an ordinary music.
That's what she's up to.
At this point, stop with the noise. Stop that you come out. Leave the house
immediately.
Bring this dragon out of the house immediately.
She's a beautiful girl, don't worry about it.
Ah, Sebastian! Ah, Sebastian!
Get the doctor!
The vet! The chamber hunter!
Ms. Steller, do you have a wish, Mrs. Rottenmeier?
Get rid of this dragon or this...
or whatever it is, out of the house!
As ordered. As Madame wishes.
She could bear that. Well done.
I like your instrument.
I still don't have the 20 pfennigs.
Yes, I know. One moment.
Here, 20 pfennigs for yesterday afternoon,
and for today, because it was especially successful,
another 20.
Thank you.
I'm going to put this very unpleasant matter on the ground after the lesson.
Please, Mr. Candidate, don't let it bother you any further.
The Greeks!
Come in!
Strange.
It's very unpleasant that I have to disturb you, but it's something that was
given to you for Mrs. Clara.
I didn't know what we ordered.
I'll take it.
Open it, Mr. Rottenmeier.
Later, child. After school.
First the work, then the pleasure.
Mr. candidate, please don't stop.
Just a moment.
Don't you want to know?
No.
Aren't you curious at all?
Not at all.
I can't understand that.
Mr. candidate, just one look, okay?
That's up to Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Mrs. Rottenmeier, just one look, please.
I said no.
But I'm so curious. I can't continue learning if I don't know what's in the
basket.
And Heidi doesn't either.
Well, it looks like we've distracted the children now.
It seems so. We should allow you to take a look inside the basket.
Do you consider this to be acceptable?
What should you do? You would only take part in the class unnoticed anyway.
It's better to allow you a little break. Show them what's in the basket and
you'll see, the work will be a lot more fun afterwards.
To be honest, I'm also curious.
Maybe it's about fresh fruit, and fruit is always good for the brain.
What's the matter with you, Mr. Candidate? Can't you get out of here?
Is your behavior strange?
Hello, Mrs. Rottenmeier. No excitement. Everything is fine. Cuckoo. Cat.
What? Cat? Alive?
Oh, Sebastian! The shovel!
Help! Help me!
Help me, Sebastian!
Did you know that? Of course you knew that!
Give me one!
Leave my feet alone! Let me kiss!
Sebastian! Sebastian!
Don't!
Sebastian!
I'll kill you!
What are you doing on the table?
Get out of the way, you disgusting cats!
Yes, madam.
Come on, you little...
Come on!
Listen to me!
Help me!
Don't be afraid, my little one!
Miss Rottenmeier, you have complaints.
That was probably too much for the poor.
It was never so funny here.
I'm sorry that the cats are now being brought back.
They were so cute.
After the excitement, it's no wonder.
But I would love to know where they come from.
Mau Mau, we forgot Mau Mau.
I'll get her.
Yours, Madame.
Oh, this child, this child.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
You should lock her up in the cellar for a whole week.
Lock her up at least one afternoon in the cellar.
Then she'll bring the mice up again.
Oh, they're still there!
Everywhere, I can hear them meowing.
They sit in the corner and laugh at me.
But no, I've taken them all away.
And not forgotten? Not forgotten by any chance?
None.
There she is. She ate well. She ate everything we gave her for breakfast.
Give it to me on the lap, Heidi, please.
There!
Mau Mau, do you know what I think? The other cats also came from where you came
from.
So it was Heidi's fault again.
Oh, that tickles!
Miss Rottenmeier!
What do you think, was it Heidi or was it not?
That was an exciting day for the two of them.
First came the turtledove boy with his turtle and then the many little kittens.
Klara could not remember that she had ever laughed like that before.
Heidi and Clara kept their secret that they were hiding in the tower room well.
Still, Mrs. Rottenmeier was not able to find out where this quiet moaning came
from that she heard.
She still firmly believed that her stressed nerves were giving her the moaning.
And every time she took a headache pill when it meowed.
Of course, Clara and Heidi could laugh about it from the heart.
But then it got dangerous all of a sudden.
Mrs. Rottenmeier discovered something.
But we want to tell you about it in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back home.