This video is dedicated to all of you who have been with us for a long time.
Thank you very much for your support.
The mountains are the world
Heidi, Heidi
Because up here you are at home
Dark fir trees
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
Do you need to be...
to be happy
Heide, heide, heide, heide, heide, heide...
Holla lala lilla lilla lilla holla lilla ho
Heide, Heide, come home
Find your happiness, and come back home
Is it blowing?
Of course! It's a thunderstorm!
Heidi, hurry up! Come on, quick!
I like it!
It's a bit rainy.
Whoever goes first, wins!
I like it!
Snuggie.
Mama is alone up there. She must be scared.
That's terrible. Maumau must be scared too.
Shit!
Mou Mou Mou, I'm Heidi.
Are you scared?
Now it's all good. Now I'm with you.
La, la, la.
Poor little kitty.
Is there someone?
It's me, Heidi.
Come in, there's no one here.
Meow, meow!
Well, you? Were you afraid of the thunderstorm, all alone up there in the tower?
I think we both thought the same thing.
I'd rather keep her in bed with me tonight.
I wish I could keep her with me too.
Well, then let her sleep with you if you want.
Can I keep her?
No, no, you'd better take her. She's used to you.
She doesn't know me as well as you do.
You'd rather have Mr. Rottenmeier come in.
Exactly. And imagine, the cat is in my bed when she comes.
Good night, Mau Mau. Now you don't have to be afraid anymore.
I already know that. Sleep well.
Good night. Sleep well. See you tomorrow for breakfast.
So, Mau Mau, we're here. This is my room.
How do you like the bed? Is it soft enough?
To be continued...
So you like it just as much as your bed.
Don't be afraid, Momo. I'm with you.
Now the thunderstorm can't do anything to you.
Do you want to lie down? How else are we supposed to sleep?
You know it's tickling, right?
Good morning, Mom.
Adelheid, where's Janine? It's time for breakfast.
Fräulein Rottenmeier. Oh dear, what now?
Adelheid, what is it? Answer me!
I'll be right there. I just have to get dressed quickly.
You're still not dressed. You know, breakfast starts at 8.05 a.m.
Yes, I know. I'm in a hurry.
You'll bring me to my senses at some point.
You took quite a long time to get out of bed, Adelheid.
What?
Now I thought you were at least dressed.
I'm sorry.
Sorry, sorry.
All day long, I hear nothing but sorry.
Act like a good kid, then it wouldn't be necessary.
I'm in the call to be a good teacher, but with you...
What's with the fax?
Do you think that's a good thing?
You'd better brush your teeth and then come.
That was good.
Come back quickly!
They're all waiting for you at the table. Hurry up!
Just one minute, then I'll be there.
There will be spiegeleier this morning. They're already on the plate and will
get cold very quickly.
Psst, Mau Mau, you have to be very quiet. You're not allowed to whine.
Psst, be quiet. I'll be right back.
We have Sunday, Mrs. Clara. The class is over.
You should use the time and rest in bed.
For you, Adelheid, that doesn't mean anything.
You should take care of your alphabet.
We want you to be able to follow the class as soon as possible,
and not always lag behind. You want that too, don't you?
I hope that my orders will be followed, even if I'm not there.
I have to leave today, unfortunately. I'm invited.
That doesn't matter, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Please, Miss Clara, don't be like that.
Make sure you have a good night's sleep.
It's good for you.
Yes, I will.
And since I have to meet for preparations,
I have to say goodbye to you.
Goodbye.
Juliette!
Did you give Mama breakfast today?
No, I overslept today.
She's still in my room.
And Miss Rottenmeier didn't see her this morning?
No, I quickly hid her in the cupboard upstairs.
Thank God!
It's better if I get her right away and bring her to the tower.
Careful, Mrs. Rottenmeier isn't gone yet.
You'd better not go past her room.
I would wait at your place until she leaves the house.
That's safer.
You're right, Sebastian.
You know what? I've never seen an animal eat.
I'd like to know how Mau Mau does it.
Bring her in here afterwards and feed her here.
Then I can watch her.
I think it's incredibly cute when she slaps.
Yes! Hooray! It's going to be done!
Shh!
I hear something.
To be continued...
Take care of the house and the children, Sebastian.
Very well, madam.
She's gone.
Good, then I'll give her something to eat. She must be hungry.
Are you hungry, Mau Mau? Poor little Mau Mau, you waited so long.
Why is this door always open?
Be careful.
You can eat that already.
But that was really sweet, Sebastian.
But I liked doing that.
Don't eat here, Mau Mau. Over there with Clara, come.
Here, Mau Mau, eat nicely.
It tastes good. She's eating.
Good girl, my dear cat.
She washes and cleans herself the whole day. I think she's a particularly clean
cat.
You think so?
I'm sure everyone does that.
Mama, you've fallen over.
Today we can at least have a nap again.
I feel like I was born again when the old woman left the house three days ago.
Who could that be?
Miss Rottenmeier, you're back already?
Yes, I forgot something.
Can I help you? I can get it for you.
Don't bother.
But it doesn't really matter to me. Not at all. That's what I'm here for.
What?
Now it's my turn again.
Give me Heidi again.
Yes, that's good.
She doesn't want to stay on my lap.
Then take her away, Heidi.
Hansi must be afraid.
Come on.
No.
Come in.
What is it, Sebastian?
Adelheid, what are you hiding there in front of me?
Adelheid, please look at me when I talk to you.
I just asked you what you were hiding in front of me.
I taught her the alphabet.
That's why she's here with me.
You said yourself that she should learn it, didn't you?
Miss Clara, please have mercy and don't dare to lie again.
Oh, a cat!
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
What now?
I don't know either.
Tinette! Tinette! A cat again!
Bring the terrible animal here immediately!
Oh no! Don't touch her! The cat belongs to me!
I only asked Heidi to watch over her.
Never in life does the cat belong to you, Mrs. Clara!
Oh yes! It belongs to me!
It belongs to me for a long time. Her name is Mau Mau.
So, whatever it is, give the cat to Tinette immediately
and then I want to talk to you, Mrs. Clara.
This is unfortunately impossible for me at the moment.
I don't have time to enter the room. Not as long as the cat is there.
What are you waiting for, Nortonette?
Mrs. Clara!
I can't change it, Heidi. You have to give Mama Tinette, unfortunately.
Please don't hurt her, okay?
Get out of the house with the cat!
Miss Clara, was that the whole truth that the cat belongs to you?
Yes, of course, why not?
I'm sorry, but unfortunately I can't allow you to keep the cat for health
reasons.
Cats transmit diseases and we really can't use that.
I don't have to tell you how sensitive they are, how easy they get infected.
Who knows what the cats are up to outside and what they'll bring in with them.
I can't allow you to keep the cat.
Why does it have to be a cat?
Your father bought you all the toys there are.
He even called the child.
But...
No, the cat has to get out of the house.
And now no more rumors.
To be continued...
In the meantime, Dinette has followed my orders and got the cat out of the
house.
Clara!
You stay out of this, okay?
Understood?
Did you understand too, Miss Clara?
Thank you for watching!
Stay here!
What are you doing? Get the cat out of here!
Right away, madam.
Mau Mau! Give her to me! Mau Mau!
What an insolent name!
How often do I have to tell you to disappear and throw the cat out of the house?
Right away!
Mau Mau!
Clara! Clara! Help me!
No! I want my cat!
You don't want it at all! You stay in there!
And I'll get you out of here as soon as you've come to your senses.
To be continued...
Miss Rottenmeier sent me. She wants you to take your medicine, Mrs. Clara.
Is Heidi still in her room?
No, she has calmed down. You can't hear anything anymore.
I'm surprised. I didn't think she'd calm down.
I thought she wouldn't calm down anymore.
Me too.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Goodbye, Clara. Live well.
What do you pay me when I take you there?
I don't have any money.
Then go to your house.
I'll never go there again. Never.
I want to go home again.
And you want to go with the zoo? I don't think you have any money with you.
Money?
Why are you running away from the rich man's house?
You must have everything you need.
Do you know the kitten? They've chased it away.
And now you're running away too.
Oh, I see.
Did you like to have her?
Take this with you, I'll give it to you.
Don't be afraid, you don't have to pay anything.
Johan! Stop! Johan! Stop it!
What was that?
Johann?
Stop!
Johann!
You impossible...
What have you got here on the street to look for?
So come!
No, I don't want to come with you!
I want to go home! My buns! No!
Where are the buns? Now they're all lost!
I want to go home!
Mr. Rottenmeier, it's something terrible, it's something unbelievable, it's
something very terrible.
Adelaide, imagine, she was in the middle of the city, that's unbearable for me.
Terrible.
Yes.
What could have happened there, she doesn't know her way around the city at all,
at least I'm responsible for her.
Good day, Heidi.
Head up, little girl, we've all been very worried.
Especially Mrs. Clara, she doesn't want to stop crying at all.
I have to tell you something about Maumau.
Tinette gave it to me, and I brought it home to my brother.
It's going very well here. My brother also has two children.
They play with her all day. My brother has a garden.
She can run outside.
Heidi, it's going very well here. Believe me.
Yes.
Well, a little calmer. At least we didn't chase her down the street.
We're going to Clara now. She's already waiting.
Heidi, is Heidi back home?
Heidi, oh Heidi, I'm so happy that you're here.
Please never secretly run away again. I was so scared if you had run away now.
Please Heidi, promise me that you'll never run away again, please.
I couldn't do it, even if I wanted to!
But Heidi...
That was not a nice day for the two girls.
But how could they understand Mrs. Rottenmeier,
who imagined herself to understand so much about children
and yet understood so little about them?
Heidi still had the hope not given up to realize her dream.
She still firmly believed that one day
Grandmother and Brigitte could bring a whole basket full of white rolls.
Heidi could squeak with pleasure at the idea of how she would survive Mrs.
Rottenmeier one day.
She dreamed of sneaking past Antinette in the middle of the night from the house
and riding home on a big rock.
But until this dream could only come true, Heidi still had a lot of difficulties
to experience.
For example, Mrs. Rottenmeier found the white rolls one day.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back again.
Thank you for watching.