Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at the top
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio
Holadio
Every night Heidi dreamed of her favorite dream, because no one can forbid
dreams, not even Miss Rottenmeier.
Good morning, Peter. Here are more rolls.
Are these the rolls you told me about, Grandmother?
Yes, my child, that's what I imagined them to be. I always dreamed of them. Now
I can at least bite them properly.
My roll tastes like raspberry jam.
I'll try to see how it tastes.
Mine tastes like sausage with cream.
How many times do I have to knock?
Good morning, Tinette.
Don't be late for breakfast again.
Miss Rottenmeier is in a terrible mood.
Since you left, what's going on here?
And of course she lets that out on us.
Terrible.
My buns!
I really have a lot of trouble with the child, you can confirm that, but I'm
just not done with her.
Maybe she's not normal, I'm sure. Yes, that's the only explanation.
What do you say to that?
Unfortunately, the question is not as easy to answer as you might think, Miss
Rottenmeier.
On the one hand, she is normal, on the other hand, not.
When you talk to her like that, she makes a reasonable impression.
She is also very awake, but it just makes me sceptical that she still hasn't
learned the alphabet.
I'm asking you, at her age.
Strange. That fits the impression I have of her again.
Without a doubt. She understands quickly and is also extraordinarily independent
for her age.
But the alphabet, the alphabet!
I'm asking you, at the age of eight, you have to be able to distinguish A from
B.
That's what I've been thinking about all this time.
I'm afraid my first impression is right.
She's not the right way to treat Mrs. Clara.
Calm down.
You have to think about yourself and your health first and foremost.
It doesn't make sense for you to ruin yourself for a stranger's child.
If you go on like this, you'll ruin Clara's education.
My years of work, goodwill, efforts and worries, all for nothing.
To be continued...
Is there poison in the coffee?
I've spoiled it.
I've made mistakes. I was way too soft.
Well, no. I wouldn't do that.
Just like this.
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I.
And J, and K, and L.
Up to this point, we can do it. Very good, my child.
And now, Adelheid, open your book.
This time, I won't give you a hint.
This time, you'll have to be able to read it by yourself.
So, what is this?
A.
Very good. And now, the next letter.
B.
Very good, my child.
And now, let's look for these letters here.
Z.
X?
P.
This is the Z and this is the X.
I'm afraid you're still messing with them.
Nobility, nobility.
So open your notebook and write down all the letters in the book.
And the ones you don't finish, you write down ten times.
I'm done.
Then show me.
Very nice. Very neat. Good handwriting.
Let's go over to the calculator now.
How many are ten times ten?
A hundred.
From a hundred, please subtract twenty.
Eighty.
To eighty, add nine.
Psst, don't say anything.
From this sum you subtract ten again.
It looks exactly like my stone castle.
Psst, Heidi, not so loud.
Where did we stop?
Yes, there...
It looks exactly like it.
Like the Steinbock I saw in the mountains.
Yes, well, take the written homework, Clara.
Page 12 in your book.
Heidi! Heidi!
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
Do you actually hear what I'm saying?
Oh!
Goodbye!
I'll never come back! I'm flying home!
I'm flying home!
Hurray!
Goodbye and thank you!
Live well and greet my Clara!
Very nice, Clara! Very nice, that you did that today!
Amazing how fast you do research!
Goodbye!
And greet my Clara!
Thank you for letting me fly with you!
That's not normal!
Greet Clara!
But not Mrs. Rottenmeier!
Hello!
Stop it!
What's going on?
Mrs. Rottenmeier!
You fell off the chair!
Did you break your legs?
Do you have pain?
No, I have to help you!
Let me help you!
Oh!
Psst!
I dreamed!
Oh!
With open eyes, with a...
On a bright day, can you dream like that?
Yes, very good. Why should you only dream in the dark?
Out of the letters became Steinböck.
What did I tell you this morning? I was right, she's just not normal.
Yes?
Come in, Sebastian!
Ah, Mr. Sesemann is coming home. Very good. Then this nightmare will probably
come to an end.
When is Father coming home? Is it written in the telegram when he is coming?
He writes in the course of tomorrow's morning.
Finally, Father is coming home. And tomorrow, already tomorrow morning.
Excuse me, Mr. Candidate. I still have a lot of preparations to make.
Of course.
You don't believe how happy I am. I'm sure you'll like my father too. He's very
nice.
But most of the time he'll unpack his suitcases and pack them back in.
The last time he disappointed me too.
Why?
Oh, you know, he only stayed for three days. He said he'd stay longer.
But then this stupid telegram came from Paris and he immediately drove back
home.
If only I could go with him.
You know, Heidi, my father is really nice. When he's here, it's always much
nicer here in the house.
He always tells funny stories about his travels.
If you want, you can tell him one of your stories.
He likes to hear things like that, if he has time for it, of course.
But he hardly has time for that.
Does your father love you?
I mean, does he love you as much as fathers love their children?
Of course he loves me. Even very much.
Yes? And how do you know that he loves you very much?
He has often told me that he loves me.
He has also written it to me in a letter.
And every time he comes home, he brings me presents.
But... no, no.
That's not true. I know it because I love him from the bottom of my heart.
I love him and my father loves me just as much.
How nice.
You're going to be right.
As always.
I'm curious about your father.
He probably didn't tell you too much.
Come here, Tinette! On the spot!
Yes, Mrs. Rottenmeier, what is it?
Come here and take a look at the windows. Do you think they're clean?
I haven't cleaned them yet, madam.
I should clean Mr. Sesemann's room first.
Should I clean the window first or the room?
Oh, of course, Mr. Sesemann's room first.
The windows can wait.
All right.
You have to clean his bed.
That's already done. You don't have to remind me of that.
Always at the last minute.
He could have sent the telegram earlier.
All right.
He could take care of his household a little more, I think, anyway.
Oh, now I would have forgotten the most important thing about my hair in front
of all the excitement.
He probably also wants to see the room of this child.
And with her you have to be focused on everything. Maybe she sleeps on the
floor.
Everything is possible with her.
WASH YOUR HAIR
Wash your hair!
You seem to be able to keep order at least. Well, at least one good page.
Oh, embalming!
Oh, I hope it's a dream!
Bride!
Christmas!
I don't trust my eyes!
Is something wrong?
that I don't have a single thing left if it had been Seisemann.
Leave them alone, they're mine! Don't touch them!
Don't touch them!
No!
Leave them alone and stop screaming!
They're mine, I want to give them to my grandmother!
They're the most precious things for my grandmother!
You'll be burned on the spot, you must be poisoned!
No!
I'll find you tomorrow morning!
They're mine, I won't do it anymore!
No, Ms. Rottmeier, don't beat them, they can't do anything about it, let them
go!
I already know that you and her are in a relationship, so stay out of it!
No! No! No!
My patience is at its end, I'll tell you that tomorrow at 6 o'clock!
He'll know what steps he has to take and what I advise him, I already know that!
I don't care, I want my brother back!
There was no reason. You can't eat the buns for a long time.
But they were very nice. I took them all off the table.
They must have been old. Old buns become hard of stone. You can't eat them
anymore.
I'm sorry, but this time Mrs. Rottenmeier was right.
They must have been completely moldy and stung.
Then it was all for nothing. Then I was in Frankfurt for nothing all the time.
Heidi, when you go back home, I'll give you a huge cup of fresh bread.
Nice new white bread. No old, rotten, stone-hard bread that no one can eat
anymore.
And stop crying, Heidi.
No, no, nothing will change.
I'm never allowed to go home after all.
Who says that? Of course you can go home at some point.
You're just angry because of the bread, but you can't just put it away.
Believe me, when it's time, we'll buy a new one.
Why are you crying now?
Heidilein, did I say something wrong?
I'm doing everything wrong and no one listens to me when I want to explain
something.
No one can suffer me and everything I like is taken away from me.
I only ate one bun every morning and no one did anything to Mama.
They will never let me go home in life, just because they know that I want it.
Heidi, stay here!
No!
I'm about to cry too.
I'm sorry, but I can't do anything about it.
Come with me to my room. I'll come up with something we can play.
I recently gave you a picture book card with a cat on it.
I'll give you the other one too, okay?
You liked them very much.
Come.
I also know a story about goats. If you want, I can tell you.
It's an exciting story. You'll definitely like it.
I'll give it to you too.
I love you!
I'm really sorry.
I'll tell you. You listen very well. I know the story of my father. He once told
her.
Once upon a time, a long, long time ago, there lived in a deep, dark forest in a
pretty, small, colorful house,
a mother goat with seven white chicks. The mother goat loved her chicks very
much and raised them well.
One day, the mother goat put on her white gloves,
took the bag,
put on her hat, and gathered all seven chicks around her.
Dear children, said the mother, I have to go shopping, and you should stay in
the house.
Please never open the door when it knocks. It could be the wolf.
The children promised it was high and holy, and as soon as the mother was gone,
it knocked on the door.
I am your mother. Open up, dear children. I have brought you nice presents.
I have great longing for you.
I love you.
But of course the clever chicks knew that it was the wolf who stood in front of
their door.
They recognized him by his deep voice.
But the wolf was not stupid either. He knew of course why the chicks recognized
him.
And he slipped away and ate a whole sack of chalk.
Open the door!
Come on, little girl, it's your mother, I'm back!
Oh, that's the mother's voice, that's exactly how she speaks.
Show your paws first, they have to be white.
But the wolf was very smart, he had dipped his paws in flour and he showed them.
Hurray, the mother is at home, come in, mother!
But what happened then?
There was the wolf!
He caught the chick and ate it one after the other.
The wolf had such a big belly that he could hardly get out of the house.
He slipped out on all fours.
After a while, the goat mother came home. She was already looking forward to her
children, but when she called, none of them was there and she understood what
had happened.
She ran out of the house again and called each of her children by name, every
single one, but none of them answered.
I told you to be careful, children, little children!
And when the mother called her youngest child, suddenly a quiet voice came out
of the clock.
The youngest was the only one who could save himself from the wolf.
The mother told him what had happened and cried big, round tears.
The mother listened to the story and cried along.
The youngest chick was ungrateful and snored loudly.
The mother cried and cried again.
The mother tried to calm the little one and went with him out of the house. She
went around the whole house and through the garden and then out onto the field.
And there on the field, there lay under a big tree the evil wolf and slept. A
terrible fairy tale.
How did it go on? Tell me!
Did he have a big belly?
Of course! And what a...
And he was rumbling and mumbling.
When it was rumbling and mumbling, the mother goat thought,
then they are still alive!
And she ran home quickly and got a big pair of scissors.
And cut the wolf's belly open, from top to bottom.
Cut!
Snip-snap! Snip-snap! And all the chicks jumped out, one after the other. They
jumped and jumped and were happy.
What do you think they were all happy about?
And the wolf was broken.
Poor, poor wolf.
But it's not true. A goat can only have one or two boys, and yours has seven.
But it's just a story. It doesn't matter if it's not true.
It's not true anyway, the way I told the story. I forgot the conclusion.
Really?
Something's going on with the wolf, but I just don't know what.
I think they put cobblestones in his belly.
I like that.
Come on, let's go to my room.
Clara!
Did you mean it seriously with the pictures earlier?
Of course. So you did listen.
Wait.
And then it was finally time, the carriage was about to pass.
Mr. Sesemann had come home. He stormed the stairs and greeted his daughter Clara
with overwhelming joy.
And also Heidi, who did not dare to say anything out of fear, greeted him with
friendly words.
He spoke to her like to a little lady.
And then he took a package out of his big suitcase.
And that was for Heidi.
Heidi knew from the first moment that she could love Mr. Sesemann very much.
And she wanted to do everything for him.
Mr. Sesemann also liked Heidi from the first moment and he asked Clara and Mrs.
Rottenmeier exactly after the girl.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges