Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark bees
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi
You need to be happy
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
are waking up this morning particularly early. Mr. Sesemann, Clara's father, was
supposed to come home.
He had sent a telegram and announced his arrival.
The next morning.
Mr. Sesemann is coming!
Hurry up, Mr. Sesemann is coming!
Already? How terrible!
Finally!
Father is coming! You'll see, he's really very nice!
I'm so happy! You don't even believe how happy I am!
Good afternoon, Sebastian.
Welcome home, Mr. Sesemann.
Thank you, Sebastian. We'll talk later.
There's a lot to talk about. You've been away for a very long time.
Good afternoon, Tinette.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Welcome home, Mr. Sesemann.
Has my daughter already woken up?
Oh yes, of course, for many hours.
She couldn't wait to see you.
Has the little one from Switzerland woken up too?
When I last saw her, she was there.
Please, Mr. Sesemann, wait a moment.
I'm sorry that I have to bother you with your return.
But you don't know what we've been through here.
This shop...
I want to see Clara first. We'll talk about it later.
Sebastian, please bring the smaller one of the two suitcases upstairs into my
daughter's room.
All right, Mr. Sesemann.
Clara! Clara!
Finally! I'm home again, Clara!
I thought you'd never come back. Finally!
But Clara, what's the matter? I always come back.
Let me look at you, my child. You're still so pretty.
I haven't seen you in three months.
I want to introduce you to someone. Listen to me, Father.
Yes, you're just as pretty, if not even prettier.
Now listen to me. I want to introduce you to someone.
My best friend. Father, this is Heidi.
So, you're little Heidi.
Heidi, this is my father.
Well, did I promise you too much?
I'm happy to make your acquaintance, my child.
Good day.
Well, how do you get along with my daughter? I know her. I have often felt
enough of her head.
Yes, you both argue a lot. But don't let yourself get caught up. Clara usually
has the last word.
I can imagine how it is. You say the same thing a thousand times and then you
have to start all over again.
But father, what nonsense are you talking about all of a sudden? What should
Heidi think of me?
Don't believe him. We haven't fought each other a single time yet.
That's right, Heidi.
What are we supposed to argue about?
You seem to understand each other well. That makes me feel better.
If what you're saying is true, then you seem to have earned a reward.
What is it? Why aren't you coming?
Here, Clara.
Oh, thank you, Father. Thank you very much.
Here, Heidi.
Is this really for me?
Of course. Is there another Heidi here?
No, there's only one Heidi here. Thank you, Mr. Sesemann.
Isn't she pretty?
She is really very pretty.
The most beautiful doll in the world.
Heidi liked Mr. Sesemann from the first moment on.
And not just because of the doll.
It's not that simple, unfortunately.
Since this child is here, everything is mixed up.
Everything is on the head. I have lost control.
She has no behavior at all.
She touches meat with her fingers.
Sometimes I think I'm spinning.
I just miss the words.
So?
It can't be that bad, because you talk a lot.
Clara seems to like you very much, and that's all that counts.
Clara is far too intelligent to like such a creature.
She brings in mice and cats and clumsy turntables.
Turntables?
Yes, can't believe it.
Who knows what she's going to do the next day.
And besides, she let Mrs. Clara free the bird.
And then the buns. She stole buns every day and hid them in her closet.
Sometimes she just disappears and no one knows where she's going.
No, no, she's a wild one and she's going to stay a wild one.
Who knows how things are going at home.
Do you know that she doesn't even know the alphabet?
Sometimes I think she's not quite right in her head.
You mean the child isn't normal?
Yes, that's what I mean.
In any case, there are all kinds of signs of it.
She sometimes says such terrible things about goats and stones.
And just imagine, she can whistle on her fingers.
I was just able to prevent her from teaching that to Mrs. Clara.
She ruins my entire upbringing.
If only you knew what we've been through here.
I still doubt the child. I don't know what to do with her.
To be continued...
We have to come up with a name for the dolls.
Oh, you did a good job.
Well, you two pretty girls, are you having fun?
Are you so nice to me and get me a glass of water from the kitchen?
The glasses are standing, the glasses are standing, the glasses...
Tinette knows what they are standing for.
Should I get cold water?
Yes, ice-cold, clear, fresh water.
I got it, I'm running fast.
There, Clara.
I have a few important questions for you. Please answer them honestly.
Have you ever noticed something about Heidi that you think is strange?
Mrs. Rottenmeier is worried. She thinks Heidi wouldn't be completely normal.
A lot depends on your answer now. If she's right, we have to send Heidi home.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Oh, no, Heidi is as normal as I am. She's a very sweet girl.
What Miss Rottenmeier claims is not true.
She just can't stand Heidi.
I see.
Heidi is just not used to living in a house and in a city.
Miss Rottenmeier says she has not even learned the alphabet.
Yes, she's right.
But that's not because she's stupid. She just has to think about the mountains.
That's all.
She likes the mountains.
Heidi always thinks about the mountains?
Yes.
She doesn't feel well with us. She wants to go back to the mountains.
She misses her goats and her friends.
She wants to play with the dog and see the sunset and help her grandfather.
I see. It looks like she has a home-pain.
But I don't want her to go back home. I like her.
Since she's here, everything is much nicer. I haven't been bored for a single
day.
And she didn't mean it badly when she said the mice and the...
...cats were here in my room. She just wanted to be with her friends. She just
loves animals so much. Please, father, leave her here.
You two really seem to have become friends.
Oh yes, Heidi is the best friend in the world. You should hear what kind of
beautiful stories she can tell.
And when she laughs, I always have to laugh with her. Let her play the dog.
What is it, father? Where are you going? Please don't send her away.
I think we'll keep Heidi here.
But I'd like to ask the others first before I make up my mind.
Sebastian, please send the little girl to me.
Yes, sir.
She must be down in the kitchen somewhere. I've sent her to get me some water.
I know.
You've lost something. A sock.
This is the only thing left.
I'm sorry.
Thank you. Do me a favor. Put the socks in my shirt pocket.
Yes. I did it.
Thank you, child. Nice of you.
Do you know if there is a fountain here where you can get fresh, cold water?
Yes, I know. I'm on my way there. Come with me.
Are you going to wash clothes there?
So you ask questions. What else should I do there?
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
If only you knew how much my back hurts.
Don't get too excited. I'm in the line now.
It's getting more and more crowded.
And then she just fell into the hot water pot.
We might have done it.
Let me through. I just want to go to the fountain.
Listen to how you get through on your own.
There's the fountain back there.
Let's go.
What are you standing around for? Kids have nothing to look for here.
I can't even imagine where she went again now.
You look over there, I'll look here.
This girl is terrible.
That's exactly what it is.
One is not a second of the day safe in front of her stripes.
She really has everything she needs, but no, she has to run away.
Do you know where I can find a fountain?
Always straight ahead and then to the right.
Thank you.
Imagine that.
He actually threatened me with the announcement because the children are so
loud.
There's a fountain! Hooray! Finally fresh water!
Ice cold!
As Mr. Sesemann wanted it to be.
Good day, little girl.
Can I have a sip of water too? It's hot in here.
Yes, of course.
Please, here's my cup.
Thank you.
Does it taste good? Is the water cold enough?
It's even very good.
Here, your cup.
Goodbye.
You little one, where are you taking the water?
To Mr. Sesemann.
What? Where to, to Mr. Sesemann?
I think he has running water in the house.
There you walk through the whole city and get water and he has some.
He doesn't have such water.
He said I should get him water, but he wanted ice cold water.
And I did that.
Then greet him nicely.
I hope your water is cold enough for him.
Goodbye, little girl.
It was an honor for me to get to know you.
Don't forget to greet.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
But then I told him my opinion.
I told him, if you don't want my children to make noise,
then I don't want your ugly dogs to bark from morning to night.
I don't want your ugly dogs to bark from morning to night.
If she had gone out to catch some fresh air, she would have been here long ago.
No, I have the feeling that this time she ran away.
And that, now that you have come home.
Oh, I have at least expected some gratitude, all your generosity for nothing.
Believe me, finally, she is not normal.
The child is a danger.
Tinette and I have searched the whole city for her, not to drive her away.
So there we have the catastrophe.
I will look for her myself. And thank you, God, if I find her.
I beg you, Mr. Sesemann, send her away. It is not to be held back.
Sebastian, get the carriage ready.
Heidi?
Yes?
Did you just get water? That took a long time.
I didn't find a fountain first.
Careful.
Most of the fountains I found had so many people standing there, but they didn't
let me through.
I'm sorry it took so long, but there was a man there who said the water would be
particularly good.
Thank you very much, my child.
You seem to have put a lot of effort into my water.
Good.
Is the water cold enough?
Yes, it's cold enough. It's the best water I've ever drunk.
I was supposed to say hello. There was this man at the fountain.
He said I shouldn't forget to say hello. He was a very nice man.
He had a walking stick with a horse head.
Who could that be? Here, Sebastian.
He had very white hair and he was very old. And he was very nice to me. And he
had this nice walking stick.
The description fits the doctor.
He has his walking stick. He will be very surprised that you send Heidi to get
water.
The whole long way through the city for a single glass of water.
Let's see what he says when he comes next time.
What's so funny?
I don't know why you're laughing so much.
Yes, I believe you, my child.
Bye!
Come, bird, fly, sit down on my foot.
There's a letter in the beak, a greeting from the mother.
Can I bother you, Mr. Sesemann?
Yes, of course. I wanted to talk to you anyway.
I have now decided to keep Heidi here with us.
Oh!
I watched Heidi go in the last few days.
She makes a completely normal impression on me.
Besides, Clara feels much better when she's there.
I am quite aware that you are having a hard time.
You can say that.
Yes, that's good.
I know that you've been having a hard time lately, Mrs. Rottenmeier, and that
you can't get over Heidi without further ado.
And to make it a little easier for you while I'm gone, I asked my mother to come
here.
Oh, do you mean to say that Mrs. Sesemann is coming?
That's what I meant to say.
I appreciate what you're doing for us, and especially for my daughter.
That's why I want my mother to help you.
But...
My mother is familiar with children. You don't mind her coming, do you?
No, no, no, no, Obeware. I appreciate your kindness.
Why should I mind your mother coming?
I'm very pleased. My mother will take the child away from you,
and then you can take care of Clara. I thank you.
You will see, this time, everything will be fine while I'm away in the house.
THE END
Well, you two?
That's your father, Clara. Good morning, Mr. Sesemann. Did you sleep well?
Yes, I slept well. Good morning, Heidi.
But Clara, don't be so sad. Didn't you like the last few weeks?
Why weeks? It was only ten days again.
I'll be back over the next month and then I'll definitely stay at home longer.
I promise you.
You never keep your promises.
How many times have you said, this time you'll stay longer and then you'll pack
your suitcases again and you'll be gone.
You can't do anything about it. I'm sorry, I shouldn't have said all that.
I'm really a rabid father, but I think this time I have a surprise for you that
you're looking forward to.
Grandmother is coming! When is she coming? How long will she stay with us?
Is she really coming?
Yes, she is really coming. I don't know how long she will stay, but she has
already left the house.
Well, now you are shining again, Clara.
I thank you, Father. I love you so much.
I love you too, my little one.
Take good care of yourself, Clara.
Heidi is already taking care of me.
Goodbye!
Don't be sad, you two!
Never come back!
Goodbye!
You, Clara!
What kind of grandmother is that your father was talking about?
My grandmother, who else?
You will definitely like her. She is really very, very nice. Believe me.
Peter also has a grandmother. You still know the white buns.
My grandmother also likes white buns. You have to tell you about the other
grandmother.
If you enjoy the story of your bun, you will definitely enjoy it.
My grandmother likes to laugh very much. Am I right?
Yes, the kind lady is a very humorous old lady.
She even hid the soup from the poorest teenager.
And she even sewed the arms of his coat to Sebastian.
Heidi, come back in. The candidate is already waiting for us in the classroom.
I'll be right there.
Yes, I'll be right there.
Heidi was very, very curious about Clara's grandmother.
If she was really as nice as Clara claimed?
If only it had finally come to that.
But it took a while for the grandmother to come.
And Mrs. Rottenmeier and Mr. Candidate
were once again not finished with the child, as they expressed themselves.
Heidi also came up with the strangest ideas a few times
and told Clara wonderful stories from the mountains.
Clara found it all very funny, but Miss Rottenmeier had no understanding of it
at all.
When the long-awaited grandmother finally came, she brought a surprise for Clara
and Heidi,
from which the two had never heard anything before.
They didn't come out of the astonishment at all.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back again.