Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark berries
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-
Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi
Holala-Edi
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back
Martinet, where are you going?
I don't think I can get anything out of the way.
The old lady is no longer the youngest.
Yes, yes, I'm driving slowly.
It's done.
Good, good.
Then I'll drive.
Good.
When you're done with my hair, I'll comb you.
I like my hair the way it is.
Nevertheless, you have to be combed.
You know, today the grandmother is coming.
Do you mean she's cursing?
Grandmother never cusses, but you want to look pretty.
Is your grandmother very strict with children?
But no, she is kind and friendly and always nice.
And why doesn't your grandmother live with you here in the house?
It's big enough.
Frankfurt is too big and too loud for you. She says she's old and wants to live
in a quieter, smaller town.
And why do you live here and don't live with her in the smaller town?
Because there are no private teachers there. They only exist in the city. And I
still have to learn a lot, as you know.
And not just me. You too.
Unfortunately.
Give me the comb. You must also want to be pretty and like my grandmother.
Mhm.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Is your grandmother like Mrs. Rottenmeier?
Oh, don't be afraid. She's really different.
You like her for sure. All children like her.
I think she's nice when I say grandmother.
I think you should, but you have to ask her first.
If we want to, she'll tell us fairy tales all day.
She knows all there is to know.
You know what, Clara? I already like your grandmother.
Abelheim, please come to me, my child.
Is the grandmother already here, Mrs. Rottenmeier?
Adelheid, how many times do I have to tell you to knock?
That was on purpose.
I don't want to be on purpose. Go out right now!
Yes.
We'll practice until you can do it.
Imagine I'm Mrs. Sesemann and you come in to greet me.
Hi!
Hello, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Of course.
It's not called Mrs. Rottenmeier and not at all hello!
I am Mrs. Sesemann, understood?
I see.
You come in and ask, how are you, Mrs. Sesemann?
Where is Mrs. Sesemann?
It has no purpose, it has no purpose.
You should speak loudly.
Where is she?
Calm down!
No one can be so stupid.
We start from the beginning.
Good day, grandmother, how are you?
Who gave you permission to call her grandmother?
No one, but I'm sure she will.
She is the grandmother of Mrs. Clara and only she has the permission to call her
that.
All the others call her kind lady.
Why?
Remember well, Mrs. Sesemann is the lady of this house.
We have to meet her with great pride.
She is a fine old lady and she knows exactly how to appreciate good behavior, my
child.
She does not deserve any noise and no impudence near her.
And if you move aside, it will fall back on me.
But Clara said she is very nice.
Of course she is.
Besides, she demands absolute obedience.
Then she's not a grandmother, then she's like you.
Nobility, you're talking nonsense.
I'm not talking nonsense.
That's part of it, too. The kind lady doesn't want any objection.
Good.
What's going on again?
What's wrong with the picture, Sebastian?
I wanted to hang it on the wall. That's all.
Why? There's already a picture hanging on the wall.
I wanted to exchange it. This is the favorite picture of the Blessed Virgin.
That's pure waste of time.
But I thought...
They shouldn't think, they should do their job.
And what they do, that's what I decide.
Yes, ma'am.
Wait a moment!
What are you wearing over your arm, Tinette?
Fork angel.
Are you both making fun of me or what's going on here?
What do you want to start with these curtains?
Hang them up.
The noble lady prefers bright colors in the house.
Mr. Sesemann has transferred me the management of his household.
And I can't remember that I gave the order to exchange the curtains.
Oh, there she is! What are you standing around for? Hurry up!
And you, Adelheid, please don't forget what we practiced together earlier.
You make a knick and ask, how are you, noble lady?
Say yes, not grandmother to her!
Oh dear, she's coming.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
How are you, Mrs. Rottenmeier?
It was easy with Peter's grandmother.
It was called grandmother without the word.
Mrs. Gnädige, Mrs. Gnädige, Mrs. Gnädige, Mrs. Gnädige, Mrs. Gnädige, Mrs.
Dingster.
How are you, grandmother? Are you okay?
Thank you, my child. I'm fine. I'm Clara's grandmother.
And if she shouts right away?
Welcome, dear lady.
Yes, welcome.
Miss Rottenmeier, come to yourself.
What's wrong with her?
Her nerves don't seem to be all right.
Oh, Miss Sesemann.
I'm sorry, Miss Rottenmeier, but how should I know that you are so horrible?
I wanted to surprise Clara and the Swiss girl.
I'm afraid I was surprised.
Well, what do you say about my bear? Doesn't he look very natural?
Oh, he looks terribly natural.
I'm very happy. It was a pure coincidence that I discovered him.
Let's see what the children will say.
Oh, merciful woman!
You can't do that! Clara is so sensitive!
Where did she drive him?
We were passing by a circus and she lent it to him.
That looks like her.
I won't forget the face of Mrs. Rottenmeier so quickly.
Mrs. Sesemann, fair lady, think of your health.
I'll take care of her.
Come in.
Oh, great mother!
I hate you. I'm a big, evil bear.
You'll taste good.
Honey would taste much better for you.
But you must have eaten honey for breakfast this morning.
Dear grandmother.
Did you at least get scared?
No, not a little bit. I knew right away that it was you.
You look funny.
Funny? I look great here.
Yes.
Yes?
You look good, Clara. Much better than I feared.
I'm happy about it.
It's good that you're here.
Let me hug you, my child.
Where is the little girl from Switzerland?
What do you think, Clara, if we both surprise her with the bear costume?
Oh yes!
I'm sure I'm the first grandmother for her who looks like a bear.
I'm curious what she says.
And you have to hum loudly.
You'll be surprised how beautifully I hum.
No, not! You can't push the cart yourself!
Sebastian, quick, Sebastian!
Look, I'll take the cart for you, but I can do that myself.
It's way too heavy for you.
Poor lady, poor lady Moosmother.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
You're hiding from me. That's how it is.
I'm the big bear.
Run away from me.
Wait, I'll catch you.
I'm faster than you.
I like Swiss girls.
I'm the big bear.
I'm a big, evil bear!
Not even Heidi is afraid!
What? You're not afraid?
And I tried so hard to scare you!
Hello, dear grandmother.
Hello, little Heidi.
Adelheid, what's wrong with you?
How many times do I have to tell you how you've grown up?
Show me what I've taught you.
It's not necessary. We've both already met.
I practiced with Adelheid this morning and I want her to stick to it.
I'm sorry I have to contradict you, but I can't give in on this point.
I don't want to interfere with your education, of course.
I'd be happy to.
All right, Adelheid. Let's start over.
How are you, Mrs. Gnädige?
Mrs. Gnädige?
All the trouble for free.
Do you say Mrs. Gnädige at home in the mountains?
No, of course not. Nobody says that.
And neither do we. I've never heard it before.
What is it, Adelheid? You know it.
It's good. If you want, I'm the grandmother for you.
But of course I want to, and I'd love to.
And now it's your turn to introduce yourself. I have to know your name.
My name is Heidi. But...
maybe my name is Adelheid.
Do you have two names? Or should I choose the one I like?
I can explain that to you if you allow me.
She calls herself Heidi. Her correct name is Adelheid.
Oh, so that's how it is. She calls herself Heidi.
Well, then she seems to be used to that name.
Hello Heidi, how are you?
Thank you, I'm very well.
Mrs. Clara, I have to report that Mr. Candidate is waiting.
Do we have to learn today, too?
Why should we make an exception today?
Because today is an exception. The grandmother came.
And this grandmother doesn't run away that fast.
I'd like to take part in the class.
I'd like to see what progress has been made.
You have nothing against it, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
What? Why? Why? Why?
Sebastian, please give the Bärenfeld to Johann. He should return it to the
circus.
Yes, dear lady.
Come in.
Good day.
Oh, what a pleasant surprise to be able to welcome you here again, Mrs.
Sesemann.
You were no longer three, or no, two, maybe just one year no longer here.
Yes, yes, that's how you notice how time goes by, you don't get any younger.
The eyes don't want to be like that anymore, and the legs don't want to...
That's good, Mr. Candidate.
We can chat a little later, now we just want to start with the lesson.
Yes, yes, I understand.
Adelheid, please tell us the alphabet, we also want to show Mrs. Sesemann what
you learned here.
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, uh, and then...
A, B, C, D, E...
...F, G, and H, I, J, K, L, M, N, O, P, Q, S, T, U, V, W, X, Y, and Z.
And once again.
A, B, C, D, E, F...
G, H, I, J, K, L, M, N, O, P, Q, L, S, T, U, V, X, Y, Z, A, B, C, D, E, F, G,
H...
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Mrs. Rottenmeier wishes that I draw your attention to the fact that we only eat
at 7 o'clock according to the house rules.
What? Only at 7 o'clock? But then we have to wait another half hour.
We will have to change that. I want to eat earlier.
What I wanted to ask is, are you still that bad or do you have more appetite,
Clara?
But how are you supposed to get big and strong if you don't want to eat?
I don't like eating. I find eating terribly boring.
What is it?
Since when is eating boring? It always tastes good to me.
I think it's nice to sit at the table, especially when there's something on the
plate that I like.
What do you think you can do with plates?
If they're really blank, you can sometimes even look into them.
You can also fill the plate with water and let little ships swim on it.
And you can even conjure with very deep plates.
Conjure?
Sebastian?
Yes, what do you want?
Please be so kind and get me an even deeper plate.
These are the deepest plates we have.
Then get me glasses. Glasses work too.
Glasses, yes. I will hurry, dear lady.
I brought some water.
That's good, Sebastian.
I think these glasses are real magic glasses.
What are you doing with that, Grandmother Waste?
Just patience. You'll see.
Oh, a colorful flower!
You can do magic, Grandmother.
But that's not all you can do with glasses.
Just wait a moment.
This seems to be a bit hoarse.
Oh, the ringtone!
You can make music!
Well?
That's...
It's the melody by Henzinglein.
If you've recognized it, then you can play it with me.
Gladly. But with what?
There will probably be more glasses.
Sebastian, are there still a few glasses in the house?
Well, let's give it a try together. One, two...
Beautiful!
Good!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Since when do you stand on the chair? Do you only have nonsense in your head?
Listen to this, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
I happened to have the nonsense in my head.
Mrs. Seselmann, that can't be true.
Oh yes, Mrs. Rottenmeier, that can be true.
And you can't even imagine what fun it is to make music with a simple spoon and
glasses.
Stop it! Right now!
I don't want to listen to music.
I'll listen if I want to.
It's time for dinner. It's seven o'clock.
If that's the case, we really have to stop now.
I'm almost starved anyway.
It's nice with your grandmother. You were right, Clara. She's really very nice.
I like her very, very much. She's always like that. She always comes up with
something funny.
I envy you. You have the best grandmother in the world.
She's yours now.
Do you know what I noticed? You haven't thought about the mountains today.
Yes, that's right. Why do you know that?
I read it from your face.
There are letters on it.
So, Clara!
Go to your room, Heidi. Otherwise Mrs. Rottenmeier will find you here and curse
at you again.
Adelaide, what are you doing in Mrs. Clara's room? Get out!
Good night, Clara.
Good night, Heidi.
But, but, that's not possible.
Do you think I'm lying to you?
No, no, of course not.
Then go and do what I tell you.
Mrs. Sesemann won't stay long, she's leaving soon.
Yes, very well, I understand.
It will be done.
La, la, la, la, la, la.
La la la la la la la la.
The grandmother is really very funny.
Who's there?
It's me.
Pssst!
Hello, Grandmother.
Can I come in?
Of course.
We have to be quiet, otherwise Mrs. Rottenmeier will hear us and will scold us
again.
Tell me, why haven't you gone to sleep yet?
Can you fall asleep already?
No.
I have something for you that I wanted to give you.
A present?
This one.
Don't you like it?
Yes, I even like it very much.
But I can't read it yet.
That's not a problem. There are some nice pictures to look at.
Take a look.
Maybe you'll learn how to read with this book.
It's not as hard as you think it is.
Should I read you some of it?
Oh, yes.
Then hurry up and go to bed, Heidi.
I'll read you so long until your eyes close.
Hooray!
I'm done.
You, grandmother?
What is it, my child?
Miss Rottenmeier says you're leaving soon.
Does she say that?
Yes, she said it to Sebastian this evening.
I'm still here and I don't plan to leave so soon.
Ah, that's nice.
Are you ready? Can I start?
Yes.
Once upon a time in a distant land, far behind the seven mountains,
there lived a little girl.
Grandmother read and read, and Heidi listened attentively.
Grandmother had to read three long fairy tales,
until Heidi could no longer keep her eyes open and fell asleep.
Finally!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Heidi had been loved by her grandmother from the bottom of her heart, and Mrs.
Sesermann also liked the little girl.
She spent a lot of time teaching Heidi how to read and write.
And then one day, by chance, she came to the secret of why Heidi was sometimes
so sad.
She understood that Heidi was having a heart attack.
To make Klara happy and to comfort Heidi, she thought it would be a surprise for
the children.
She went with them on a warm spring day out to the country, but we want to tell
you about that in our next story.
To be continued