Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
the other and the youngest was not much over the length of his fingers when he
was born.
That's why he was called Däumeling. He grew up a little afterwards ...
... slightly over the ear.
Oh, I was in the wrong line with my finger.
The little thumb is in the ear of the horse. That's smart.
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, L, M, N, O, P, Q, R, S, T, N...
Adelheid!
Yes?
Adelheid?
Oh, there you are, child. What are you still waiting for?
Time to study.
From the Rottenmeier?
Yes, please, dear lady.
Come in. I want to talk to you in my room.
But not now. The children's class starts in a moment.
Yes, right now, because I want to talk to you about the two children's class.
Please.
Anna, apple, evening, Anna...
Anne-Marie!
Apple,
Axe,
Eagle,
All,
Fear,
Whore,
An,
Climb. Anchor. And now the B.
Bertha Ball Besen Blumenbeet.
Grandmother taught you that. Heidi can read now.
Yes, I can!
Lies!
Oh, I don't believe that, I don't believe that!
When I have to experience that, a miracle has happened.
Since the twelfth year of my life, I no longer believe in miracles.
This brings all the newly established rules of pedagogy and science together.
I studied for nothing.
I don't believe in miracles.
Tell me, do you know what he has?
He wonders that you can read all of a sudden.
He just doesn't want to believe it.
Don't you want tea?
And what does Heidi do when Clara has to hold her nap?
Then she stays in her room, as I called her.
But she always thinks up all sorts of stories.
I mean, I don't care what she does, but she tells them afterwards, Clara.
I would certainly think up stories if I was locked up in my room.
Do you really think that's necessary?
Yes, please, come in.
It's a miracle in our house.
The Swiss child can read. Isn't that wonderful? She can read!
Before I believe you, I have to have seen it with my own eyes.
You're right, it's hard to believe, but it's true.
Yesterday she couldn't distinguish A from B, and today she's just sitting there
and can read.
Adalbert, Annemarie, evening, flower bed.
And imagine, she can even read the difficult word flower bed, and no one has to
help her.
What do you say?
Wonderful, I immediately thought that she would learn it with the right book.
Oh, this book must be able to conjure, Mrs. Sesemann.
Nonsense, I knew it.
I saw it right away. She is such a clever, loving, little thing. I will reward
you for it.
Mr. Candidate, you have a break now. This Heidi is a wonderful child.
You can read. You don't believe how happy I am.
It was much easier than I thought. It wasn't difficult at all.
Anne-Marie, evening?
And Adalbert.
Whoever reads so fast deserves a reward.
A reward? Hooray!
Slowly.
What's that?
That's a secret.
But don't tell Miss Rottenmeier.
Do you know what it could be?
Sit down, please.
Mr. Candidate isn't here to go on vacation.
Discipline!
Grandmother, please don't go away so soon.
Please, Grandmother, yes? Heidi also wants you to stay here.
But Clara, now I'm here and I'll stay too.
Now sleep well for an hour.
And then I'll wake you up and then we'll play together again.
I'm curious about the surprise.
You can do that too.
Yes?
Hello, Grandmother!
Hello, Heidi. I'm so bored.
Do you want to play with me?
You want to play with me?
Uh-huh.
Oh, yes.
One, two, three.
Scissors or stone?
You won.
One, two, three.
Now I can finally climb a few steps.
Well, you have a good laugh.
One, two, three.
Stone grinds the scissors. Edge!
Tell me, you're better than I thought.
Are you really playing the game for the first time?
One, two, three!
Hurray! We won, we won, we won!
Unfortunately, you lost.
We haven't been on the roof for a long time.
That's right. Then you have to work hard.
Only a few more steps.
I'm still winning. One, two, three.
Won!
Again nothing.
One, two, three, four.
One, two, one, two, one, two, three.
Finally I've won too.
You're definitely not getting me in anymore.
I'm almost at the top.
these steps here. One, two, one, two, one, two, three.
They cut paper! I've won again! Wonderful!
One, two, one, two, one, two, three!
Finally, a few more steps up.
Quiet!
One, two, one, two, one, two, three!
Scissors, paper, scissors, you won!
One, two, three!
Adelheid, stop!
How many times do I have to tell you that you have to be quiet in the house
during the quiet hours?
Look at me when I talk to you and go to your room.
Mrs. Sesemann is not a little girl, please notice that!
But the grandmother said...
Humble women, not grandmothers!
Stop behaving as if you were part of the family.
You are strange here.
Thanks for watching and till next time!
If you want to go home to your grandfather, then please tell him that I've
learned to read.
Oh dear.
Yes?
You're alone, that's good.
Come on, we'll continue to play, but this time I'll win.
No, Miss Rottenmeier said I'm not allowed to play with you anymore.
And I'm supposed to say merciful woman.
Aha, she says that.
I'll probably have to talk to her about it later.
Forget it, Heidi.
The way you talk to me, it's just something between us.
You and me.
Do we want to play together or not?
If you come up with a game.
Do you know this key, Heidi?
No, what kind of key is that?
That's a magic key, of course.
Don't you recognize it?
Yes, I do.
Oh, so many books.
And this is the magic land that I mean.
Come with me, Heidi. What are you waiting for?
Ah, fuck!
When I was a child, I often came here.
I sat on this sofa for hours and dreamed.
Just imagine, I always imagined I was Rapunzel.
When you open it, he starts singing from the front again.
But there are even more beautiful things hidden here.
Just come with me.
I've always imagined it to be here.
But it has to be somewhere here. I don't understand.
Maybe I should clean up after all.
Motherfucker.
The mountains, the grandfather,
Svenja and Berli.
And down there is Peter.
You can even see my little cuties.
So, I found it.
Where else could it have been?
Now you're going to experience a surprise, Heidi.
Heidi!
But Heidi, what's wrong with my child?
I see. The picture up there reminds you of the mountains, doesn't it, little
one?
You're home, my child. Were you so happy in the mountains with your grandfather?
Come on, calm down, my love. I think I know how to comfort you.
That's it!
Yes, that's right.
The two of them will be very happy about it.
I'm going with you out of town.
You should finally see green meadows.
Poor Clara has never been out in nature before.
And Heidi may be comforted by that.
La la la la la la la la la.
La la la la la la la.
A picnic where?
In the forest?
Yes, of course. Only if you feel like it.
I know exactly where to go.
It's beautiful there.
I used to go there every Sunday
when I was a little girl and had a boyfriend.
Later your grandfather Clara became your boyfriend.
We often walked through the meadows there for hours.
And there is a stream there with sparkling fish.
Please let us go right away, Grandmother.
Right away? Without preparation?
Then let us quickly prepare everything.
Maybe we'll see butterflies there.
I would like to go with you, but I can't.
Oh, really?
Yes, I will make sure that it works.
We take the wheelchair and Sebastian with us.
And when we get small, we all fit into the carriage.
But Clara...
Why are you so restless? What are you afraid of?
We're going on a trip to the green and tonight we're back home.
You don't want to sit in this dark room all your life, do you?
You have to go outside to the fresh air.
That's probably not good for me again.
Yes, it is. Fresh air has not harmed anyone yet.
It is much more unhealthy to sit in here all the time.
Do you know squirrels?
Not yet, but I would like to see them.
Then come with me. You will see them outside.
They jump around in the trees.
Why?
Okay, I'll go with you.
Hurray! We're going!
And now, since we agreed, we have to make a promise.
With crossed arms?
Yes, with crossed arms.
We all go or no one goes.
If one stays here, everyone stays here.
The promise is a promise and will not be broken.
I'll go with you.
Yes, we all go out of town together.
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
I go into my room and meet the preparations. Hooray!
Let's go!
Hooray!
I will take full responsibility.
What you are doing is a criminal offence.
Mrs. Clara must stay at home in her wheelchair.
You forget that the child is not healthy.
I see.
Nonsense.
You make me very nervous with your speech.
How am I supposed to find my sunscreen if you scream all the time?
Why do you always have to see everything from the bad side, Mrs. Rottenmeier?
What harm is there?
You don't know if it's a shame or not. Clara is very sensitive.
She must not strain herself and not get pulled. I am responsible for you.
I have good news for you, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
My gloves have just been found again, which I was looking for this morning.
May I give you an advice?
I knew something for you that you could use very well.
Just a little bit of humor. What do you think of it?
Mrs. Sesemann.
I'm shocked. I'm employed in this house.
As a teacher and as a respectable person and not as a tramp.
A little hamper wouldn't hurt you at all.
Are you finished?
Yes.
Clara, you look pretty, my child.
I'm looking forward to it, Mother.
Oh my!
Have you fed the horses?
Yes.
Sarah, here!
Clara, we're here! We're here!
Clara, we're here! We're here, Clara!
Hurray! We're here! Hurray!
Come on, get out!
There are a lot of pretty...
Plum, the whole meadow is full. Do you want me to show it to you?
Yes, please send me there.
Hold on!
We are now preparing the food.
Don't drive too far away, you two be careful!
Yes, we are!
Is this peaceful here.
I am glad that I brought the two of them here.
Thank you, Heidi.
But they are beautiful.
Beautiful, beautiful.
I never want to go back to the city.
Shall we go over there?
Yes.
Heidi, look! What is that?
A sea beetle.
But it has pretty dots, round dots.
Yes.
And up there, birds.
If they fly a little higher, they have disappeared into the clouds.
Clara was never as happy as today.
For a moment she even forgot that she could not walk and had to sit in the
wheelchair.
She hoped with all her heart that this day would never come to an end.
For Clara, every flower, every butterfly was a new adventure.
She could not be satisfied with everything.
Sebastian and Johann also knew how to enjoy the afternoon.
But Heidi was the most overbearing. She ran and jumped like at home in the
mountains.
And when the sun slowly approached the horizon and it was time to go home,
the two fell asleep as soon as they sat in the carriage.
Tired, but very, very happy.
Unfortunately, Clara was a little too tired for this day.
She didn't feel well at all after coming home in the evening.
But...
That's what we want to tell you in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains, Heidi, Heidi, because up here you
are at home, Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.
Thank you for watching.