Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Klara, look! A butterfly!
It's flying!
Did you see it?
Yes, he is beautiful, Heidi.
Will you bring him to me?
Wait, Butterfly! I'll catch you!
Ouch!
Are you from the city?
Yes!
That's why we're marking you!
And how!
If you thought you could do it better, then go ahead!
Come on!
Let's go!
Don't be so rude!
You can't just stand on your feet like that!
He flew over there!
I caught him!
Now I'll catch him!
Careful!
But be careful with him!
Don't hurt him!
Butterflies have sensitive wings!
There?
No!
Over there!
Hang on!
I'll catch him!
Now!
Oh, nothing again!
Don't worry, I can save you!
I can catch him!
I'll catch him!
We did it! We did it! We got the butterfly!
There you have it.
Thank you.
I've never seen you here before.
We're only here this afternoon.
But you must be quite rich.
I saw how you arrived.
You rarely see such a big carriage here.
It doesn't belong to me.
The carriage belongs to Clara's father.
Why is she sitting in the wheelchair?
What's wrong with her?
Clara can't walk.
Clara!
We caught the butterfly.
The two boys helped us.
Come on, Klaus, let's go.
Goodbye.
It's okay.
Goodbye, girl.
Maybe we'll see you again.
Goodbye.
Klara!
It's a pretty butterfly.
You'll like it too.
I have it in my hands here.
Now I don't want to see it anymore.
But why all of a sudden?
The two boys and I have put so much effort into it.
That's what it is.
You have put so much effort into it and I have to sit here in this stupid
wheelchair.
Now you're sad.
I'm sorry.
You walked around with the two boys and you forgot me here. I know that it's
more fun than sitting here with me. I find it boring too. But you could have
come over to me. After all, I can't come to you.
But Clara...
I'm sorry Clara, but I thought you wanted to see the butterfly.
I know. It wasn't right what I said.
What can you do about me being sick?
Clara...
No, let me go. I want to be alone.
I was alone all my life. Go and play with the other children.
But Clara...
What is it?
Children, children, where have you been so long?
We have already prepared the food.
Oh, isn't it wonderful out here?
There are greens and flowers everywhere.
And there are flowers in all colors.
Clara, look!
Clara?
Oh, tell me, my dear, are these tears?
We would cry on such a beautiful day.
Grandmother, please tell Mrs. Rottenmeier
she should send Heidi back home to the mountains.
Oh, but child!
I don't want to see her anymore. She should go.
I'm afraid I just don't know what you mean.
I know what she's thinking, Grandmother.
I ran away with two strangers because I wanted to catch a butterfly for her.
And I left her alone.
I've done everything wrong again.
And that's supposed to be all that Heidi has done wrong?
What kind of child are you?
I don't care. I want to go home anyway.
Johan is supposed to finish the cart.
But we just arrived here.
You want to go home so quickly?
Do you mean that seriously?
Yes, I mean that seriously.
What a pity for you.
We can't go yet.
And do you know why? I don't feel like it.
And you? Do you want to go home already?
I'd like to stay.
But if Clara really wants to...
Ah, so you like the city with Miss Rottenmeier better.
You'd rather do homework.
I understand.
We have strawberry jam with us.
If Clara really wants to go home, then I want to too.
That's better.
You think?
I'll tell Johann. He's supposed to tie the horses.
Heidi, but...
So, and now to you.
You want us to send Heidi away.
So you want to be alone again.
So she's equal to you all of a sudden.
And I always thought you loved her.
Heidi...
Heidi, come back!
Leave it with the cart. I'd like to stay here.
Or do you not want to anymore?
Come here to me, Heidi.
Clara noticed that everything was nonsense.
Yes? Did she?
Now say something nice to her, Clara.
She is such a sweet little thing and I really like her.
Should I catch another butterfly?
No.
Then all the problems seem to be solved now. Except for one, of course, the most
important thing.
I wonder all the time if you've never been hungry.
That looks pretty.
You think I like something like that?
You like it very much.
May I take the flower pot with me?
Clara!
Oh, a butterfly, Clara.
Psst, I'll catch it for you.
Then you can see it clearly.
No, Heidi, please let it sit there. It looks like a loop.
A living one.
Come here, loop.
It's like flying to its friend.
Goodbye, butterfly.
Now there are even three butterflies.
The end
Where have you been all this time, Heidi?
On a hill.
There, a squirrel.
Squirrels are also in our mountains.
Exciting.
Hurry up, but don't run into a tree.
I'm trying.
Where did it hide? I can't see it anymore.
Up there on the big branch, look!
Come on, little squirrel, come!
Bravo!
Clara! Heidi!
Where are you children?
Heidi! Clara!
Come on, let's hide!
Quiet!
Kids!
Little children!
Where are you?
Clara!
Heidi!
We have to go on, or they'll find us!
Quiet!
Oh, where did the children go?
They were just here somewhere.
Hello!
Heidi!
Clara!
Look at you!
Cuckoo!
The earthworm has hidden her.
The poor children have disappeared.
How can I help it, Miss Rottenmeier?
The poor little ones.
That's too bad for me.
I can never forgive myself for what has to happen.
What are you going to do? And where are you going to find food?
Grandmother, there we are. Please don't cry.
Edge, you fell in. I'm smarter.
She did something to us.
You're mean, Grandmother. I thought you were crying.
Why am I mean? You two also wanted to put me in.
Or is that not true?
I don't know.
I'd like to go for a ride.
Let's go.
Hello.
John had to hurry to pick us up.
Heidi, over there.
Where?
There are cows.
Come in!
And over there are even they.
Do they look like yours?
Yes, exactly the same.
Grandmother, may I go to them?
Yes, of course.
I've never seen Heidi so happy before, Grandmother.
Do you want to stand still? Stay here!
Oh, Sebastian, please prepare tea and cake for us.
Right away.
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you!
What are you doing with my goat?
Don't chase my goat around like that, it shouldn't lose weight.
We just played a little bit.
If you want to play, then buy a parrot, but leave my goat alone.
The child didn't mean it badly, but may I ask you something?
Would you give the two children a sip of goat's milk afterwards?
Me?
Of course, you shouldn't do that for free, but our Clara has never drunk goat's
milk before.
From me, if you really want to.
A gold piece.
You could take the goat with you to one of them.
That's unbelievable.
There's actually milk coming out of it.
Gail, you're amazed. You've never seen that before.
May I? I'd like to milk her.
You couldn't do that.
I think I can.
Well, the world hasn't seen that yet.
You even do that better than me, little one.
That's hard to believe.
Heidi, how can you do that? Just as well as the farmer's wife.
Huh?
I told you, eating is boring.
You actually ate more this afternoon than Heidi.
But I've never been as hungry as I am today.
Yes, I know.
Fresh air and sunshine even make a beep as if you were hungry like a bear.
It tastes so good.
HAPPY HALLOWEEN
High on the yellow hill
I sit at my brother-in-law's.
Where did the fox go?
The fox went to the grave, the sun glistens in a funny way.
Forests, meadows and meadows,
shining gold of the earth.
I would like to see
above the rolling waves.
Good evening, Mrs. Sesemann.
You're back later than I thought.
At least we're back.
Miss Clara, as I can see, you're tired.
Miss Clara, what's wrong with you? Wake up!
Mrs. Rottenmeier, please don't wake the children up, they are tired.
The day was nice, but long.
Aha, then Mrs. Klarau has over-exhausted herself.
Oh, what, don't get so excited all the time.
Sunlight and fresh air make you tired.
It was fun.
Just look, like the angels.
Put the children in, Sebastian, but be quiet.
Please don't wake them up, okay?
Yes, madam, I will try my best.
Something's not right.
What is it, Sebastian?
Is something wrong with her?
She feels so hot.
Oh, that too.
Does she have a fever?
Very hot.
Clara, child, what's wrong with you? Do you have a fever?
It looks like it.
Johann, go straight to the city and inform the house doctor.
Hopefully he's at home.
Adelheid, wake up and come in!
Are we home again?
Yes, we have arrived.
Get up quickly, child. I have to get the doctor.
Is someone sick?
I think it's Miss Clara. She feels very hot.
What? Clara is sick?
I will not allow her to stay in this house any longer.
Since she's been here, Clara has completely changed.
She would never have thought of going to the countryside.
It can't go on like this.
No matter what I say in this house, it's just not followed.
Just look at how pale she is.
Was that really necessary?
Clara is not like other children.
She is sick and weak.
And the worst thing is that it was all your idea, Mrs. Sesemann.
Oh, I really would have expected something more sensible from you.
But this Heidi has turned your heads with all her nonsense about the mountains.
It's okay, Mrs. Rottenmeier. We'll continue talking when we're alone.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm probably to blame for that, too.
I always do everything wrong. That's always the case.
And I thought you were having fun in the forest.
Maybe you got sick because I left you alone.
Oh, you're Clara's doctor?
Ah, look at that. That's the little lady from Brunnen.
Where did you leave your beautiful stick?
Mr. Secret Service, please.
Mr. Secret Service?
Make Clara healthy. It's all my fault. I made her sick.
Why did you do that?
I wanted to go to the forest and then I left her there alone.
I wanted to catch a butterfly.
I don't think it's your fault, little girl. Leave it to me.
I'll see what I can do.
Please make her healthy again, okay?
Heidi, what are you doing here, my child?
Grandmother, I'm scared.
Heidi.
Poor little thing.
Why are you so worried?
Everything will be fine again.
Your Clara only has a little fever.
But maybe she's really sick.
And then I'm to blame.
No, Heidi. If someone is to blame, then I am.
Can I at least do something for her? I would like to help.
The Secret Service will help you.
And if he doesn't help?
Now calm down. He knows Clara from the beginning.
He knows what he has to do.
You will see, Heidi. Everything will look completely different tomorrow.
So I don't have to be afraid?
Yes, you can be very calm.
How are you?
How are you, little lady? Very well.
The fever will go away soon. She just has to sleep.
Oh, how nice.
And now go to her quickly.
She just told me that she wants to see you.
Yes, good.
Clara!
Psst!
Yes, how nice that you came.
But just one moment, if I may remember.
The doctor has explicitly said that you should sleep.
Would you please leave us alone, Miss Rottenmeier?
Would you please repeat that again?
Gladly, if you want.
Would you please leave us alone, Miss Rottenmeier?
Yes, I understood that too.
As you wish, Miss Clara.
In this house, there's been no value for good education for some time now.
Why?
Now she's outside.
Come closer.
Doesn't that make you tired?
Not at all.
I was mean to you.
I'm sorry, Heidi. Please don't go away from here.
But Clara...
I didn't mean it like that. I really like you. Please stay with me.
Since you're here, everything is much nicer.
I used to be alone all day and now I have a sister.
I like you too, Clara.
I liked it so much in your forest.
Let's go there again when I'm healthy. Let's go there again when I'm healthy.
Mhm, if you want to. Mhm, if you want to.
And Johann will take us there every day. And Johann will take us there every
day.
That's nice. That's nice.
I think so too. I think so too.
Then we'll catch butterflies. Then we'll catch butterflies.
And so a day full of excitement and adventure came to an end.
The two girls thought about this afternoon for a long time.
They often talked about it. They often talked about it.
Catching butterflies, going on a boat trip, milking goats and the fact that they
became friends on this day. 捕獲蜜蜜蜂 捕獲蜜蜂 捕獲蜜蜂 捕獲蜜蜂 捕獲蜜蜂 捕獲蜂 捕獲蜂 捕獲蜂 捕獲蜂 捕獲蜂 捕獲蜂
捕獲蜂 捕獲蜂 捕獲蜂 捕獲蜂
Just as fast as Heidi hoped, Clara did not get well.
The Secret Service came almost every day and looked after her.
And Mrs. Rottenmeier finally got a reason to cheer herself up.
It was not so great for Johan either, when Heidi asked him to help her one day.
Heidi had a plan.
She wanted to make Clara happy, and that's why she went out to the countryside
on her own. She looked for her two friends and together they got something for
Clara.
What that was, that should still be a secret, because we want to tell you about
it in the next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.
To be continued