Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark
Trees
Green meadows
In the sunshine
Heidi
You need to be happy
Holala Edie
Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
I'm back, grandmother. Good day. Actually, I should be picking flowers, but I
haven't found any.
Picking sausage would be better.
And then I should bring a basket with red wine and a cake, but the baskets down
in the kitchen are all too big.
You have to ask my ears and my eyes.
Good. Why do you have such big ears?
So that I can hear you better.
That's good. Then you can listen to me well.
Because I only look like a red cap.
In reality, I am Robin Hood.
The better. Bring your horse in.
And I have big eyes so that I can see you better.
That's my text.
Grandmother, why do you suddenly have such big eyes?
So that I can see you better, my child.
And grandmother, why do you have such a terribly big mouth?
So that I can eat you better!
Stay here! I have to eat you!
But I don't even taste it!
If you just run away, you'll ruin the whole play!
Then try to catch me!
A break!
I think I'm too old to run after Robin Hood all the time.
That's very good! I...
I don't want the wolf to eat you anyway.
Well, then don't.
I also think that our wolf has eaten enough today.
At least he swallowed me down.
Do you know what we're going to play next time? We're going to play Snow White.
But we only have the red cap.
Grandmother didn't buy us Snow White.
We? You two?
I think the wolf looks exactly like Snow White.
But he doesn't look like Snow White.
When I was little, I also had a wolf.
I even played Hans im Glück with it.
You poor Snow White.
Maybe you've been enchanted into a wolf.
Maybe you're even a little bit like the Frog King.
Poor, ugly wolf.
And what if we make him a dress like it has a red cap?
That's definitely not difficult. The dress my doll wears is very simple.
You can now imagine which fairy tale we're playing.
Maybe we can play the story with the roses in the tower.
Do you mean a little rose?
Yes, I think that's what I mean.
If that's what it's like with the cook who sniffs at the earwax, then I mean it.
that's what it's like with the cook who sniffs at the earwax, then I mean it.
That's what a wolf has to look like! Now it's much nicer!
Now I have sewn the tablecloth tight.
Wow!
Wow! Wow! Wow! Wow!
Excuse me, please. I didn't know you were here.
I'm always here. What are you hiding behind your back?
Nothing special. I definitely didn't want to scare you. I'm sorry, Miss
Rottenmeier.
What is that supposed to represent?
How disgusting!
What are you doing with the big mouse in the sign of nobility?
That's not a big mouse, that's a wolf. And the grandmother bought it for us to
play.
And I sewed the nice costume he's wearing.
What you don't say. A wolf.
Would you be so kind and explain to me what you're up to with this wolf?
I take it, it's known to you that I don't tame animals in the house, not even
out of fabric.
Give it to me!
Mrs. Sesemann, very nice.
Do you think it's possible?
Of course I think so. I didn't even know you could sew so well.
Very nice. You really did a good job, Heidi.
The wolf is much funnier than he was before.
Come on, we'll show him to Clara.
We'll hold him to the door and make him cry.
It's high time for Mrs. Clara's nap.
I can't wait for her to not go against the rules of this house.
But of course, Mrs. Rottenmeier, I understand what you mean.
You don't want Clara to see this disgusting animal, do you?
You called this disgusting handpump disgusting, didn't you?
No, now I know it again.
She even said disgusting.
Am I right?
Yes.
Now just look, Clara, what Heidi made of our wolf.
Didn't you want to make him a costume so that he looks like a snail?
Yes, it should also be a snail costume.
And when I looked at it, it was just a wolf again.
The wolf did a particularly good job for that.
Maybe we should give your wolf a few drops too.
Maybe he'll get so big and strong that he can ride the red cap.
Drops again. I only took some earlier.
See you tomorrow, Clara.
Mouth open.
Can't we skip lunch today?
But I don't like it.
Clara, don't make it so hard for us. They don't taste that bad either.
Yes, they taste awful.
Oh, Clara, you're being really mean.
I know what, Grandmother.
I can go to Clara's doctor. Maybe he knows a medicine that tastes better.
I'm sure Clara will take drops that taste good. May I, Grandmother?
I don't know, Heidi. Can you be sent on your own?
Do you even dare?
But why not? It's not that hard!
But Johan is supposed to drive!
Maybe the doctor can tell us when Clara can get out of the boring bed again.
Goodbye!
You can be really proud of this friend, Clara. She's especially nice.
Now you're making her happy, too.
What? How can I make her happy?
Very simple.
Take your medicine so you can get out of bed again.
Then you two can play much better together.
Drink it, then it will slip better.
It doesn't taste good either.
Disgusting, bitter and disgusting.
I know, but it will help you, Clara.
Hello?
Oh.
Aha, who do we have there to visit?
But that's a surprise. Or are you sick?
I think all of a sudden, yes.
Oh, that's what you mean.
That doesn't bite.
I thought it was a ghost.
Can't you make the medicine a little sweeter? Maybe Clara will take more of it.
She only takes very little.
Maybe she'll even drink everything at once. If she takes more of this medicine,
she would have to get better faster.
That has nothing to do with it. She has to get healthy on her own.
The medicine I give you can only help her and speed it up a little.
I'm a doctor now and not a magician, even if I would enjoy it.
Besides, Clara is only allowed to take as many drops as I write down here.
You don't play with medicine, Heidi. If you take too much of it, it can even be
very dangerous.
I'll tell Clara about it later.
Clara should actually know that very well. I've explained it to her a hundred
times, but sometimes she just doesn't want to.
Well, it's understandable. The poor child sits at home all day.
The best thing would be sunshine and fresh air for her.
To be continued
Sunshine and fresh air. The doctor said she doesn't need so much medicine.
What she needs is sunshine.
Very simple. So we need sunshine.
Johann, how do you start sunshine?
I don't have the quietest idea.
Then we have to come up with something.
He said Clara needs sunshine.
Sunshine nonsense.
Why? Sunshine is not nonsense. It's something beautiful.
Please Johann, let's take sunshine with us.
So say nobility.
Are you serious?
Yes, we're going to the forest to get the sunshine.
And how, if I may ask?
I don't know yet. I'm already thinking of something.
You just have to take me to the forest.
You don't have to worry about the sunshine.
I'll do it then.
Thank you!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Heidi, hurry up a little, please.
Otherwise we'll get in trouble with Mrs. Rottenmeier.
I'm just picking a bouquet of flowers.
Why don't you help me, Johann?
Picking flowers, that too.
Over there is the little girl from the city. Heidi!
Oh, it's you two!
So you came back after all.
Good day!
Did you leave your girlfriend in the car back there?
Clara had to stay at home. She's sick.
I came here alone today.
Does Clara have to stay in bed all day?
Yes, unfortunately. That's why I'm picking the flower bouquet for her.
I know a place where even more beautiful flowers grow.
Yes? Then show it to me!
Do you know where the grandmother always washes the laundry in the stream?
Oh, there you mean!
But then you have to walk a bit.
Come with me, we'll show it to you!
They're there!
Down there!
How beautiful!
But they have beautiful colors.
That was really worth it. Thank you!
You know what? I know something.
Come.
If Clara could be here and see it all, she'd love it.
I think that the new soap that Lisa brought from the city
washed much better than the old one.
The stains come out much easier.
With the other one, you always had to exert yourself.
My arms hurt every time.
There she is. So you can catch her after all. I knew it.
May I take the basket with me? I would like to carry my flowers in it.
I already have so many that they no longer fit into my shirts.
He is not one of us. Take him with you. He has been lying there in the water for
weeks anyway.
Thank you very much.
That's good. We have something here that you need the body for.
You really wanted to have something like that.
Of course, I know what you mean.
Here.
We did it! They're in there! Caught! We got them!
Careful, don't let the lid fall off and they come out.
Thank you, that was really very nice of you two.
Greetings, Clara.
Yes, I'll tell her that they're yours.
Goodbye.
Goodbye and thank you.
Live well.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Are you finally coming?
Yes.
Where could you have been for so long?
Miss Rottenmeier is getting angry again.
Yes, of course. I'll go and let you in.
Careful!
Oh dear!
Don't stumble!
Mrs. Adelheid, take a look.
I'm glad to see you again.
As I was told, you just wanted to go to the doctor.
Two streets further.
What's in this basket?
I want to know right away what's in this basket.
Cats?
Since the child has lost his language, you answer, Johan.
Unfortunately, I have no idea.
That's supposed to be...
a surprise for Clara. You stay out of it, please. So, Johann, what's in the
basket?
Well, I really don't know, unfortunately. That's a secret, too.
So, condolences! These kinds of secrets are well known to me.
Most of the time they have four legs, scratch and stink terribly.
Get him out of my sight!
Out!
There are cats in this basket for sure.
Am I right?
No, you're not right.
I brought a sunshade in this basket.
And a sunshade is good for Clara.
That's what the doctor said.
He said it's not good to sit in the room all the time.
Clara should have a sunshade and fresh air.
And that's why you brought a sunshade.
Oh, Mrs. Sesemann, convince yourself. I'm powerless.
Who knows what this terrible child is holding in the closet?
You heard it. It's a sunshade.
Heidi brought a sunshade for Clara because the doctor wants it that way.
I'm in a madhouse.
And maybe there are a few pretty blind fleas in there.
And snakes.
No, Mrs. Rottenmeier, there's not a single snake in there.
Oh, what a shame. What is it?
Are they at least fresh?
Frogs always jump around in a funny way.
No, they're not frogs. But I can't tell you what it is. It's supposed to be a
surprise.
Be quiet. Otherwise I'll burst with curiosity.
Oh, that's even better than frogs and snakes.
Please, Sebastian, bring the basket to Clara's room.
But be careful, don't let the lid fall off.
And don't shake too much. Be careful when you step on it.
And close the window, so you don't get pulled.
You are very sensitive.
Heidi, Heidi, every minute a different idea.
Isn't it wonderful to be so young and carefree?
What do you mean?
I don't know what you're talking about.
That was wonderful, Heidi.
Thank you, Heidi. That was a huge surprise.
Oh, that looked wonderful. I will never forget that in my whole life.
Many colorful butterflies, like on a summer meadow.
Look in the basket, Clara. I brought you something nice.
The butterflies caught the two boys, but I picked the flowers.
I really want to go back to the forest, Heidi. It was so beautiful there.
But first you have to get healthy.
Yes.
Nice.
You will see, Clara is getting stronger every day.
This child from the Swiss mountains is a true blessing for Clara.
This is for all of us.
It is a great relief for me to know that Clara is with Heidi.
Now I can drive home in peace.
You want to drive again, Mrs. Sesemann?
Do the children already know that? How did you take it?
That's it.
I have not yet taken it to heart to tell you.
But nothing else will remain for me tomorrow, I have to tell you.
This will be difficult for Clara.
It would be better if you could come here one day forever.
Clara needs you, Mrs. Sesemann.
Heidi and Clara still did not know that the beautiful days with their
grandmother should be over soon.
Uncompromised, as always, they spent their time playing, singing and telling
stories.
None of them thought that the grandmother could leave again one day.
But then it was time. Heidi and Clara had to find out the truth.
Heidi found the farewell particularly difficult and it seemed as if she could
not comfort anything in the world.
But as always, Mrs. Sesemann knew how to help herself this time as well.
She thought of a surprise for the two of them.
But we want to tell you about it in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world is the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back home.
Thanks for watching.