Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark berries
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Where are you, Grandmother? I'm already up there!
This time you wanted to win!
Did you at least count the steps or did you forget?
I can see that you forgot because of all the enthusiasm.
I think I only went up two and then five steps.
Now it's seven steps in total.
Good job, Heidi. One, two, three!
Scissors! I won!
One, two, three!
Now you've won again!
That's no wonder. You always just take the paper.
One, two, three!
Stone! Oh!
You fell in!
One, two, three!
Where are you staying?
I don't feel like it anymore, Grandmother.
Just because you're losing? You know what? You're a game-destroyer!
You're right!
One, two, three!
Paper wraps the stone, so I won! I can go on for a few more steps!
Another round! You're lucky for the moment!
One, two, three!
Lost again!
And again! And again!
Paper rolls the stone! Paper rolls the stone!
One, two, three! Hurrah! I won! One, two, three! Hurrah, hurrah!
One, two, three! One, two, three!
Why didn't you two tell me that you play jumping stairs?
It's easy. I didn't know you'd already woken up. I thought you were still
asleep.
Why don't you play with me, Clara?
What do you mean? I'd like to.
I didn't think about it. I'm sorry.
But of course you'll join. You play and I'll run for you.
You think that's possible?
Please let me run, Mrs. Sesemann.
That's really very nice of you, Sebastian.
I've actually gotten a little tired. My poor back.
Are you sitting comfortably on the stairs? Heidi, let's get started. One, two,
three!
Paper! Now you've made a scissor!
We've won! You can go up two steps!
Very well. Will be done.
It's not that bad.
You're good! You've just won the first game!
One, two, three! Scissors, scissors, paper!
What kind of noise is that? What kind of noise is that in the house today?
Warm up, Miss Clara! Why did you break your nap?
Because I woke up a little earlier today.
There you can see it again! You made so much noise as an unmarried child that
Miss Clara woke up from it.
I asked Heidi to play because I use Clara's lunch breaks to teach her how to
calculate.
Learning to calculate on the staircase? That's what you do in the classroom, at
the table, in a quiet way.
Where is that actually written, Miss Rottenmeier?
It's much easier to learn in the game. I myself have learned to calculate in
this way.
All right, Mrs. Sesemann. From my point of view, you can do whatever you want.
Just destroy the children. It won't take long.
Oh, how good that you remembered me.
I would like to discuss something with you that is very important.
However, alone and in your room.
As you wish. I will wait for you, Mrs. Sesemann.
What does Mrs. Rottenmeier mean by, it's almost over?
Who knows what Mrs. Rottenmeier always says when she's angry.
That probably doesn't mean anything at all.
Come on, Clara, let's keep playing, okay?
I'll start now, watch out. One, two and three.
You're moaning, Clara, you have to show your hand earlier.
Sebastian! What is it?
Yes?
She probably didn't say it for no reason.
Yes, I...
Did she mean that Grandmother will be going home soon?
No, no, no...
Is she going home, Sebastian, or not?
Did she say that she will be leaving soon, Sebastian?
Sebastian!
Say it!
Yes, I'm afraid that your Grandmother will be going home soon.
Tinette has already packed some clothes.
Clara!
Well, then she will leave us alone again.
That's not true, Klara! Klara, that's not true!
Grandmother said she would stay with us for a long time!
Yes, I think she's leaving pretty soon.
Come on, Wolf, play with us again.
You can eat me up too.
No?
At some point she will have to go home again.
Why? The house is big enough, isn't it?
She really wants to go home.
I see.
Then tell her that she can stay here with us.
You think you're particularly smart.
I've tried to tell you a thousand times.
Yes.
She lives in a small town, in a small house.
There she has a big garden and she loves it very much.
And besides, she can handle the climate better there.
Then you can't do anything anymore, can you?
Still, I don't give up. I want her to stay here, Clara.
Maybe I should tell her that it's not so nice here without her.
Maybe that helps.
I don't know.
This has no purpose at all. I've tried it many times.
She's driving, believe me.
No, I won't let that happen.
Heidi...
It's always like that. Father leaves me alone.
Your father always gets these telegrams, but it's different with her.
Grandmother didn't get any telegrams.
It's for nothing.
Hello?
Well, my child, what's on your mind?
So it's true.
What kind of face are you making?
Did you have a fight with Clara?
No.
Oh, of course! I almost forgot about that!
When I was packing, I found these pretty fabric scraps for doll clothes.
You can sew a lot of them.
Maybe this time you can make a snowman out of the wolf.
Here, take it.
Oh, don't you like it?
Oh, Heidi.
My little one.
Every visit has to come to an end, even my child.
No, he doesn't have to. If you don't want it, he doesn't have to.
But Heidi, you really are a lovely girl.
Heidi, believe me, I also had a lot of fun playing with you and Clara all day.
You will miss me. It was very nice.
Then stay longer if it was fun, okay?
Unfortunately, that's not possible.
But that doesn't mean that we will never see each other again in life.
Will you visit us again? When will you come back?
I can't say that yet.
I will write to you as soon as I am at home and have seen the right one.
Only then can I make new travel plans again.
Now the tears are falling. Then you look prettier.
Goodbye, Grandmother.
Heidi, goodbye, see you soon.
I am looking forward to my next visit with you.
Can't you say when you will come back?
Unfortunately, no.
Also not roughly?
Roughly, yes.
I'll come and visit you again when you can read the thick book all by yourself
that I gave you recently. You know what I mean, don't you?
There lived a man called Little Muck. I can remember him well.
Little Muck, who I mean, was an old mate when I knew him.
But he was only three or four feet tall and he had a head that was much bigger
and thicker than the other people.
He lived alone in a big house and even cooked himself.
Why did he cook himself?
Besides, the picture doesn't make sense.
It's from another fairy tale.
It doesn't make sense to say it out loud.
I guess I have to read it.
Little Muck, little Muck lives in a big house.
You only go there every four weeks.
You're such a good boy.
Do you know the fairy tale?
Let me see.
Of course. That's the Frog King. The picture shows the princess and the frog.
So, I thought it was the Frog King and not the little mug.
Now I have to start all over again, such a fool.
What are you doing? Why are you saying it out loud? You can read.
Sometimes I really can't understand.
Of course I can read, but it takes too long. Saying it out loud is faster.
As soon as I've read the book from the beginning to the end, Grandmother comes
back.
Is moggling also valid?
You are a small, brave dwarf.
You have a head like a mountain.
Turn around and look, run and catch us, little Muck.
Poor little Muck.
Read what's written there.
Why should I? I don't want to know it at all.
Heidi, stop moggling, she'll notice.
When I tell her in detail to close the book cover, she won't notice.
The main thing is, she'll come back.
You and your ideas.
To be continued
Well? Does anyone of you play along? Heidi, what is it?
Can't you change it?
Don't make it so hard for me. I can't change it.
What do you think if we go for a big walk tomorrow for the farewell?
On my shore there is a fisherman.
Thank you!
There they come.
A real bride at a real wedding.
She's wearing a very pretty dress.
I like that.
And write to us that you have arrived.
We have to hurry, Mother, they're already getting in.
They're already getting in.
Have fun.
See you again.
See you later.
See you.
Have you ever seen a wedding before?
Yes, of course, in our mountains, but it was completely different.
Write it down! Write it down!
Oh, why are we going...
Why don't we all go home and play a wedding?
Us?
Why not? Heidi can make such beautiful costumes.
Come on, Clara, don't be a playboy.
Join us.
If you...
Everything falls down when you move it.
I can't put it any tighter, but it looks nice.
Somehow I find myself very pretty.
I like it so much, it's a pity that I'll never be one later.
What? Why is that, Clara?
You know.
Oh.
Oh, come on, don't be afraid. You'll be healthy again at some point.
It can't always stay that way.
Thank you, Heidi. Hopefully.
Who's that?
We came to let you live.
Oh, Grandmother has invited guests.
If they are our guests, we have to say good day to them.
Happy birthday to you, Grandmother!
Clara!
All the best for your wedding!
The best for your wedding!
Wonderful!
Musicians, play the dance!
That's too boring!
Dance like this!
Musicians, play the dance!
That's too boring!
But don't even dance like that!
Yes, why not?
So...
Johan, I'm afraid it's about time for the both of us.
I'm afraid it's about time for the both of us.
Dancing is so much fun!
1, 2, 3, 1, 2, 3, 1!
2, 3, 1, 2, 3, 1!
The grandmother, Clara, where is the grandmother?
Grandmother, grandmother!
Grandmother, please no!
Grandmother!
No, don't go away!
Grandmother, don't go away! Stay with us!
Grandmother, Grandmother, stay here!
Please don't go away! No, no! Grandmother!
Heidi!
Stay, Heidi! Go home and tell Clara that I'm very, very sorry!
Goodbye! Come back, please!
Goodbye, my child!
Goodbye!
To be continued
It's you, Tinette. Wasn't that a wonderful party?
It's over.
Where are our guests?
Mrs. Rottenmeier threw them out.
To the front door.
Well, at least she slipped on a poppy seed.
You shouldn't be sad, but I really gave it to her.
She took herself impossible in front of people.
Completely impossible.
Clara!
Grandmother is gone.
She's secretly gone.
I know.
Just like every time.
To be continued
This nonsense stops right away.
Sounds good.
I really hope that in the time with Mrs. Sesemann your good education has not
been completely lost.
It may have been very entertaining for you all, but we probably want to go back
to behaving like decent young ladies.
I hope you understand what I mean.
The nobility is sitting right now.
Well, as always, she just doesn't listen.
That's the way it is.
Adelheid please. You seem to have forgotten that a lady doesn't snore.
Is good. Adelheid, what are you doing again now?
Oh, have you forgotten that you have staff for something like that? Sebastian,
where are you? A new spoon.
Thank you, Sebastian.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
The next morning Mrs. Rottenmeier took over the regiment in the house again.
It was all the same as before the visit of the grandmother.
She scolded every little thing and especially Heidi could not hear a friendly
word from her.
Every morning at ten the Mr. Candidate came and Heidi and Clara had to listen to
him for hours.
It was all no longer fun.
She could not stop playing with the two handpuppets either.
It was as if Mrs. Sesemann from the big house there in the Frankfurter Straße
had also taken the laughter with her.
But it didn't take long before Heidi noticed something.
And we want to tell you about it next time.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
www.amara.org