Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark berries
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
In Egypt, 639 to 641 of the Arabs are conquered, the capital Alexandria 642 and
after a short
retake again 646 of the Byzantines. And imagine, the conquerors
are happily welcomed by the Coptic monophysites. They maintain the old
administrative system, also take over the military camp Babylon Fusatum as
Fustat with
Amrumosche in later Old Cairo. And in the year 658 the nobility is actually
still dreaming.
Tch!
Adulthood, where is your behavior?
Excuse me, Mr. Candidate.
Discipline!
Mr. Candidate tells us the many exciting stories about the ancient Egypt for his
pleasure.
I want you to learn this by heart.
Egypt? Cairo?
Cairo is a beautiful place.
grandfather, grandfather
Oh, that was here.
I think the old Egyptians are boring.
Do you want to play?
My name is Miss Butterfly and I look like an old Egyptian.
Take the wolf, Heidi.
There?
There, Mr. Candidate. He looks very similar to him.
Knock, knock, knock. Adelheid, stop sneezing.
Knock, knock.
What's the matter, Heidi?
Can't you remember the old Egyptians?
I know what you think when you make such a face.
You think of home and the mountains, don't you?
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
What is it? You're so different, Heidi.
Aha, in this house everything seems to be mixed up.
Have you forgotten that it's time to eat?
Come on, we have to go.
We have to go.
I don't need them.
But these are all clothes that used to belong to me.
They are hardly worn.
Yes, you can see that.
Then take them.
When I go to the pasture with Peter and the goats, you can't wear something like
that.
Heidi.
You can't play well in such clothes.
But Heidi, you don't really want to go away.
No, I can't.
No, no, no! I won't let that happen! You just can't leave me alone!
I have to.
But we're friends after all.
You said you'd stay with me. What am I supposed to do if you leave?
Then I'll write to my father that he forbids it!
No, I don't want to be alone anymore.
I don't know what to do either. I want to go back to the mountains.
We can go to the forest together, like we did with Grandma.
Then we'll take a look at the flowers and the trees.
Is that possible?
Why shouldn't that be possible?
We're asking Johann to take us to the carriage.
Maybe then we'll meet your two friends again, yes?
The ones with the butterflies.
Or even better, you're going alone.
Did you get a call for me?
Yes, come in.
Please read it to me.
This is something very unusual.
Why unusual?
Because you have never asked me for it.
I'm just a little tired.
Then you should lie down for a moment and rest.
No, I don't feel like it.
The book is ugly.
Still unusual.
Well, fine.
639 to 661
Egypt is conquered by the Arabs.
The capital Alexandria 642 and
Ancient Egypt
I would call this book interesting, but not particularly pretty.
Heidi! Stay here!
No!
Do you want to run away again?
Let me go! Let me run!
Be quiet! You'll come home right away!
Please no! I just want to pick some flowers!
You don't want to pick flowers?
You want to run away again, that's all!
You're heavy! Don't pull me like that!
I want to catch a squirrel and pick flowers!
Come in!
You're mean! I didn't do anything at all!
I just wanted to go for a walk!
You're mean all the time!
to call a grown-up extremely indecent.
Let Heidi go, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
I don't think about that. She gets her punishment she deserves.
Get in your room, you evil thing.
That wasn't right. Heidi had no fault at all.
I wanted her to pick a few flowers for me.
Thank you very much for the clarification.
But that is now well known to me.
Reading it out was immediately remarkable to me.
Now this monster has done it. She has taught you how to lie and cheat honorable
people.
You should write to your father.
Heidi is not a monster. She is my very, very best friend.
Lady Clara!
What is it? You know that you are not allowed to get upset.
If you keep being like this with Heidi, then she will leave one day and then I
will be alone again.
And I have to be honest, I can even understand if she will leave one day.
Why are you always so mean?
Yes, but Mrs. Clara, do you want to indicate that you like this shop?
Yes, I like it. And I can't imagine how it is without you.
To be continued
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
Of course he disappeared!
Sebastian! Sebastian!
Yes, please.
Let's go!
Peter! Grandfather!
Hurray! Hurray!
Good day, General!
Good day, Peter!
I have a reputation....
I am guests...
Adelheid!
So, the dent has again....
No, I don't think so. She was still closed earlier. I just came by.
Adelaide?
Excuse me.
Didn't I send you to your room earlier? What are you looking for here?
This room belongs to Mrs. Sesemann.
Grandmother gave me the key. She brought me here.
Who? Mrs. Sesemann?
You've been standing in front of this horrible old hamster once again.
Forget about these stupid mountains.
You've become a city girl now.
No! I'll go home again.
That's out of the question.
After all, you're Mrs. Clara's partner.
But it doesn't seem to interest you at all what she thinks.
Don't you feel sorry for the poor Mrs. Clara in her wheelchair?
But...
And since we are talking about this topic right now, I would like to ask you to
never mention your stupid mountains in front of Mrs. Clara.
Not even at Clara's?
Yes, not even there.
Mrs. Clara is very sick.
The doctor strictly forbade her to get upset.
Do you understand? You really have no reason to complain and could show a little
more gratitude.
And now come with me.
Yes, I understand.
Grandfather Peter Schnucki.
Now Miss Rottenmeier forbids me to tell you about you.
She's mean.
Who's there?
Oh, the wind. At least it's like at home.
Only the tannins. They don't rush in front of my window.
I want to hear and see it all over and over again.
That's how it feels to be the only one.
In autumn there are always storms here, but I'm not even allowed to tell Clara
yet.
I'm not even allowed to tell Clara yet.
What happened? What's going on? What's going on?
Come on, say something.
There's a white ghost on the stairs.
There's no one standing there.
What is it?
Look again, such a big white...
Ah, stop it.
Yes, there it was. Up there on the stairs.
Oh, what? There's a shop opening a window.
You just want to calm me down.
I know the sound of the creaking windows. It has nothing to do with it.
I know very well that there was a little white figure going back and forth up
there.
I'm not blind.
I had closed the door earlier.
Maybe you accidentally turned the key the wrong way.
What's going on here?
Well, there you see it, Miss Rottenmeier.
Who else am I supposed to be? A spy, perhaps?
So what's going on? I saw a little white figure up on the stairs.
And if I didn't know there were no more ghosts, I'd say that was one.
I don't have any ghosts in the house.
Yeah.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Everything seems to be in order here.
Everything is quiet in the study.
You can't have made a fool of yourself. She's asleep.
I can find something somewhere.
Tinette, you must be mistaken.
Oh no, I'm not mistaken.
Then it must be somewhere.
Ghosts sometimes just show up very briefly.
Now stop with the nonsense!
And if it wasn't nonsense?
I swear it to everything that is holy to me.
It was on the stairs.
I beg you.
But...
It was on the stairs.
Hey Heidi, what was that? Something must have happened, didn't you hear
anything?
Clara?
Yes?
The clouds look like white sheep.
White clouds.
I see. You think of your mountains and want to go home.
If I could only imagine how I could keep you here, Heidi.
I can't, after all.
I think of clouds. I didn't think of mountains.
But I saw it in your eyes.
Then you were mistaken.
I want to go home. I want to go back to my grandfather.
Yes?
Why is Mrs. Clara sitting alone in her room?
But Adelheid, you seem to have cried.
So you thought about the mountains again.
But child, you can get over it if you want.
I don't think so.
But yes, for sure.
And now a kind little girl wipes your face off and goes to Mrs. Clara's room.
Discipline, my child.
To be continued...
Heidi?
Heidi!
What is it?
Nothing, Clara.
Heidi!
Leave me alone.
Clara, don't even ask me!
Heidi, calm down, please.
Why do you have to cry so much?
Is there anything I can do to help you?
I want to do everything you ask of me.
You can't do anything for me. Just nothing.
But I...
To Wolden.
The drop is not as bad as I thought it would be.
I could get used to this wine.
It's just a pity that the bottle is empty and so is the glass.
I don't know. I can't help myself.
I have such a silly feeling in the stomach area.
What if it wasn't an imitation?
What do you mean by imitation, Sebastian?
Well, the ghost, what else should I mean?
Well, let's do that. We'd rather open another bottle.
We'd rather open another bottle.
Johan, Johan, wake up, it's twelve o'clock.
Oh, so what?
It's midnight, it's ghost hour.
Come on, we're going to catch the guys.
Does that have to be?
Watch out, you're doing the best you can.
What are you waiting for?
Why should I go first?
Because you have the light.
The wind blew out the candles.
Don't be like that.
Don't let it go.
What's going on?
The ghost! I saw the ghost!
The ghost is up there!
You mean the network ghost?
Oh!
Psst!
No one there!
There's the door!
It's open again!
I think I'm dreaming!
Someone's coming!
The ghost is up there!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
The excitement in the house of Sesemann about the alleged ghost was so great
that Fräulein Rottenmeier sent a telegram to Paris and Mr. Sesemann asked to
come back.
Clara's father listened attentively to the reports of his employees, but he also
did not know any explanation.
Only the secret council brought him on a trail.
Did the ghost have something to do with the mountains, Heidi and the
grandfather?
But today we don't want to solve the mystery.
We will do that next time when we tell a new story about Heidi.
Heidi, Heidi, your world is the mountains, Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are
at home, Heidi, Heidi.
Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.