Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark
Trees
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
A ghost!
Holadio
Ms. Rottenmeier?
Yes!
Please, what is it, Sebastian?
The ghost is back.
How many times do I have to say that I don't like this nonsense?
But it's true. I saw him myself.
It's a white ghost.
You must have only dreamed.
That can't be true at all, because we haven't slept yet.
Oh, you don't want to say that he exists?
Of course. I saw him with my own eyes.
Oh, then get garlic, chamber hunter, ghost summoner, whatever you need to get
rid of him.
Oh, why? I was just missing that.
Fräulein Rottenmeier, what happened?
Wait a minute!
I hope he's not with her.
In which direction did he disappear?
I don't know.
Come with me.
Why aren't you sleeping, Mrs. Clara?
Someone was screaming in the hallway.
You're only dreaming.
I didn't hear anything.
I was awake. I heard it exactly.
Well, well.
You'll find out at some point.
We have a ghost.
When did the guest come?
I didn't mean guest. I said ghost.
Ghost!
Sebastian claims he was ghosting on the stairs.
I don't think there are ghosts anymore.
Ms. Clara, calm down, please. No excitement.
It's just supposed to be a very small ghost.
I don't care how big it is, I think it's terrible.
I'm convinced that Sebastian was mistaken. He must have been dreaming.
Yes, believe me.
And if he wasn't mistaken?
I'm so scared. Please write to my father.
Yes, of course.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Good afternoon, Sebastian.
Welcome home.
Thank you.
Clara!
Oh, Papa! Good afternoon!
Let me look at you, my child. You have become much prettier since the last time.
How do you do that?
You always say that when you come home, Papa.
I think I have to say thank you to the ghost. He brought you here.
Hello, Heidi. Well, little one?
Good afternoon, Mr. Sesemann.
Where did your red becky go? You're so pale.
Have you grown up?
I think so.
You're going to be a lady.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes, I'm coming.
I hope you weren't afraid.
We'll show it to the ghost.
Were you afraid?
Yes, but not anymore.
Now he can't hurt us anymore.
He was standing on the stairs and I swear to you, it was a ghost.
At first he was just so small and then suddenly he was so huge.
I'm really not very fearful, but that was too much.
He was white and he was floating.
Maybe it's a young ghost because he didn't even crawl.
Very strange.
Johan, please fasten the horses and get Mr. Geheimrat off.
We will lure this supposed ghost out tonight, but I would like to have our
doctor.
Come in, please.
Good day.
Well, little lady, how are you?
Did the flu get over well?
The flu does, but I'm afraid it hasn't overcome our house spirit yet.
Dad's right.
And you?
Fear too?
Good day.
I don't like you at all, child.
Why are you so pale?
Heidi hasn't eaten anything for two days now.
That must have a reason.
After we have captured the ghost, we want to examine you in detail.
No, they don't need that. I'm very healthy.
Maybe only one of the servants is allowed to make a joke.
Or it's an intruder.
Chess the king.
Now it will show itself.
It will show itself.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
It's so beautiful outside!
Who are you, grandfather?
Where are you?
It's so cold.
Why are my feet so cold?
Hello? Is anybody there?
Hello?
Heidi, what are you doing there in the cold?
Calm down, Mr. Sesemann. Leave it to me, please.
You don't have to be afraid. Come on.
We're going to your room now.
Come on.
Don't be afraid.
Here, please.
I should talk to her alone for a few minutes.
Well, have you calmed down a bit? Can't you talk to me yet?
I definitely didn't want to run away again. Suddenly I stood in front of the
house door. So that's how it was. Then you must have dreamed.
Yes, I always dream when I sleep. Can you still remember what you
dreamed? Yes, of course I can.
I always dream the same dream every night.
My roosters called for me and I went out of the hut to see them.
But every time I wake up, I'm still here in Frankfurt.
So?
In Frankfurt. The stars have fluttered so beautifully and the moon is shining.
Does something hurt you, Heidi? The head or the belly?
No, but there's something in my throat. I always have to cry.
Really?
If you have that feeling, will you cry then?
No, Mrs. Rottenmeier said I can't cry so that Clara doesn't get upset.
That's how it is. Did Mrs. Rottenmeier ask you to do that?
Yes, she forbade me to cry. And I'm not allowed to talk to Clara about the
mountains.
I assume you like to talk about the mountains.
Tell me, do you actually like being here with us in Frankfurt?
Yes.
Child, where does your grandfather live?
At home in the Alps.
Don't you want to go to him?
Yes, but I can't. I have to stay here because of Clara.
That's the way it is. Just stay with me.
You are a lovely thing.
Try to fall asleep, Heidi.
The poor little one, that can't be true.
Yes, I'm very sorry to have to say that.
Heidi doesn't know how to behave at home anymore.
Yes, didn't Mrs. Rottenmeier notice that?
No.
Oh, yes, of course, I have to make the accusations.
I should have noticed it right away.
She couldn't stand the child from the beginning.
I should have taken care of myself. But what should I do?
Even accusations have no meaning.
This is lost time.
We should rather think about how we can help Heidi.
She has to leave this place.
Is that the only way?
How am I supposed to teach Clara how to do that?
What a disaster!
Oh, come on.
We have to think about the little one first.
She's in worse shape at the moment.
Not least because of us.
Unfortunately, Heidi has to go to the mountains.
So far, no one has been able to invent any medication against home pain.
Just remember the little, lively child that came here.
And then take a closer look at what Heidi looks like today.
Yes, you're right. I'm an old fool.
Yes, it's me. Can I bother you so late?
But of course. Come in.
Thank you. Please prepare everything for the departure immediately.
What? You're driving again? The poor Clara.
Heidi is leaving. I found out that you are the ghost.
Oh, Heidi! Uh, Adelheid. I thought of that right away.
Yes, Heidi.
I'm used to it, but this time it's the summit.
Wait a minute. Heidi didn't do it on purpose.
But of course!
But no, didn't you actually notice that Heidi is sick from home sickness? She's
changing in her sleep.
Uh ... I only did it for Clara.
What does that mean?
I really had no other choice.
Mrs. Clara likes Heidi.
She really wanted this child to stay here, but she doesn't look like this
creature.
What do you mean, she doesn't look like this?
I forbade her to mention these mountains to Mrs. Clara.
But instead of being grateful, she threatens to travel away with it all the
time.
In the end, she went so far that she cried uncontrollably.
And I forbade her to love Clara.
What did you say?
You seem to have tormented this poor little thing terribly.
I only meant well with your daughter.
Then you must have forgotten that I love Heidi like a daughter.
Oh, this thing!
I think I've just met her.
Poor little Heidi.
What did you do with it, little one?
Good morning.
How are you today?
Heidi, I want to tell you something and I'm sure you'll be very, very happy
about it.
You're going home, to the mountains.
To the mountains?
Yes, home to your grandfather.
Home to my grandfather, to my mountains?
Yes, Heidi. You can go home right after breakfast.
I can go home! I can go home!
I can go home! I can!
I can't.
Why? Don't you want more at once?
Oh, yes. I can't go because of Clara.
When I drive, she has to be alone again.
Heidi, are you afraid to tell Clara?
Not that. I'm afraid that she'll cry.
I see.
It's not nice when you always have to cry.
I don't want Clara to be like me.
But Heidi, Clara will never be alone again.
I promise you that. Believe me.
You know, Heidi, I'll stay with Clara.
I don't know yet how, but I'm still thinking about it.
With swearing?
Yes, with swearing. What I once promised, I also keep.
But Heidi, do I look like I would lie to a little friend?
Clara and I, we'll stay together from today.
That's nice. But if...
Don't worry. You can leave in peace.
Yes.
No, no!
No, no, no! I don't want Heidi to go away!
Clara, calm down.
No, Papa, I don't want to calm down! I don't want it! Why?
Because your Heidi has a disease.
There's no medicine for you. Heidi has a home-ache.
A big home-ache, even.
Oh, no!
It can't be any other way.
Does that mean I'll never see her again from now on?
If she's better, she'll come to visit us.
Believe me, for Heidi it's the best, yes?
She never really liked it here in Frankfurt.
When Grandmother was here, she liked it. It was nice there, too.
Calm down. Heidi grew up in the mountains.
You can't just lock her up in the city.
I'm sorry, too. Heidi has grown very fond of me.
But the Secret Service talked to me last night and said that she would get very
sick if she stayed here any longer.
Now we can prevent that.
You know what, Dad? I don't think Heidi will ever come here again. But I will go
visit her.
Clara, will that work?
Of course it will work! We also went on an excursion with Grandmother once.
We picked flowers and caught butterflies and went on a boat trip.
And a few days later, Heidi gave me a thousand butterflies.
A thousand at once? Clara...
This Heidi, I think she's really done for.
She says they're also in the mountains.
Yes, they're also in the mountains.
And that's exactly where you'll see her fly one day when we visit Heidi
together.
With swearing, Papa?
Yes, with swearing.
That seems to be common here now.
Where did you get that from?
From my grandmother, of course.
You? Papa?
Will you bring me, when you have time later, Heidi's travel basket in my room?
I would like to give her a few things that she wants.
Yes, of course.
A triller pipe for Peter, tobacco for grandfather,
and white rolls for Peter's grandmother.
I'll get you everything.
Oh, it's bad. I know it's hard to do.
I have to regret it again, but Mrs. Diete will not get a vacation.
Aha, then you have to accompany her to the train and deliver it to her
grandfather.
I should go?
Yes, you, so finish your journey.
Yes, very much.
See you later.
Come in!
Clara!
Thank God you came.
I know how much you're happy.
Aren't you angry with me?
You should be angry with me.
I knew all along that you wanted to go home.
And I tried to stop you. That was mean of me.
Clara.
I packed a few things for you that you might need.
Oh, there are the white rolls for the grandmother in there.
And a pipe for Peter.
And tobacco for the grandfather.
That's nice of you, thank you.
Sebastian takes even more with him, I thought everything would be too heavy.
And what pretty handkerchiefs.
And what is that for a box?
But that's nicely painted.
Oh, a sewing box.
That's almost too much to sew with.
What is that?
You look wonderful. And how it fits your dress.
Oh, I see. Your favorite hat. But it's really too old now.
You think, Clara?
If you can't get rid of it, then pack it in the suitcase and take it with you.
Yes, I'll do that.
Goodbye, Clara, and thank you very, very much.
You have to go now.
Take good care of yourself, and greet the others, and don't forget me.
You know what, Clara? I'd like to take you with me.
You don't need that at all. I'll be there at some point.
Whether you want it or not, you won't get rid of me so quickly.
What is it? Don't you want me to come?
But, Clara...
Like you, I must have looked like Miss Rottenmeier when she saw the ghost.
Now, believe me.
Oh, Clara!
When are you coming?
Soon.
As soon as Mr. Secretary allows it. In the spring.
Clara, live well, Heidi.
Take good care of yourself, Heidi.
Yes.
And don't lose him.
Give him to your grandfather, yes?
And tell him I would be happy to hear an answer.
Yes.
Oh, Mr. Sesemann,
please tell the secret police a nice greeting from me.
With pleasure.
Johann, it's time for you.
Goodbye, Clara.
And come back for real, yes?
Yes, of course.
Clara.
Heidi?
See you later!
I'll come to visit you, Heidi!
Live well!
See you later!
Live well, Clara!
He mustn't get lost, kid!
The farewell from Frankfurt was not difficult for Heidi.
The whistling of the locomotive sounded like music to her.
Only when she thought of Clara, she became sad for a moment.
But the unending joy of being at home immediately drove away all the gloomy
thoughts.
Again and again she tried to imagine with her eyes closed in which light she
would see the mountains
and whether she would storm the Alps at sunrise or sunset.
Heidi could hardly wait to finally get home.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heide, Heide, your world are the mountains.
Heide, Heide, because up here you are at home.
Heide, Heide, come home, find your happiness,
come back again.