Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio
Holadio
...
Heidi, Heidi
Come to your home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
We don't have to run like that. The train doesn't leave without us.
Stop, Heidi. We have to get in here. This is our department.
Come.
There's even a place for a window.
Are there any stones in there?
Shouldn't I put the basket up there too?
No, I won't give you the basket.
Clara put the buns in there for Peter's grandmother.
Oh yes, the buns. That reminds me of your very first evening with us in
Frankfurt.
You quickly grabbed a bun from the table and then hid it in your shirt.
Did you notice that?
Yes, of course. I still have to laugh today when I think about what you always
liked so much.
Just remember the cats like that back then.
She chased them all away back then.
You cried terribly. And I had terrible pity.
That's over now. I don't need any more cats.
Schaffner!
Do you know that the train is going home to the mountains?
Of course, don't be afraid.
We're leaving!
You don't even know how long I've been waiting for this.
It's going home!
That must be Heidi's train.
Dad, now she's gone.
Yeah.
For ever. She was like a little sister to me.
It was so beautiful when Heidi was there.
I hope Clara doesn't cry now.
We'll see each other again, Clara.
I'm sorry I didn't like it.
Everything was so bad.
If you hear such a strange noise, then it's not the train, but my stomach.
I'm hungry.
Me too. Did we bring something to eat?
Not that. The train has a food truck in which we could both go to eat.
Are you hungry, Heidi?
Did Mrs. Rottenmeier actually say goodbye?
I couldn't find her on the street when we got into the car.
But I guess Mr. Sesemann told you the truth, didn't he?
Now just say you're done.
But the meat is good. Take some more.
You, Sebastian?
Yeah?
We have to be there soon, don't we?
It'll take a while.
Don't you remember your ride?
Oh, good.
We have to change again.
What?
Well, you know, you can hardly expect to be home again.
I'm so happy. I'm so incredibly happy.
To be continued...
It can't take long now.
Will we be there soon?
Okay.
Don't run like that again. We have half an hour to get around.
Our train is already here!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
But Heidi, it still takes hours for us to be there.
You haven't slept a second yet.
I can sleep at home.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Heidi, wake up. There are only two stations to Mayenfeld.
There are my mountains! Sebastian, look!
Not at all. I'm starting to understand you.
I'm starting to understand you.
These are my mountains.
Finally I'm back home.
Mayenfeld! Mayenfeld!
Pascal, I'm back home!
Oh, is everything still as it was?
Yes! Hurray!
Slowly, Heidi!
We have to go this way, Sebastian!
The way over there leads up to Dörfli.
Come on, Sebastian, come on!
There are waterfalls everywhere!
Let's go!
We have to go this way!
Something has been going on downstairs.
Heidi, slowly, I can't stand it anymore.
It's impossible.
Please stop. Could you take something with us?
From me, Gern.
Thank you. I'll show myself.
Well, get on. You're probably not used to our mountains.
You say so. We can go with you.
Oh yes!
Do you know that for the first time in my life I'm in the mountains?
Hard to believe.
Yes, and certainly very impressive for you.
Do you want to go on vacation here or visit friends?
Neither of the two. I only accompanied the child.
There, Sebastian! Over there is Duffy!
Look!
Hurray! We're there! I'm home!
Go away, sit down.
But Sebastian, why aren't you holding on?
You can guess three times.
I thought you might want to jump off.
Sebastian.
Over there, that's the church tower.
And over there, that's the way up to our hut.
But you can't see it yet.
Even steeper.
Well, just say, we have to go up now.
Ah, now I remember.
What?
You could be the little girl that the Almöhi had picked up. What was your name
again?
Heidi.
Heidi, yes, yes, now I remember again. Heidi is the little one. You should have
been in Frankfurt, they say.
Why did you actually come back?
Quite simply, I wanted to. I like it here better than in the city.
You must have been homesick.
Yes, and how.
Don't fall asleep, Lise.
Do you know my grandfather, because you know so much?
Of course I do. Who doesn't know him?
He used to always bring me the bread.
A long time ago.
And why doesn't he bring it now?
Because we had a fight. But it's no wonder.
Why is that no wonder?
Because he's getting more and more strange.
I mean, he's always been a bit strange.
But lately it hasn't been as strange as it used to be.
That's right. My grandfather isn't strange at all. He's very nice.
Nice? I hear that for the first time.
Gross!
Sebastian!
There's Snuggie's stable!
I can't wait to see her again!
Snuggie? Is that one of your girlfriends?
Snuggie, I always liked you the most of all. She's my favorite goat.
Excuse me? A goat?
End of the line.
That's far enough.
There's my fountain.
Good thing he's still there.
Good thing I met you.
I could never have gone on foot.
Sebastian!
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Do you know someone who can take Heidi to her grandfather?
If I do it myself, I won't be able to reach the train anymore.
I can go alone.
I don't need anyone to accompany me.
And the suitcase? The grandfather can get it.
Do you think he'll do it?
If I ask him to, he'll do it for sure.
Good, if you think so.
I'll open it.
Goodbye, Sebastian.
And thank you for bringing it.
Heidi?
Yes?
Live well, Heidi. Take care.
You can come to visit us whenever you want.
It could be that you don't like it here anymore.
That can never be in life.
Sebastian?
Please say a nice greeting to Clara and thank you again.
And when the grandmother comes to visit again to Frankfurt, then tell her that I
like her very, very much. And Mr. Sesemann too.
Goodbye, Heidi. Please take care of yourself.
Goodbye. Live well!
Goodbye, Heidi. Goodbye.
That's Heidi from Almöhn.
No, that's not to believe, Heidi!
Good day! Since when have you been back from Frankfurt?
Since just now, goodbye!
She's wearing an odd dress.
And he's wearing a hat to scream.
She looks like a city child.
Maybe she has school holidays and is visiting.
I want to know what the old man says.
I can't imagine that he knows it.
He hasn't received a single letter in the last few days.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
You can look all the way into the valley.
You can look all the way into the valley, all the way.
If he had gone up, all the buns would have rolled into the valley.
What a bunny!
Come here, say good day, I'm back!
No!
I won't do anything to you!
The hut! Peter is at home!
Yes! Grandmother!
Grandmother! Grandmother!
There she is!
Who came?
That's how Heidi always came in. But she can't be.
Why can't Heidi be?
I'm home again! Grandmother, I'm back!
Aren't you happy?
My heathens!
Believe it, it's me!
Good day, Grandmother!
Heidi is back. Our little Heidi, that I can still experience that.
I am so happy, Grandmother. I would like to scream loudly.
Then just scream. No one is there except the two of us.
My child, you have to tell me exactly what you have experienced.
Now I have to start crying.
Grandmother, don't cry, okay?
Please. Now I'm back and I'll never go away again.
Definitely not, Grandmother.
Even that! Now I almost forgot!
Heidi, what is it?
I brought you something. Guess what I have in my hand.
No, I'd rather tell you. It's a very soft, white bun.
Heidi, I can feel it. It's really a bun. I'll let myself taste it.
You're a sweet child, Heidi.
There's more!
What? Even more? But Heidi!
Did you mean that when you were talking about it?
Very well.
Is it good?
It is delicious.
I can not remember when I last ate such a good bread.
Nice.
Wait, I'll get you the others.
There.
What? So many?
There are even more in the suitcase.
Heidi, thank you, Heidi, thank you very much.
That was a very nice surprise from you, but most of all I am happy that you have
finally come home to us again, child.
That is more beautiful than all the rolls in the world. Thank you, Heidi.
Oh no! That's Heidi!
Good day, Brigitte! I'm back!
Heidi!
Yes, imagine, she suddenly came in the door.
Good day, Heidi. That's unbelievable. You are hardly recognizable.
You have become an elegant lady.
You should see her dress, Grandmother.
And first the pretty hat.
Please put it on. I want to see how it looks.
I can't start with such a hat. You can keep it if you want.
Heidi,
I can't just keep this good hat.
But of course. I don't like it.
Heidi.
Finally. You can keep that too.
Why? It's very pretty. You can wear it well.
I know, it's...
It's a pretty dress, but I'd rather go up the hill to my grandfather.
I want him to recognize me right away.
So, I just want to put this hat on and no one else.
That's how I like it. That's how it's right.
Goodbye, Grandmother.
Goodbye, my child. Will you promise me that you will come back as soon as
possible?
Yes.
Goodbye, Heidi. Be careful.
Goodbye.
I completely forgot what kind of sweet little thing she is.
I'm glad she came back.
What do you think will make the Almöy happy first?
we'll see
Hooray, Dad!
Joseph!
No!
Heidi!
Grandfather!
Heidi, Heidi, Heidi!
Finally!
Everything is all right again.
To be continued
At this moment, Heidi had been dreaming for so long.
She had painted a thousand times how it would be
if she could finally see her beloved grandfather again.
And now that it was so far, she could only cry.
And all the beautiful words that she had learned by heart were forgotten.
But soon the tears were over and Heidi began to look at the right one, as she
called it.
But that...
We want to tell you in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back home.
To be continued