Hello and welcome back to my channel!
Today I will show you how to make a
Horny
Lullaby
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
because up here you are at home.
Dark bees,
green meadows in the sunshine,
Heidi, Heidi,
you need to be happy.
Halaleli, Halaleli, Halaleli, Halaleli, Halaleli, Halaleli, Halaleli, Halaleli,
Halaleli, Halaleli, Halaleli.
Heidi, Heidi,
come home.
Find your happiness.
Come back.
Grandfather! Grandfather!
Hey!
Heidi, dear little Heidi, you are back at home.
Finally, finally, finally, finally.
My little girl, everything will be fine now.
I'm back. I came home.
I know that now.
But why? I don't know yet. What was it?
Did they chase you away?
But of course not.
Clara, Mr. Sesemann, the grandmother, they were all very nice.
Why then?
I really wanted to come home again.
I wanted to be back in the mountains.
Here, with you.
Home, Heidi?
Sometimes I couldn't breathe at all and I had to cry all day.
Not breathing and crying?
Mrs. Rottenmeier forbade it.
She didn't want Clara to get upset and Clara can really hurt you.
She sits in the wheelchair all day. She can never get out.
Clara's doctor then suddenly said I have to go home immediately.
Clara's doctor?
Are you sick, Heidi? Is something wrong?
Not at all. I'm very healthy.
I've got a letter from Mr. Sesemann in my head. Wait, I'll get it for you, okay?
This child.
Thank you.
Please read the letter right away. Mr. Sesemann wants it.
And this is for you.
Thank you.
You know what, grandfather? I'm thirsty.
I'm running over to the fountain.
Thank you.
It tastes much better than cocoa.
At best, I'll wash myself with it right away.
Still so cold.
The valley.
They're snoring.
I've been waiting for this for so long.
Sometimes I've kept the cuckoos that passed by the house for palm trees.
Something so barbaric. Imagine that!
Then there probably wasn't any.
Not in the city, but outside in the forest there were some.
Just imagine that. No tree in front of the house.
Now I understand why you said that. No trees in front of the house.
Heidi, do you also know exactly that you don't want to go back to Frankfurt?
Oh, how can you ask that?
If I would have liked to have stayed in Frankfurt, then I would have been there.
Or do you not want to have me with you anymore?
What? You don't even know how much I would like to have you with me.
How nice!
What's wrong with you?
Just a fly.
Put on something.
It's getting cold.
Did you come here like this?
No, of course not.
But I couldn't wear the dress I was wearing.
That's better.
The other dress was way too fine.
Oh, really?
When you first came here,
you only had a shirt.
I just pulled the shirt out of Peter's hut.
Did you change anything inside?
No!
Yes, it's all the same as it was.
The table.
The fire.
Are you going to make cheese again soon?
Of course.
Then I can help you.
But this time I'll do it right.
Look what I've got in my closet for you.
My dress.
Here, put it on.
It looks so small.
Oh, I'm stuck.
It became too small.
And what now?
I grew up in Frankfurt.
At least that's what it looks like.
I'm a ghost. I'm a ghost.
That's not possible.
Now I have to stay in this dress forever.
Forever not.
I think I should help you get out of this dress before you suffocate me.
I didn't even notice that I grew so much.
It looks like I would need Clara's fine dresses.
Where are they?
Oh, I left them at the bakery in the village.
Will you pick them up?
Of course.
Yes, I knew that and I told him that too.
Well, he couldn't imagine that I would come.
Yes.
Hooray!
My bed!
Aha! He did not lift it up.
What have you done to my bed, Grandfather?
My bed isn't up there anymore.
I know. I've taken it down now, Heidi.
And why?
Because... because I...
How should I know that you're coming back so soon?
You left so happily back then.
So you thought the whole time that I'd never come home again.
That's right! You thought that!
Yes. Yes.
That's what I thought.
But sometimes I didn't even think about it.
I just couldn't imagine it.
I didn't want to imagine it.
I was afraid you would have forgotten us.
But Grandfather...
I thought you were a little city girl.
You're still my Heidi.
And I'll always be.
I can't imagine it any other way.
Because here in the mountains you grew up.
And this is where you belong.
And not in the city.
Mom!
And now we're making a new house for me. 小心, you'll fall. 小心,你會跌倒。
It's a beautiful day.
It smells good.
Eilidh!
Hurrah!
It's just like my old bed.
If only I could sleep.
Grandfather.
Yes, Heidi?
You know, I also had a bed there.
That's what I thought.
But it wasn't very nice.
Was it hard or was it wrong?
No, it wasn't. I couldn't sleep.
You're crying?
Because I have to be so happy! I'm crying because I'm so happy!
I don't know what's going on with me either. I have to cry and I have to laugh.
All at once!
Cheers!
Father, I loved you.
I loved you too, child.
Isn't Peter coming?
Yes, indeed!
Peter!
Heidi!
Peter! Peter!
Peter!
Hurray!
Oh, that can't be!
Why didn't anyone say that?
Heidi!
Sven!
Bernie!
I came back home!
Good day!
The kids are so scary!
No!
Well, my little ones, good day!
Why are you screaming so loudly?
There he is!
Good day! I'm here!
Well, tell me, aren't you happy at all?
You still look exactly the same as you used to.
Yes, how else should I look?
Not quite, I've grown a little.
Say something so I can believe it.
Yes, sure. My name is Heidi and I've finally come home.
Great!
Why doesn't anyone tell me you're home?
I don't know.
Hooray!
The green one is Snuggie!
Snuggie, stay here!
What is it? You don't know me anymore!
Why don't you turn around, Heidi?
Why?
You're running away with the doll's daughter all the time!
No!
But you're a shi-
You've become a beautiful, big goat.
Now I definitely don't want to sell you to anyone.
Then you have to be Snooki's daughter.
Hello, little white goat. My name is Heidi.
How cute!
Don't stay too long. It's going to get dark soon.
We have to go now. Will you come with us to our garden tomorrow?
Of course. What did you think?
It's starting again.
Get in motion!
We'll be there soon!
Come on, what's wrong with you? We'll see each other tomorrow.
Now go with him!
Come on!
Get up!
What now? It's just like it used to be!
Are you going to move now?
Goodbye, Heidi!
Goodbye, Peter!
Wait!
No, no, not again!
A swan?
Go!
Go and get it!
Hey, you lazy faggot!
You're right, they already know where they belong.
Do you still know how to milk goats or have you learned it in the meantime?
Learned, milking?
You haven't done it for a long time.
Well and?
Learned.
Good day you two, how are you?
Swinley?
What's wrong with Swin...
What could it be?
She suddenly looks like an old pillow.
Did she eat too much?
Swinley? Oh, come on.
She's all right. She's healthy, that's all.
She's having a baby!
Oh, yes, Swinley.
And I took a picture.
Nothing has changed.
I took a picture.
But that tasted good.
Anything else, please?
Anything else?
That's already the third bowl.
Won't that be too much for you?
Oh no, definitely not.
I haven't had fresh goat's milk in so long, Grandfather.
There must have been other food for that.
Yes, there was.
But it didn't taste as good as the cheese here.
Well, that's just how it is.
Fresh mountain air always makes you hungry.
That's all.
No, there was only salad and pudding fried with sauce and jam rolls.
But it didn't taste that good.
In the afternoon there was always cake and cocoa to drink.
And I always had to eat everything, even though I didn't like it at all.
What do you say about that?
It's really not very nice there. Even the clouds look completely different than
our clouds.
There are no eagles. I haven't even seen a rooster yet.
They don't even have a dog. And no cats either.
Not even holy enough, that's good.
Miss Rottenmeier didn't want to have it.
Forget it, Miss Rottenmeier.
I think you like the cheese bread.
Did something fall in there?
Someone looked through the window.
Through the window?
You must have been mistaken. There was definitely no one there.
Yes, there was someone again.
Is there someone?
What was that?
I don't know.
Why are you driving around here in the middle of the night?
Peter, can't you knock?
Yes, I can.
Just because...
Because of what?
Something important.
That this is supposed to be for you.
For me?
I hope you like it. These are your favorite nuts.
That's nice of you, Peter.
I think so, too.
You think so? Come on, General Siegen, come on in.
Don't be like that. Come on in.
You used to eat with us, too.
Yes, but that was before.
You weren't here anymore.
Without you, I only dared to open the door.
It was all so different all of a sudden.
I didn't know if your grandfather still knew me, so do you know...
Come here, you two, sit down.
I don't understand a word of what you want to say.
Later.
Psst, I can't talk so well now.
Is that why...
After you were gone, he didn't talk to me anymore.
When I brought the goats, he always looked at me in a bad way.
Grandfather?
That has to happen to me!
Why don't you two sit down next to me?
Where did you want to eat the world?
And you, Peter, you're always hungry when I remember correctly.
So what is it? I can't ask for more than that.
He's changed.
He's always like that.
He hasn't changed at all. And you're a coward.
Could be. Yes, maybe.
Do you think he'll stay so friendly with me?
Mhm. But only if you finally sit down.
You go first.
The pipe!
Where is it?
Well...
There, Peter. I brought it with me.
No, I can't accept that.
Why?
Actually, I wanted to give you a pipe, but you must have lost it somewhere.
Heidi, let go!
You can accept that. Yes, for sure. Please accept it, please.
You don't need that, Heidi. Thank you very much.
Are you finally coming or not? I'm still here. Or have you forgotten that I'm
sitting here and waiting?
I just want to say something. I'll pick you up tomorrow, okay?
Peter!
Well, tell me, do you want to go without eating? You're not sick, are you?
No, but you used to stay here all the time.
I promised your grandmother to come home soon.
Aha.
Even if there's cheese and fresh bread and dried meat?
Meat?
No, thank you very much.
It looks good, but I should still go home.
Why don't you take anything with you? Put it in the basket.
That doesn't work.
Why not?
There!
There was a star, Schnuppe. Now I can wish for something.
What did you wish for?
I'm not going to tell you.
I can understand.
Will you really stay here?
I'll never go on in my life.
Say hello to your grandmother!
I will!
Goodbye Peter! See you tomorrow! Get me out of here!
Up! Up your legs!
See you tomorrow!
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
Grandfather?
You have to sleep now.
I'm not tired.
Are you happy too?
Yes, my child, very happy.
Thank you for watching and see you in the next video.
The next morning Heidi went right after sunrise for the first time in a long,
long time with Peter and the goats up on the meadow.
Again and again Heidi shouted loudly. It was as if she had never seen all of
this before.
The mountains, the clouds, the meadows. Heidi could not grasp her luck.
For hours she lay in the meadow with Peter and enjoyed the sunbeams.
For Heidi, a dream had come true.
Even an eagle saw her on her first day up here on the alp.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
The Amara.org community