Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
You'll have to find a family
I wish you the best
Don't worry though
You're not yelling
You just need to find a good place
But you've got to find your friends
I've got a friend
to save you
Honey, don't just go
Keep your eyes open
She's still asleep, and it's not even our Joseph's turn to wake her up.
I'll let her sleep tonight.
Now I'm so anxious. She wanted to go to the pasture with me.
To be continued...
You can see the valley, the sun is shining.
Wait for her, otherwise she will be angry with me.
Heidi said yesterday that she wants to come with us.
Then you go tomorrow.
I'm back home. I'm not in Frankfurt anymore and I thought I was dreaming.
Good morning, grandfather! Good morning!
Wait, Peter!
What are you doing in front of the stable?
You wanted to take me with you!
Yes!
Yahoo!
Good morning!
Did you finally fall asleep?
You're a nice friend. Just wake up the goats and...
Don't worry, you know I want to go with you.
It's not my fault. I shouldn't have let you fall asleep.
Did the Grandfather say that?
I'll get my breakfast.
Grandfather, can we make breakfast together?
It's been a long time, but it's open, isn't it?
Uh-huh. Thank you, Grandfather!
Peter, watch Heidi!
Yes! I'll watch myself!
Joseph, here! What's the matter? Stay with me! Come on!
Joseph! Here!
This dog is impossible!
La la la la, la la la La la la la la la
Check out this flower greenhouse!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
There was no such beautiful flower meadow anywhere.
Peter, can you please hug me?
Because I'm afraid that I'll suddenly wake up and then everything was just a
nice dream.
Do I look awake?
Even very, but I'm tired.
If you like this meadow so much, then we can stay for a moment and rest in the
grass.
Oh yes, we'll do that.
Flowers and goats everywhere, some even running up in the sky.
What is it?
You're fine.
Come here, all my clouds!
Cloud-herds!
You have to fly into them!
Heidi, watch out where you're running!
Nanou, where's Peter?
Peter?
It's raining flowers!
All the best for your birthday!
But I don't have a birthday today!
I'm sorry.
Hurray!
Faster!
Hurray! We're here!
I'm the first one here!
I won!
I'm back!
It's still the way it was!
Nothing has changed!
Echo!
I'm home again!
First, make sure we have breakfast.
When do we want to have breakfast?
Peter?
I bet you've long forgotten how beautiful the mountains are.
I haven't. How did you find out?
Forget it, Peter.
That's the only thing that has always bothered me about you, Heidi. You never
get hungry.
I asked you earlier when we wanted to have breakfast. And what do you do? You
just lie down.
Oh, well, we can still have breakfast. But who tells us if the sun will still
shine so beautifully afterwards?
I haven't been in a meadow for so long, and I've rarely seen the sun either.
That must have been very strange.
Yes, that was it. And how?
Imagine, no mountains and no trees in front of the house and not even goats.
And you know what? They all feel really comfortable there.
That can't be true.
Yes, you know, they live in big rooms.
Like birds locked in cages, and the windows are always closed.
They have a servant, and a maid, and a teacher, and they all take care of Clara.
Clara is my best friend.
I thought that was me.
Something like that.
Listen, I said friend.
You are my best friend.
Clara is nice.
Mrs. Lenn-Rottenmeier was the only one who wasn't nice to me.
Adelheid, you can't do this, and you can't do that, and you can't do that, and
you can't do that at all.
From morning to night, she's been yelling at me.
Is there so much you can't do all the time?
Uh-huh.
I don't really know.
She's been thinking about something all the time.
Well, that's all over now.
Rottemeier.
That sounds like seagull eggs.
She has a very sharp nose.
That's true.
If that's all true, then she was pretty mean, Rottenmeier, Rottenreier. If
that's all true, then she was pretty mean, Rottenmeier, Rottenreier.
There you are, Adler! There you are, Adler!
You have it good. You can fly.
Peter, look!
Heidi, wait for me.
I'm coming with you!
Clara!
I'll come visit you!
Yes, we are much more beautiful than you told us. I should have gone with you
right away, Heidi.
I should have gone with you right away, Heidi.
Huh? What is it?
I just had to think about what Mrs. Rottenmeier would say if she saw you eat.
What?
Have you forgotten about my beautiful upbringing again, my dear Peter?
You're like a thorn.
Oh, stop it!
Or do you mean...
But you know what? I don't care.
Really? Doesn't it bother you?
Why should it bother me?
Because you've been in town for a long time. Maybe I'm...
I'm not fine enough anymore. But Peter, do you know what I've always dreamed of?
That you've eaten 135 rolls. 135? Even I'm getting sick of that thought.
I think I won't feel bad after all.
I thought you could do it!
Yes, I think I can eat 350!
In Frankfurt they buy the milk in the shop.
The little daughter of Schnucki is just as cute as Schnucki when she was little.
Clara only knows all this from pictures, if she could see it.
I always described Snooki as a very small goat, just as I remembered her.
Clara would think I lied to her when she sees that Snooki is so big.
She sees?
Yes, when Clara sees it.
How can that be possible? From Frankfurt all the way here.
There is no binoculars that can see that far.
Snooki, come!
She's actually coming.
That's funny.
Because whatever you are, I'll call you Snuggie too.
Understood, Snuggie 1?
And you too, Snuggie 2?
From now on, they'll all be called Snuggie.
Is there anything else you want to know?
No, it doesn't matter. Come with me, I want to show you something.
A surprise?
Yes, even one that you'll like.
Then show me.
Get a grip on yourself.
Psst, be quiet.
Right away.
Over there.
Where?
Back there.
Oh, a bird nest!
Maybe they belong to Peep.
They're cute, aren't they?
They must be Peeb's.
The mother, there!
Such a big worm, it doesn't go in.
Yes, just like back then with Peep Matz.
Little peep-mutt.
We have to go back.
Already.
The goats have been alone for too long.
Come with us, Heidi.
If you want, we can go back tomorrow.
Goodbye, you little pussies.
Thank you, Peter.
I thought you liked it. And you know what?
Your stupid friend Clara wouldn't have been able to show it to you.
That's the best part about it.
Peter?
Yes?
You're mean!
Ouch!
Oh dear.
Ouch.
Excuse me, are you badly hurt?
Fall in! Fall in!
Yippie!
Look at the little birds!
Look at them!
How beautiful they are!
Especially the little colorful ones!
There are no colorful ones.
What?
Oh, my! That's one of ours!
A goat?
That's not good!
It's never good!
Peter, help us!
How?
Come back!
Here we are!
Here! Watch out!
I'm really scared!
No! She's running away! But I won't let that happen!
Peter! What does she want with the boulders?
I don't know. She just wants to run away. That's what Bunte does all the time.
But I won't let it happen!
Bunte!
Over there in the shop, they say that the Almy would have bought the child a new
dress.
She brought a whole suitcase with her.
I thought that the old man wouldn't dare to come in.
Hello.
Long time no see, Almy.
The child says you're opening a suitcase for her.
Yes, and what a fine one, made of leather.
Come on, old man, go and get it.
Do you trade bread?
Yes, I've never let a good business go to waste.
Then do it.
So, the suitcase.
Yes, we haven't seen each other in a long time.
So come on and have some bread from us.
Here.
That makes me very happy.
A nice girl, the little one you have there with you.
I know her.
I recently took her with me in my horse carriage.
She was dressed wonderfully and looked like a lady from the city.
A lady from the city.
What a joke you always make.
Thank you for picking up the suitcase.
You're welcome. No problem.
A lady from the city.
I heard him laugh for the first time today.
And we've known him for so long.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
I don't think we'll catch them again.
I have to. I have nothing else left.
Don't jump!
Stop! You can't do that! Stay!
You're falling into the water!
Wait! I'll come and help!
Hurry up! She's standing there so strangely!
I'm up there! Thank you!
A lake!
A mountain lake!
There she is!
Hey you!
What are you doing?
Without it, we wouldn't have found the lake.
Right, you're right.
Not even I knew that there was such a beautiful lake up here.
And everything on my first day.
It's cold.
Colder than our fountain water.
You think so?
But come on, we have to go.
Already?
Yes, I'm sorry too.
But we can't leave our herd alone for so long.
Oh, why?
Let them run away.
Heidi.
Oh, you'd better look around.
A sunset. Everything is clear.
The most beautiful sunset in the world!
I hope you enjoyed the movie!
No, don't catch me. I had to do something first.
There is a lake.
You were so far up.
Yes, and then the sun went down and the mountains lit up.
Yes, nice. But now guess what I have.
What? My suitcase?
A new dress.
Yes, just like your old one.
Thank you, grandfather, I wished that.
That's much nicer than the others.
In Frankfurt I was never allowed to wear my old dress.
Close your eyes.
If you want to.
Are you closed?
And now open it again.
Well, and?
Yes, that's right. Just like before.
Good. Yes, that's how I got you in there.
Yes! Hooray!
My old dress!
My favorite dress!
My old dress! My favorite dress!
Heidi was out of bounds and bound for joy.
She cheered and sang and jumped around the field with Peter and the goats.
Frankfurt was forgotten for her.
The life in the mountains, which she loved so much, had begun again.
Every day she went up to the meadow with Peter and the goats and even thought of
Clara more and more rarely.
But one day a letter came from Frankfurt.
Clara wrote to her and told her in her steep, clean writing by Miss Rottenmeier,
Mr. Sesemann and the canary bird Hansi.
For Heidi this letter brought memories that she did not like at all.
For a moment she was very, very sad.
But then something happened that immediately distracted her again.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back again.
To be continued