Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio
Holadio
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Let's see if the little goat is already here.
Grandfather, is the little goat already here?
Good morning, Heidi.
Bye
It's still so thick. What a shame!
It will take some time. And I could have sworn that it would be done today.
Yes, it will take some time. And I was so looking forward to the new one.
Have patience, Hailey. Nature does not follow what we want.
Yes, I know.
Hurry up a little, my love. Yes, Swanley?
There, Peter!
Is it already done with Swanley?
Unfortunately not yet. It will take some time.
Yes, I thought so.
Why?
That's usually the case.
Aren't you disappointed?
Huh?
Peter has already seen so many newborn goats.
But not this one!
Huh? I was supposed to hand over a letter, man.
Then I almost forgot again.
There.
The letter is from Clara.
Clara?
Here, for you.
A letter for me from Clara Sesemann from Frankfurt. A letter for me from Clara
Sesemann from Frankfurt.
Clara wrote it! A letter from Clara!
Clara Sesemann wrote me a letter.
Now just say you can read.
Of course I can read.
Heidi!
You didn't tell me at all that you can read.
Yes, and?
I learned it in Frankfurt. Why?
Come on, let's go.
It's from Clara Sesemann.
Puh, who's Clara Sesemann?
Dear Heidi, is it nice in the mountains?
Yes, it is!
I hope you're doing well.
It was nice when you were there.
Dad went to Paris again.
So he didn't keep the promise he gave you.
It's all the same as it used to be.
Miss Rottenmeier hasn't changed either.
I have to do what she asks of me.
I talk a lot with Hansi now, as if it were you.
School hours are boring without you too.
Sometimes Sebastian takes me for a walk in the yard,
but that's also the most exciting thing I've ever experienced.
Poor Clara.
If only I could at least imagine what you do all day long.
Are you going for a walk with Joseph?
I'm so sorry.
You still haven't had breakfast.
Are you sad?
It's not a very funny letter, Grandfather.
Clara is all alone. Read it.
Do you think she wants to visit us?
Yes, she definitely wants to. That's what she's always said.
Besides, it would be very good for her health.
That could be.
Mountain air is healthy. Why shouldn't it also help your Clara?
We both should invite your girlfriend.
Can I write to her right away? She should pack her suitcase right away and come
to visit us.
Yes. Here is the address.
Thank you.
When you come soon, you will see Swinley's little chick.
Can one read your writing?
But I...
Dear Clara, Grandfather and I would like to invite you.
When you come back, you'll see Swindy's little chick.
Do you think that's enough?
Did I do something wrong?
No, child, you didn't do anything wrong.
Do you think Swindy can wait that long?
I see.
Yes, you're right. I'm writing that she should hurry.
Do it.
Can't I go visit Peter's grandmother today?
She has a thick book with fairy tales and she always wanted Peter to read
something to her.
Peter? Can he read?
No.
And that's why you want to read to her.
Good, but I'll go with you and repair the hut.
Oh yes, grandfather, let's do that.
THE END
First you have to come in and tell her that we're here.
The last time she got so scared when you started to tap her nails, do you know
that?
Good morning, good morning, grandmother!
Oh, Heidi!
Yes, me, Heidi. And I even brought someone with me.
Isn't Peter with the goats?
Yes, but grandfather came with us. He wants to repair your hut again.
The Almö.
You can start now, I told him.
That's very nice of you, Almö. Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
That's all we have to thank Heidi for.
What are you doing? I can't hear you.
You're in the cabin.
Did you bump into something? Did you hurt yourself?
A farmer has...
I had a son who was so pale and immaculate that his father...
That's a Swiss fairy tale.
I can read it.
Yes? Brigitte, what do you say to that?
Please Heidi, read it to me, as long as you want.
I'd love to.
Where was I?
When the father came to his senses, he did what he could not dare to do.
First, he put a straw man into the church tower and then sent the boy up to the
tower at night to open the clock.
A light burned on the table.
While he wanted to make himself comfortable, two men came into the room, who
supported him for some time.
But then, after a short conversation, he was told that the house had no master
anymore, because it was haunted.
But this circumstance serves them for their thievery.
To be able to hide here, when the companion asked the closer one?
I liked that as a child.
But a woman's hut here, a treasure. Why do I have to read it if you know it by
heart?
I'm having a lot of fun.
Keep reading until grandfather is finished, okay?
And appear regularly at the ghost hour.
Now they have united for the third time today to lift this treasure.
As soon as the midnight hour was over, they heard someone calling.
And then the wild son handed over the white woman and got the treasure.
Why are you crying when he got it?
I don't know. Just like that.
I'm glad you learned to read so well. I'm very, very proud of you.
It was hard. So many letters.
Heidi?
Oh.
Are you coming?
Yes, soon. There are more fairy tales in the book. I'll read them again next
time if you want.
But of course I want to. And how much? I can't wait.
I'll come as soon as I can.
I'm looking forward to it.
Goodbye, Brigitte.
Say thank you to all of them.
Yes.
Oh, this Heidi.
I just hope that no one will take us away from here.
Yes.
Do you know how many years I haven't thought about this fairy tale?
I can't even count how many there are.
When you were a little girl, I often read to you.
Now I know at least what was good about Frankfurt.
I learned to read there.
Not only that, you also found a girlfriend, didn't you?
Yes, Clara. We mustn't forget to send her the letter later.
Unfortunately, we don't have a postcard. We'd better give it to Peter tonight.
Clara also has a grandmother. A merciful woman.
Mrs. Rottenmeier wanted me to call her that.
And do you have one?
Really not.
Clara's grandmother was far too nice to call her a merciful woman.
I called her grandmother.
Hopefully she had nothing against it.
She said that she wouldn't be a grandmother just for Clara.
She was nice.
And how!
。・゚・ ・。
Here, look! ・゚・ ・。
Here, look!
I learned it with that! ・゚・ ・。
Yeah? ・゚・ ・。
THE LADY AND THE MONSTER
There. Finished.
Tell me, didn't you want to write something?
No, send it like this, yes?
Like this?
Please.
Can you imagine that you give a wet, disgusting frog a kiss?
Oh, you're just reading the fairy tale of the Frog King.
You know it? I've always read the fairy tale in Frankfurt.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Tell me, don't you want to go to school?
Did you just say something?
I don't think so.
Heidi, it's getting late. Go to bed now, please.
Bye bye, Hansel and Gretel.
To be continued...
Yes, it can't be any other way.
And what if the little goat is born today? I should go.
Don't worry. If she came today, he would have said so.
And if you're not right?
What do you want?
You understand me very well.
I want to rent your house for the winter.
I have nothing against it, but you're not the only one.
I assume you're afraid that I can't pay.
Oh, what?
Someone recently came out of town.
He really wants to have it for his many grandchildren.
I want to rent it.
What?
Tell me, Almö, you seem to be
really serious about it.
If you pay in advance, I would let you talk to me about it.
Wendy is right.
I'll sell the new one, and then you'll get the money.
Is that agreed?
Yes. Why should we let a stranger into the village?
Thank you. You'll hear from me.
I wonder what he's up to again.
It's gone!
Maybe he went into the village.
There's something with Swendy.
Swendy?
Heidi, I'll pick you up tomorrow!
Peter!
Come quickly, Peter, please!
Swendy is sick!
Come quickly!
Oh, what?
Poor little Swenie. I'm really sorry.
It's all right. It'll be all right soon.
That's all.
You think so? Grandfather, here it comes!
It won't take very long.
I think it'll be quick.
She looks like it.
Maybe tonight.
Or tomorrow morning.
That's exactly what I thought.
At the latest tomorrow morning?
Exactly.
We'll see.
Hopefully it will be a girl.
Do you know what I'll do then?
Then I'll feed her with the most beautiful, greenest and freshest herbs in the
world.
Do you think she will be painted white or black or something like that for the
little blonde?
Are there also striped ones?
That would be quite funny, wouldn't it?
Tell me, were you downstairs today in the village to buy bread?
Yes, that's right. Here, take your cheese.
Maybe she'll be here soon.
Still nothing.
Be patient, Heidi.
Yes.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
I fell asleep! He took me to bed!
Grandfather! Grandfather!
Is she there? Is she born?
You can guess three times!
Sweet!
Such a little one.
What's she doing all of a sudden?
She's just trying to stand up.
Bye.
A little bit more, a little bit more, then you've done it!
Well done!
Hooray, hooray, hooray! We have a new little goat!
A pretty one!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Have you ever seen such a little goat before?
Every year.
That's not true. Last year we didn't have a boy.
If we ever want to get to the top of the moat, we have to go now.
But I can't go to the moat today. I have to look after my little goat.
Yes, of course. I feared that.
What name should we give her, grandfather?
I don't know.
Vivienne?
What does it mean with little? But that doesn't work when she's big.
It's a pity that Sweeney is already called that. She looks like Sweeney.
But we can call her Sweeney Two.
Is something wrong, Grandfather?
Yes?
It doesn't make sense to come up with a name for her.
Every goat has to have a name.
We will sell the little goat soon.
We will rent a house in the village in the winter and I need the money for that.
I want you to go to school regularly from now on.
But what am I supposed to do there?
All of a sudden. You always wanted to go to school before.
Not anymore. I want to keep the goat.
Heide, unfortunately it can't be any other way.
I have watched you in the last few days.
You are a smart girl who can learn a lot.
Please don't give the little goat away.
Soon we will have another one.
The little goat will be sold in the village. You can see her every day in the
meadow.
No, still!
No, not still!
It has to be.
So, is Swinley no longer fit?
No, how can she be? She brought the boys to the world last night.
Well, then you can pay.
Somehow I can't sell the goat anymore.
But in spring I will be able to pay.
I'll be carving toys all winter.
The things sell well and it brings a lot of money.
Oh, you know, I would prefer if you would pay me in advance.
Of course.
You're still the old fat ass.
That's possible, but I need the money right now.
I have to finish the house for the winter.
I would have done that myself.
I'd rather not. That can't be a problem.
Well, keep your house.
What does that mean all of a sudden?
You know exactly. You can rent it to whomever you want, but not to me.
You can rent it to whomever you want, but not to me.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
If you were with me, I'd call you little ghost, you know?
You're a little ghost, too.
Heidi!
Who took her?
We're going to keep her.
Well, what do you say?
Why, Grandfather?
Are we going to stay up here in the hut all of a sudden?
Not that. We'll take another house.
Why? Why all of a sudden?
I've been thinking about it. I've found another house. It's very dilapidated,
but it'll be fine.
I don't care!
I'll set it up for us for the winter. We'll feel good there. Besides, we don't
have to pay anything.
So we don't need any more money for rent and can keep the ghost?
Yes, we can keep your ghost.
Thank you, Grandfather!
I have to go down to the village and see the house every day.
Do you think, Heidi, you can take care of the little one alone?
Yes, of course!
Why shouldn't I be able to do that?
Little ghost, run slowly, little ghost.
You're good at falling, but not yet at running!
Every day the grandfather went up to Dörfli and repaired, to the amazement of
the villagers, the half-torn house in which he wanted to move in with Heidi.
Heidi was a little sad that she should no longer see her beloved Tannen for so
long.
But then she was very happy with the new house down in Dörfli.
She was only worried about Peter's grandmother.
And she asked the grandfather to help, so that she would also have a nice warm
winter.
This year there was a lot of snow.
Peter and Heidi saw each other very rarely.
You can imagine how angry Peter was about it.
But we want to tell you about it in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back again.
Thank you for watching.