Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark bees
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio, Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Honey, come back home
Every day the Almöhi went down to Dörfli and worked on the half-torn house that
he had found for himself and Heidi.
This winter he didn't want to stay up in the hut with the child.
The Almöhi had decided to send Heidi to school.
You can never do that in life until winter. I think so. Imagine the
Alp Öhe wants to pull him down in winter. He only does that for Heidi. What he
puts in his head
for the Alp is always like that. While the villagers were watching exactly which
progress the works at the old house made, Heidi had a lot to do.
She wanted to help her grandfather in her own way. She scrubbed and washed the
laundry.
She didn't want to sit still for a second.
The stable had to be mixed and the spirit brushed
She fed the goats and milked them
Heidi even prepared food
She wanted the grandfather, when he came home in the evening, to be satisfied
with her
I'm glad you're back!
Two apples!
Nice! Very good!
All for you, grandfather!
The next day
Wait!
You know what?
We're not staying at home this winter. We're moving into a new house down in the
village.
Are you waiting a moment, Grandfather?
I just have to say goodbye quickly. You know it.
But hurry up and say a nice greeting.
Yes!
I'm going with you. I'll tell you that I'll come home later.
Heidi is coming, big mother!
The Heidi, that's nice.
I just wanted to say goodbye quickly.
We're going down to Dörfli.
I'm supposed to go to school now.
That's good. Then you can read better soon.
Yes.
Will you come and visit us?
You know how long the winters can be up here
if it doesn't stop snowing.
And you always bring us some variety.
Good. As soon as the snow is solid
and Peter gets me with the sled, if he may.
But of course he may.
I have to go now. We want to go down early.
Oh, so you're going to Dörfli today. Peter, will you help carry it?
I'll do it on my own. And I'd love to.
Goodbye.
And see you soon, Heidi.
Have fun at school.
I'm very, very happy that Peter gets along so well with Heidi.
Maybe he'd like to go to school too.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
That the palm oil is going down again, I wouldn't have believed it in my dreams.
This is our new house.
In this big house we want to live.
Yes, there.
It's almost as big as the house of Sesemann.
It only has more holes.
But that doesn't matter. Come on, little ghost.
To be continued
He doesn't have a roof on his roof at all.
Look at each other, it's a little better.
Thank you for watching and see you in the next video!
Why are you standing around there? Come on in!
Err... Yes, I'm coming!
This is your stable, little ghost.
That looks pretty good, doesn't it? Maybe I'll move in here too.
This house is so huge!
Which room are you in?
Oh, in there.
This is our kitchen.
Yes. And where are the bedrooms?
Go and look for them.
You'll get to know the house soon.
Let's see.
Oh, it's beautiful here.
The grandfather must be sleeping here.
I would never have thought that from the outside.
Peter, look at the stove oven.
No, that's my bed. Then I'll sleep in this beautiful room.
But where are you sleeping, grandfather?
Just look around.
In the beginning I was scared, but now I like our new house very much.
I think it will be a very nice winter down here, grandfather.
Hopefully, because then the effort would have been worth it.
Peter, come in.
This is my room.
Nice. I didn't know that there are such beautiful rooms here.
Me neither. I've known the house for a long time.
But I've only seen it from the outside.
The people in the village say there are ghosts here.
What kind of ghost is that?
Why don't we take a look? Maybe we'll find one.
Come on! Oh yes!
Heidi!
No!
Is this your room, grandfather?
Yes, I sleep here.
That must have been a very nice room.
Come on, there's more to see.
Such a house ghost would fit in here.
Heidi, how do you know that there are no ghosts anymore?
You think that's funny, don't you?
You don't know how funny I think it is!
Watch out, the ghost windows are coming!
And I thought there might be a hidden roof somewhere.
Ghosts!
Two ghosts at once?
Heidi the ghost!
Until today, I've always imagined ghosts differently.
Me too, but I like ghosts very much.
And you, Peter?
Also.
Peter is the only ghost in the world that is constantly hungry.
I think I understand what you want.
May I invite you in?
You super ghost, do you want to eat with us?
Now Heidi is acting as if she doesn't know exactly that you like to stay for
dinner.
Very much, I'm already very hungry.
Me too!
Thanks for watching!
It's starting now.
Dirty snow. I have to go home.
Thank you for the food.
I have to thank you. You helped me.
Tomorrow morning I go to school for the first time. Will you come with me?
Unfortunately not.
What? You saw it yourself that it's snowing outside, didn't you?
And?
Tomorrow morning everything is wonderful white and that's why I can't go to
school.
I'd rather come here in the afternoon to play, yes?
But if you can come down the mountain to go here, you can also go to school.
Like this?
Peter, now you've ruined your own excuse.
So, Peter, you should really be ashamed.
At some point you have to learn to read, don't you?
You're welcome to read with me.
No, thank you very much, I don't want that. You have to read yourself.
Do you swear to me high and holy that you will come?
Come on, do it!
It's a promise, and it's a promise, and it's not broken.
I swear to you high and holy.
And?
Put your hands up!
Ouch!
That works forever!
Hooray! Hooray!
When are you going to pick me up tomorrow morning?
I would never have trusted you to do that.
I'm sorry. How could you have come up against Heidi's plans?
It's a promise.
You put me in.
Good thing you noticed.
Goodbye!
Not so fast. Here, put it over there.
Thank you all. See you tomorrow.
And don't...
I have a new excuse. No, not until the day after tomorrow.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
For a moment I thought I was in Frankfurt.
Oh, I have to get up. Today is my first day of school.
It's still snowing.
Peter, please, please come anyway.
Alright, as you wish, Heidi. But believe me, I'll never forgive you.
Where are you going?
Why did you get up already?
I have to go to school.
Yes, yes, Heidi finished that too.
Isn't it still too early?
And if I go later, I might think about it again.
And do you know why I'm going? Because Heidi put me in!
Disgusting!
Do you understand what he means?
Heidi put him in, you heard it!
Peter, please tell Heidi that she is a lovely child and brought you a miracle!
I don't think about it!
Cold!
My hat!
Don't be like that. As long as it's snowing, it can't be too cold.
If you knew...
I'll show it to you all!
This year I'll learn how to...
They will be surprised!
The flat ice!
Watch out! Now comes a surprise!
Or...
Close it. So, nothing about the school.
What am I going to do now?
Has someone run away?
Peter, heaven sent you!
Can you quickly run to the station and bring the bag to the farmer?
No, I have to wait for school.
Then you still have time.
He left the house just a minute ago.
You are still young and fast. You'll get him in easily.
Please, Peter, run!
I don't know. What's promised is promised and won't be broken.
Oh, Peter, come on, I don't understand a word.
We always give you the goats.
I don't even know what the farmer looks like.
But Peter, you see him every morning when you pick up the goats for the pasture.
Here, Peter, take it and hurry up, okay?
Then you talk to Heidi.
What, then you talk to Heidi?
Well, then I'll talk to Heidi if you want.
She won't tear my head off right away.
Maybe.
Nonsense, Peter Nunbach.
Well, well.
To the station!
I don't know!
That's exactly what I was thinking.
He's already all over the mountains.
Come on.
Let me in first.
No, I want to.
Why don't you come in?
Don't you dare?
Yes, but there.
What then?
Man, Heidi, the one from the Alp.
Why are you looking like that?
Three times you have to guess.
I thought she would show up.
That's Heidi?
Is this your first day?
I've never been to a school before.
You were lucky.
It's not worth it to go to school.
It's a lost time.
I saw you coming out of town with your hat on.
Klaas Jürgen!
Sit somewhere else.
Why?
Because it's her place.
I didn't know that. I'm sorry.
You can tell that you haven't been to school yet.
And what if I have?
Tell me which seat I can sit on.
If you haven't been to school, you don't know your grade yet, do you?
No, I can only read.
That's an achievement.
You've all started. Stop it.
Where did you leave your friend Peter?
He must have invented a new expression.
Sit down on your seat.
No, I can't take him away. He needs him when he comes.
He's not coming. Don't worry. It snowed yesterday.
You don't think he'll let this excuse go?
Peter always complains, even if it doesn't snow.
He's coming today, I know. He told me he was coming.
What do you mean? That would be something completely new.
He's coming! He promised me!
Don't get upset. Maybe he'll come when he says so.
Good morning.
Good morning, Mr. Teacher.
Yes, who do we have here?
Children, I can introduce you to Heidi.
She's going to our school from today.
I want you to be nice to her.
Do you understand me?
Yes!
Sit down on Peter's place.
No, I don't want that.
It's not a better day at the moment.
You can sit down. Your Peter won't come today.
Yes, he told me he was coming.
Yes, yes, but it snowed. He won't come, believe me.
No, I don't believe you.
Be quiet.
Heidi, be so nice and sit down until he comes.
I thought he kept his promise.
Well, the school has started.
Stupid!
Stop!
Is that my bag?
Of course!
Peter, thank you, you saved me.
Now I'll get the next train.
Yes, that's nice.
What kind of face are you making?
Oh, you're hungry?
Come on, I'll invite you to my field for dinner.
No, it's not possible. I promised Heidi to be at school on time.
Today's her first day.
What? Forget about school. I was only in school a few times a year.
And I've also become a good student.
No, I can't. Not today.
Ten minutes break. Thank you.
And under which bench did your father hide?
Too bad.
He always kept what he promised.
Get used to it. Peter pushes himself wherever he can. He's afraid.
Peter has never been afraid in his life!
Disgusting!
What's wrong with you?
I would never have thought that of you, Peter. No, never!
Just so you know, from now on we're no longer friends!
To be continued...
It seems to taste good to you, doesn't it?
Well, what's better?
Something decent to eat or school?
You can still have my leftovers.
Heidi must be mad at me.
I'm not even in school at the last minute.
Tomorrow is school again.
Yes, but now I don't dare to go in there at all.
Are you afraid of Heidi?
Tell me, isn't that the little one from our Almöhi?
Keep eating. What difference does it make whether she shouts today or tomorrow?
Give me your hand.
There.
Thank you very much for bringing me the bag, Peter.
My pleasure.
If I have two apples and you have eleven apples, how many do we have?
Together thirteen apples!
Peter, you promised me. You're mean.
Heidi!
Tell me, are you dreaming? Do you not like school that much?
I'm not dreaming.
Oh!
There's Peter! Peter!
But...
Peter! What's wrong, Peter? Are you sick?
I ran all the way from Mayenfeld and now I have side stings and a stomachache
and everything together and a headache.
You were in Mayenfeld?
Yes, but why? What did you do there?
Ah well, Peter. Did you give him the bag?
What's wrong with you, Peter?
He ran up from Mayenfeld to here.
You had to go all the way down to Mayenfeld?
Peter, I'm sorry.
Did you send him there? Why?
Oh, the farmer forgot his bag again.
And because I'm not very good at walking, I asked Peter to bring it to him.
Peter.
Peter, you're a sweetheart. You wanted to keep your promise.
Mayenfeld! Mayenfeld! Mayenfeld!
You keep your promise!
I think you're particularly smart! You're mean and educated and stupid!
Shame on you and your teachers!
Master Grandfather, it's very bad that I told them all this, but I couldn't do
it any other way.
Otherwise I would have burst!
In order not to disappoint Heidi, Peter trampled through the deep snow every day
to go to school.
Heidi helped him with the homework, because as much as Peter was suffering, the
numbers and letters did not want to go into his head.
Heidi put a lot of effort into it, but Peter preferred to ride a sleigh and plow
through the snow,
and after a week he tried to convince Heidi to forget the whole stupid promise.
Because Peter needed every second of the day to prepare for the big annual sled
race.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back home.