Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark berries
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio, Holadio
The mother is standing on the stove.
It's not a goat stove, it's a kitchen stove.
Where is the stove?
Aha.
On the stove.
Stir in the pot.
And she stirs in the pot, because she's packing a...
cake. For that you need flour, milk, sugar. Flour, milk and sugar. The whole
sentence, you
moron. You need flour, milk and sugar. The mother. Flour, milk and a mother.
Are you coming with us today, Heidi?
No, I can't. Look how it's snowing again.
Yes.
Do you think it will stop snowing again at some point?
Hey, I have an idea.
Which one?
Come with me home and warm yourself up.
That's a good idea for the first time.
That. That was good. Thank you.
It never stops today.
Don't you think, Peter, that the grandmother is already waiting for you?
I don't know. I think you have to go.
What? He's still cutting!
If I don't run now, I won't get through.
Wait a minute, okay?
Why?
I want you to take a letter for the grandmother.
From whom?
From me! From who else?
Do you know if you can write a snow storm in front of the door?
If you don't even know that, how should I know that?
What are you thinking about? Maybe you'll come up with one.
I don't like it.
Promise me you won't forget to hand over the letter.
I'll hand it over.
Certainly.
Goodbye, see you tomorrow!
Come home safely! Goodbye!
Everything's covered in snow! Wet!
Good day! I'm home!
Please!
This is not to be stopped!
There's already snowing all over the place!
What day is it?
Did Heidi come with you?
Of course not. She can't do that today. It's snowing way too much. A meter high.
Yes, of course. If it snows like you say, it's way too dangerous.
Oh, I have a notebook with me. For you, grandmother.
From school?
No. From Heidi. There. Here.
This Heidi. She knows exactly that I can't read.
Yes, we both forgot that earlier.
I've never been to school. You have to read it yourself.
There's definitely nothing in it.
There's definitely something in the letter. Why else would Heidi have written
it?
Yes, I don't know.
Dear Grandmother, I wanted to come today, but I...
I'm snowing in a snowstorm, it's a pity.
As soon as it stops snowing, I'll come up.
Promised is promised.
What kind of writing is that?
Promised and will not be broken.
I would have liked to come today, but...
I'm snowing in a snowstorm, it's a pity.
What kind of writing is that?
I would have liked to come today, but...
I'm snowing in a snowstorm, it's a pity.
DADDY IS GONNA DIE
Now don't be so mean.
You forgot it too.
It has nothing to do with it.
You know exactly how hard it is to read.
That's what makes me mad.
Don't pretend, what was that?
You don't know how you write.
I know, my writing is not beautiful.
But I think that you can please your blind grandmother without pretending
afterwards.
Yeah!
Are you done now? Did you tell Peter everything you meant?
Mhm. I also told him everything I meant.
You can write another letter.
But then write a very short one with two sentences that I can learn by heart.
I think I know what we're doing with you.
We're giving you Heidi's thick fairy tale book to read.
Heidi's fairy tale book? No!
I also learned with it. It was very easy.
Yeah, uh, forget it. I have to go now.
Peter, if they hear you, they'll think it hurts to learn to read.
Come with me, you'll get a warm cheese on the way.
No, come on, Peter!
But only if you read the book in the closet.
You coward!
Should we play now or not?
Play!
It's your turn, now do it!
You sleepyhead, this is my little piece of wood.
Like this?
Oh come on, let's stop it.
Don't you feel like it anymore?
Yes, but you don't.
All you do is watch your grandfather.
You don't care about the game at all.
Do you find it so exciting what I'm doing here?
I've never seen her doing it before.
Well then come on, try it.
Let's see if you can do it.
Yes, can I really do it?
Yes, if you want to.
All the best.
Yes, thank you.
Grandfather, he dropped something.
You can call it that, too.
Really very good, Peter.
He's really good at that, isn't he?
Not good enough for a long time, but it works.
Yes, for the beginning it's already very good.
Really very skillful.
Good money!
Heidi!
This year you win!
I think so!
Yes!
But only if this time who goes through the finish line last wins.
Who goes through the finish line last?
Is this a race?
Uh-huh.
Not a race.
There will be a sled race again.
Like every year.
Yes?
I'm in!
And you'll see, I'm the winner!
What?
No way!
You'll be amazed!
I'm really good at sledding.
Ask Peter!
Yes, ask him!
What's wrong with them?
Why are they laughing like that?
Did I say something wrong?
Girls don't take part in this.
It's only for boys.
And that's what you like?
Good morning.
Dude, there's a sled race.
There's a sled race every year. Why?
I know, but this year it's a special race.
A girl is taking part for the first time.
Why?
I'm taking part. It's easy.
You must be crazy.
We'll see.
Come on.
But we were always together.
I don't participate in the race, either.
Why?
If I'm not there, you can go with me.
No, I can't.
Of course, and you win too.
If I don't participate, I can't win either.
Why? I don't understand you. You're very good at it.
And with which sled?
Peter!
Should I participate in a race with this orange box?
Then we have to get another sled if it doesn't work.
What do you mean?
Oh, I see.
Do you think I always drive with this car because I enjoy it so much?
That's a sled!
How am I supposed to get across there?
Peter, the grandfather has enough wood for a sled.
And?
What would he give me right now? You need that for his toys.
How do you want to know that now, before you asked?
Do you dare?
Why not? I think he'll give us the wood for sure.
But then you have to help him with the sled.
But that's very difficult.
Where do you get that from? Come with me, we'll ask him.
To be continued...
Yes, I can understand that very well.
Exactly. You should have seen the other sleds. They are fast.
There is only one thing that helps. We have to make a faster sled.
Yes, hurray! You said it right.
You can have wood under one condition. Peter makes the sled himself.
Yes, he will help you.
What do I need?
That's nice.
With zeal Heidi and Peter went to work to build the sled.
They sawed and hammered and were not tired of painting themselves
as Peter would drive through the destination as the first with the self-made
sled.
The grandfather supervised the work. From time to time he helped them with a
wheel.
But that was all he contributed to the sled building.
Peter could be proud of himself, because he was really very skillful.
And then the fox said to the goose and what do you think how the goose would be
happy if Peter could also listen.
Peter!
Yes?
What do you think if you finally pay attention?
I did pay attention!
That's right!
Don't lie again!
All right.
Then the goose said to the fox, too stupid.
We'll hear that tomorrow.
Well, finally!
Pack your things!
Pack your things! Let's go! Only today afternoon, then it's over!
Peter? Yes, what?
Is it true that you're participating in the race this time?
How do you know that?
They say that the Almöhi builds the Alps.
Aha, that's how they say it.
That will definitely be a good one. The Almöhi understands something about it.
He does that only because Heidi likes you.
If you want to know exactly, he doesn't do anything. I do it.
Yes, and you don't even believe how well he does it.
We really don't believe that. Don't give him any questions.
What?
Who's betting here?
Well, you. Who else?
Making a sled is not that easy.
Why?
Peter can never do that in his life.
I'll bet with you if you want.
Peter has two left thumbs.
Everyone knows that.
Then everyone knows that you have two stupid heads.
You're pretty cheeky.
Heidi, come on, we don't have time for that.
Aha, first lie and then believe it.
So good, if you don't want to believe it,
then come to us and ask my grandfather
who makes the sled.
Ask Almy?
Al...
You're too shy to do that. That's fine.
Shy? I've heard that before. Come on, let's go.
Actually, I have to go home. I shouldn't be late for dinner.
Grandfather, we're back!
Is school already over?
I've got a few schoolmates with me. They really want to ask you something they
don't want to believe.
Well, what are you still waiting for?
What's going on?
We... we know it's...
Because... because we said...
Exactly because of that, yes.
Are you all hearing badly or stuttering?
The food is getting cold.
Goodbye.
You have to explain that to me now.
Gladly.
They just didn't want to believe me earlier that Peter was making the sled and
not you.
Then I told them they shouldn't ask themselves.
But why did they all run away all of a sudden?
Who knows? Sometimes you children behave so strangely.
But your sled is waiting for you.
Good!
This here?
Yes! Hooray! Hooray!
Come on in quickly! He's gone!
It's done.
Show me.
Very good, Peter, excellent.
So?
Isn't it good enough?
Oh yes, it's very good.
I just want to improve it a little bit.
No, leave it.
It should look exactly like everyone else thinks Peter made it.
As you wish.
Thank you.
Come on, let's go out and try it on, okay?
Oh yes.
Let's go.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
All of a sudden, he went to the side all by himself.
Like this?
I don't think I did that right.
Like this.
And if you can't do it now, what do we do then, huh?
Just don't be afraid. I can do it. Easy.
Hopefully.
I'd rather help you.
It doesn't matter.
Really, Heidi, it's easy. Believe me.
How do you want to know? You don't even know what's wrong.
One side is higher than the other.
I don't know.
I need to pee!
How was the first ride with the sled?
Short.
Isn't he fast enough?
If only. He doesn't even ride straight.
Let's go.
Well, don't look so disappointed. Peter will get it right, for sure.
I don't know. He's going to take it all off again.
No, it's going to be right.
Peter! Grandfather thinks it's going to be something.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
Hopefully, everything will be fine.
And if he falls apart now?
Here we go!
Come on!
Peter, we're going to catch him!
Here we go!
I'm finally going to catch him!
Peter! Peter! Peter!
Peter! Peter!
Here we go!
No! No! No!
Peter?
Peter!
We arrived at the bottom.
Congratulations, Peter.
That went quite well.
Isn't it nice that you made the cut all by yourself?
Unfortunately there was another one who came exactly with him.
So two wins.
Nevertheless, it is a good result that you can be proud of.
Are you happy?
Yes, I would love to burst.
Well, let's hope that you don't do that.
You will be a good carpenter.
Could be.
Could be!
I would like to!
Then let's go to my grandfather.
Good, I'll bring it to you, but only after school.
Not instead.
That could be good for you.
Now run and tell Grandmother that you've won.
And greetings.
Goodbye and thank you very, very much, Grandfather.
Did you say Grandfather?
Yes, of course.
The winter went by and Heidi discovered together with Joseph the first precincts
of spring.
Every single flower was greeted by her with joy and soon the Almöhi and she
could pull up to the hut again.
It was still cold and there was high snow, but up here Heidi still felt the most
comfortable.
And then for the first time in a long time a letter from Clara from Frankfurt
came again.
In which she wrote that she would not wish for anything more beautiful than to
be able to visit Heidi and Peter, but we want to tell you about that in our next
story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains. Heidi, Heidi, because up here you
are at home. Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.
Thank you for watching.