Welcome to my channel!
Today I will show you how to make a
Heidi. Heidi, your world is the mountains. Heidi. Heidi, because I too am a
Heidi.
Heide, Heide, your world are the mountains.
Heide, Heide, because up here you are at home.
Dark fir trees, green meadows in the sunshine.
Heide, Heide, you need to be happy.
Heide, Heide, come home.
Find your happiness.
Come back again.
Come back to me.
Heide, Heide, he's getting up.
Heide, Heide, get up.
Heide, Heide, you need to find your happiness.
Heide, Heide, you need to be happy.
Heide, Heide, he's getting up.
We're going back home. We're going up to the hut.
Heidi, where are you staying?
I'll be right back, Grandfather.
Well, good night.
Good night.
Well, then stay away from me. I'll go without you.
But it's about time.
After Geißlein was ready to join the group, Heidi and her grandfather could
finally break up.
So you're going up to the hut again now?
Yes, of course! It's spring! Goodbye!
Are you going down again next winter?
I think so. In any case, the grandfather said it earlier.
One moment, Heidi!
Here, a few places to go.
Oh, thank you very much! Goodbye!
Goodbye, Heidi.
Don't you need to go to school anymore?
Of course!
Goodbye!
She's in a good mood.
You know, it was really nice down there, but I'm glad we're finally coming home.
There you are again, Grandmother. You're coming back.
Yes?
Good morning!
We're coming home again. Good day!
Good day, Heidi.
There, the cookies were given to me down in the village. Take them, please.
No, thank you very much, Heidi.
You keep them. You got them.
Oh, what? Keep them? Where is Peter?
He's collecting wood. Maybe you can see him somewhere in the forest.
Maybe. I have to go now. Goodbye.
See you soon. Peter will be happy to see you again.
There!
Please, Grandfather! Come on, Kaislein, quickly!
Kaislein, we're at home!
Kaislein? Kaislein!
Kaislein!
Oh, he's half.
You slipped.
Kaislein!
Ah, my feathers.
Do you hear them rustling? They say good day!
Did you hear the tannins? They're rustling!
Yes, at home!
Is everything okay up there too?
Yes!
Done!
Nice!
I like it even better!
Miss Clara, what about the meat? Is it too tough?
I'm not hungry. I don't like it.
What does that mean?
What kind of strange behavior is that, Miss Clara?
You have to eat three times a day, regularly.
It's good for your health.
Dear Clara, everyone wants you to come visit us.
Grandfather, Joseph, Schweli, Berli, Geißlein.
We would like to show you how beautiful it is here.
I have already seen three eagles this spring.
Peter and I usually lie in the meadow and sleep in the sun.
I have grown a bit again and have become completely brown.
Yes, please.
Can't you sleep? I saw through the window that you still have some light.
I can't sleep yet.
Would you like me to make you warm milk or a glass of sugar water?
No, that's not necessary. I sleep like that too.
Good night, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Your grandmother was right. If you were here with us, you would quickly become
healthy.
And I know that you like it here too.
Do you remember our afternoon in the forest?
You liked the sun so much back then.
...
And do you know how many flowers there were?
You might not believe me, but there are many, many, many, many thousand more
flowers here.
Sebastian, Sebastian, come!
Yes.
Yes, please.
I have to talk to Mrs. Rottenmeier immediately. Please bring me in.
Of course, Mrs. Clara, gladly.
Has the sun gotten too hot for you, Mrs. Clara?
No, but we have to write a letter to my father right away.
Whaaat?
Did something special happen?
No, but I have to remind him of something.
He gave me a promise last time, but he probably forgot it.
So?
What kind of promise?
He said I was allowed to go to the mountains.
Did he really promise you that?
Miss Clara, do you want to take me on your arm or how am I supposed to
understand that?
Your father can never have said such nonsense in his life. Never!
Oh yes, when Heidi left her at that time, he promised me that I would be able to
visit you when spring comes again.
And how do you imagine yourself getting there? The mountains are not just on the
other side of Mainz.
I know, I'm not stupid.
What a language, how ordinary.
You should be ordinary to me. I'll write to my father anyway.
Don't talk to me in that tone.
What do you think if we were a little more in shape?
Please think about it, my love.
Sebastian?
Yes, please.
Bring them to your room.
Mrs. Clara wants to think about it.
No.
This is my third one.
Do you think Clara has already received my letter?
I mean the last one, the long one.
You should have had it a week ago.
Hopefully she can read my writing.
Well, I doubt that.
Do you think I should rewrite everything?
No, I didn't mean that seriously.
I'm sure she can read your writing like that.
Then she knows that we invited her to us.
Hopefully she'll come soon. That would be great.
Yes, please.
I've been waiting for you in the dining room for 15 minutes.
The soup is already cold.
Should she?
What do you mean, can it be that you just said, should she?
I'll eat again when you write the letter.
So no, that's not to be understood.
You are unwise, Miss Clara, and I have to say it, also undressed.
But you are intelligent enough to know what to do with it.
I know that very well, but I don't care.
I'm shocked. Shocked and very disappointed.
I didn't expect that from you.
I don't care.
What do you mean?
Don't act as if you didn't understand.
I want you to write the letter.
Be reasonable. That's not possible.
Why?
It's possible.
I won't eat anything until you write to my father.
But...
Well, fine. I'll ask your father to come home. He'll decide for himself.
Unfortunately, I can't bear that responsibility.
Good. Write it down for sure, okay?
Don't change your mind anymore?
Yes, I'll write it down. You've won.
But I'll also write that I'm against it.
Write the letter down for tonight. Then we can send it to you tomorrow.
Thank you.
Yes, please.
Sebastian! Sebastian, I'm hungry!
Come on!
Heidi!
Good morning! Did the postman give you a letter for me today, Peter?
No, why should he?
Then Clara can't read my handwriting after all.
Of course, Clara.
You can't write to me, can you?
You don't believe how happy you can be.
You couldn't read my handwriting after all.
Are you sick?
Tell me, what's wrong with you?
You're slowly getting on my nerves.
I can't change that either.
What is it now? Are you coming?
No, I'm not going with you anymore. I'm going home. I have to write a letter.
You're crazy.
Fine, then I'm crazy.
That's not so mean!
What do you want here?
No, little ghost, you belong to your herd.
Now eat well so you can grow, okay?
Go on!
No, no, no, I don't have time to play with you today.
Run to the other little ghosts, and fast!
I said fast!
For Clara, she throws us away like an old roller.
Love...
Finally you're fine. I'm fine too.
This time you can read my handwriting for sure.
I'm home again, Clara!
Papa, finally, papa!
Nice, you look very good, my child.
I thought you were very pale.
Mrs. Rottenmeier wrote you were on a hunger strike.
What's going on?
I wanted to, too. I was afraid you'd forget the promise you gave me.
And you almost did, didn't you?
How did you know?
Clara, I just wanted to talk to you.
You don't need to. I want to visit Heidi.
Who says you're not supposed to do that, child?
Yes, but why do we have to talk then?
Because I want you to realize that I have to talk to the doctor first.
I want to leave the decision to him.
He knows best what is wrong for you and what is right for you.
And I stupid man thought you kept your promise.
But Clara, what am I supposed to do?
Just keep your promise. I don't want any more.
You are very strict and very unfair to me, Clara, do you know that?
I know my promise and I want to keep it.
I want to see Heidi, Dad, please.
What is it?
The Herr Geheimrat wants to speak to you.
Don't worry, child, I'll be done with him.
Hopefully.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Have you already made vacation plans for this summer?
You always travel around this time.
Yes, as usual. But this year I don't know where to go.
Maybe to the North Sea or the Baltic Sea.
I am undecided if I only knew how the weather will be.
Well, I heard up there on the coast there should be a number of very nice
islands.
Yes, that's why I thought about it.
But you're right, it can be very rough up there.
What do you think of Baden-Baden? My mother was there last year.
She says it would be very pleasant.
Yes, in a healing town, to Wiesbaden, for example, that's an idea.
Peace, peace, hot springs.
I think I have reason to thank you, Mr. Sesemann.
Wiesbaden is a pretty town and I don't have to drive far yet.
I knew something else for you.
Yes, you make me curious.
Where are you sending me?
To the Alps.
What? I've been to the Alps every summer for ten years.
It's beautiful there.
Splendid clear air, flowers, cows, goats, but I actually wanted to see something
different.
Hm, if it's so beautiful in the mountains, wouldn't that be something for our
Clara?
For your daughter?
Well, air change wouldn't be bad for her, but whether that's the right thing to
do...
I'm convinced that the fresh air, the peace, the peace, the good milk would be
good for her.
But she can't use her wheelchair.
The roads are steep and narrow and not paved.
Maybe you could solve that problem.
But I'm afraid of the steep slopes.
So that means no.
I don't think your question came without a reason.
Yes, unfortunately. You know...
Oh, let's leave it at that.
Okay.
Yes, that's it, that's it.
What?
Didn't you say you were going to the mountains earlier?
Me?
Yes, me.
It doesn't matter.
The main thing is that you're leaving tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Yes, someone has to check how Heidi is doing.
You want to go on vacation.
You said that yourself.
So what does that mean that you're going to the mountains?
And that's best tomorrow.
I haven't decided yet.
But, Mr. Secret, I don't understand you.
Earlier, you were like a schoolboy from the mountains, and now you're in a
hurry.
Yes, but...
No buts.
I promised Clara that she could visit Heidi.
And you have to keep promises.
But no!
Mr. Zesemann!
Clara?
Papa! Oh, good afternoon.
Good afternoon.
I have a message for you that will make you happy.
We have come up with a solution.
He drives up and watches everything.
But no!
The secret council? No, I have not yet decided on that.
Oh yes, don't worry, he's driving. He will visit Heidi and her grandfather and
see if you can go.
Well, what do you say to that? Nothing yet.
Clara Sesemann, now you disappoint me again. I expected you to be happy and what
do you do? A sad face.
Yes. And if he doesn't like it up there, what then?
You see? Then I'm not allowed to drive, that's what you mean.
But I want to see Heidi.
We've already noticed something.
Clara, please believe me.
I can understand that you're disappointed now, but have patience.
Always patience.
At the moment it's just about finding a proper accommodation for you.
I can't send you to the mountains from today to tomorrow.
We have to meet for preparations.
That's just another excuse.
Excuse me, Mr. Secret Service.
Please find a way, okay?
Take a good look at it.
You have to tell me what it looks like.
I want to know if it really is what Heidi has always described it as.
But before you go, please come here again.
I would like to give you presents.
I know exactly what you all want from Heidi.
Grandfather likes tobacco for the pipe.
All right, pack everything.
I will greet you and give it to you.
Yes, please.
Heidi will be sad that I can't come with you.
Please tell her that I haven't forgotten her.
Explain to her that it's not my fault. I'd like to come.
I'll do that. She'll certainly understand.
She's my girlfriend.
Don't cry.
I'm already curious what you're going to tell her.
I like you better this way, Clara.
You're laughing again.
Herr Geheimrat, packen Sie.
Ja, gut.
Ich werde Fräulein Rottenmeier zu dir schicken, damit ihr gleich die Geschenke
besprechen könnt.
Ja, und sie soll den größten Koffer vom Dachboden holen.
Guten Morgen, hat dir der Postbote heute einen Brief mitgegeben?
Ja!
Endlich, sie hat geschrieben.
Clara wrote me a letter, hopefully a long one.
Morning.
If you say it again, I'm talking nonsense.
I won't say it today, but don't you want your letter?
Is it a long one?
I don't know.
Show it to me, we'll open it.
Oh Peter, I've been waiting for it for so long.
You can probably say that.
Yes, I know.
My dear friend Heidi, thank you very much for the many letters.
How are you? I'm fine. There's something new.
The Herr Geheimrat is coming to you in the mountains.
Clara is coming with the Geheimrat! Grandfather!
Clara is writing that she is coming to visit us with the Geheimrat.
I've already packed all the presents. A warm winter coat for you and a scarf for
Peter's grandmother.
And tobacco for your grandfather.
And because you told me that Peter likes to eat, I've also packed sausages.
That's good.
Oh.
They taste good. They're different from the ones we always eat here.
Yes, do you mean that?
Many, maybe even...
A whole suitcase full!
A suitcase!
But doesn't she give him everything at once, or does he eat them all at once?
That's what it says.
Of course it says that.
Do you think I came up with that?
Don't give him everything at once, or he'll eat them all at once.
That's what it says.
You can check it if you want, but you can't read it.
Of course I can, but not so fast.
I'm so happy to see you again one day, Heidi.
And I finally want to get to know Peter and his grandfather.
Heidi, are you finally satisfied?
You don't know how much.
Klara, Klara, come, Klara has written, she's coming.
Heidi had misunderstood Klara's letter.
Maybe it was because she couldn't even imagine in her dream that Klara would not
come.
That Klara only spoke in her letter from the secret council, to which she wanted
to give gifts.
She had overread that.
Every morning, when Heidi opened her eyes, she hoped that Peter had a new letter
with him, in which Klara would announce her arrival.
But instead of a letter, the secret council came. Peter met him one day when he
went up to the meadow with the goats.
And after he had understood who the stranger was, he brought him to Heidi and
the Almöhi.
Heidi was disappointed. She was angry and distressed that Klara did not come
with her.
With the help of a milk bucket, the secret guard tried to make it clear to her
how dangerous the stay in the mountains would be for a girl in a wheelchair.
But Heidi was not convinced so quickly.
But we want to tell you about this in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back home.