Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark berries
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-
Edi, Holala-Edi
Holala-Edi, Eidi, Eidi, Holala-Edi, Holala- Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-Edi, Holala-
Edi,
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back again
Good morning, Grandfather.
Good morning.
But you wake up early.
Don't you know?
Clara is coming from Frankfurt today.
Clara?
Show me the letter, please.
Sure.
Here.
Read it.
The Secret Service is leaving in a few days to visit you.
You're wrong, Heidi. She only writes about the Secret Service.
But there's something in it. Thank you.
Dear Heidi, no, further down.
I'm really looking forward to seeing you again one day.
I knew she wrote it.
That doesn't say anything.
Yes, how is she supposed to see me again if she doesn't come?
And if Clara writes something like that, she'll come too.
What do you want to know?
Maybe I'll film a video of you and Clara getting married.
No, I can't.
What else do I have to teach you?
You can't just push Klara around like that.
You have to be careful with Klara, do you hear?
How did you start with that?
What? That's what Snooki always did to my skirt when she was as small as you,
little ghost.
Joseph, wake up! I have good news.
We're getting a visitor from Frankfurt, you know, my friend.
Klara is coming! Wake up!
Finally!
Joseph, that's...
That's disgusting!
Josef, did you understand what I said? Clara is coming!
You're not a dog, you're a lazy animal.
Grandfather!
You two probably don't have eyes in your head!
They never do!
Of course, those two.
You're not standing there like...
good morning peter why don't you say anything you're called peter or something
not where do you know my name because heidi described you to me in frankfurt
exactly described the secret that drives me crazy so i didn't even know that
i look so scary that it drives you crazy when you meet me
i said good morning very kindly or not
yes, already
then it's very good, can you take me up to the Alme Oevi you know the way
it's still very far
it tastes good
I hope you enjoyed the video, thank you for watching and see you in the next
video
And I didn't want to come here first.
Stop! Not so fast.
Unfortunately, I can't go slower than the goat herd.
Now I know again why I didn't want to come here.
And where is this Clara?
In Frankfurt, where else?
I went ahead, because before we can send Clara here,
I have to take a closer look at the area.
Then she won't come here.
Why are you so angry? Do you really want her to come here?
What? I can do without it.
But not Heidi.
That's what I thought. In Frankfurt she was homesick for you,
and here she is homesick for Clara.
ARD Text im Auftrag von Funk
Oh, well, city man.
Let me carry the bag.
No, it's okay. It's way too heavy for you.
I'm used to that. Give it to me.
Yes, if that's the case, that would help a little.
This wonderful air up here.
I can understand Heidi, that she did not feel well in our city.
Only this hill, then we are there.
Finally! Peter's whistling! But it's about time!
Peter! Good morning!
What is he carrying on his shoulders? Is that a suitcase?
That can only be Clara's big travel bag.
Peter, where is she?
Where?
Now tell me.
Of course in Frankfurt.
Oh, don't lie. I know the bag.
Mr. Secret Service.
Heidi!
How are you, my child?
Welcome!
How nice that you are here. I'm so happy.
Good day!
Not so stormy.
How do you like the mountains?
Simply overwhelming and beautiful.
But let me greet you first.
Oh, you've grown quite a bit. The mountain air seems to be very good for you.
That pleases me. And burnt brown.
When they are here for a few days, they also look like that.
Yes, maybe. Clara?
Good that you remember me. I should greet you warmly.
I don't understand. What should that mean, greet you warmly?
Do you want to stay down in Durfli?
Heidi, Clara didn't come with me. I drove here alone.
She didn't come with you?
Yes.
Come on, dear.
I'll explain it to you. You know that Clara can't move without her wheelchair.
Yes.
It's bad, but we can't change it.
You have described in your letters how beautiful it is up here,
but you didn't write how she should move in this wheelchair.
I didn't even think about it.
And now they are here to decide whether Clara is allowed to come to us.
I understand that.
Grandfather!
Clara didn't come with us.
Yes, Heidi, I know.
I'm happy to finally get to know you.
Heidi told me a lot about you.
She described everything very precisely.
Welcome and thank you very much for what you have done for Heidi, Mr. Secret
Service.
I didn't know what to thank you for.
For sending Heidi back to me.
Mr. Sesemann wrote it in a letter he gave to Heidi.
Thank you.
Oh no, I had only done what I did best here. The child had a homecoming.
Grandfather, the Herr Geheimrat has come to see if Clara can be sent here.
I see, that's why.
And earlier you said you like it in the mountains, so Clara can come.
What's so strange about that? Did you say it or did you not say it?
Heidi, he has just arrived. He has not seen anything yet, but why don't you show
him your mountains afterwards?
Yes, I will do that and he will like it too. I can tell you that.
In the travel bag are gifts for you from Clara.
She wrote that in the letter, I know.
Then pack it up.
Yes, thank you, we'll do that right away.
Peter, open the bag.
Did she also pack my sausage?
What Clara promises, she keeps it.
What do you think of a big glass of goat's milk?
Fabulous! You can't imagine what kind of thirst I have.
This is the winter coat she wrote.
Why should something like this be good?
This is the warm scarf for your grandmother.
And this is the whistle-trap for my grandfather.
Tell me, what are you looking for?
What? That's what I was looking for.
Such a big sausage.
Peter, there are more!
I think I'm dreaming.
Mine!
No, leave it!
It's mine!
The sausages are for me!
Yes, but she wrote that I shouldn't give them to you right away, so that you
don't eat them all at once.
Please, you say it yourself, they're mine!
Give them already! Don't be a frog!
Do you promise me that you'll give them away at home? If not, I'll send them
back to Frankfurt!
You don't care about that, do you?
Of course I do!
We'll put all the sausages here in the travel bag and you'll take them home with
you.
Goodbye, my sausages.
A lot of frogs!
You know why Clara didn't come?
Clara!
Can't you think of anything other than Clara?
I want to tell you something.
You can keep your sausages.
Don't you want to take me with you today?
You're going with me? And the secret council?
He just comes with us to the meadow.
We have to show him everything very carefully.
Every mountain and all the meadows.
And of course the flowers.
Say yes, he should see how beautiful it is.
He just has to like it here so that Clara can come.
I thought something like that was behind it.
Of course. Don't be like that, Peter. Clara will definitely like it.
Peter, we have to show him all the animals. The marmots and the geese and maybe
an eagle.
I know that Clara will be healthy again. We just have to make it so that she can
come here.
All right. I'll help you.
Peter, what kind of a sweetheart are you?
Ouch!
Just knock the door on my head.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Does it taste good?
A Moor?
A Moor with you!
Peter and I have discovered it!
Come in with you, little girl!
Peter!
Goodbye! See you tomorrow!
We'll bring the presents to you later!
Can I say it to your grandmother already?
No, keep it for yourself!
I'll do it!
Watch out!
She had her first day in the...
Wonderful. But that it was my first day in the mountains, you can't say that
right now.
I've been spending my vacation in the Alps for 20 years.
That's why I was so worried. I know this landscape.
How should I explain it? It's a paradise, but for Clara it's a dangerous one.
Yes, I know.
What does that mean? What does a dangerous paradise mean?
You're eavesdropping.
That was just on purpose, on purpose.
Calm down.
I don't want to.
Do you want to say that Clara is not allowed to come?
I don't know.
You found the day here wonderful.
Why can't it be wonderful for Clara too?
Isn't it about time that you bring Clara's presents downstairs?
If it's too late, you can't go anymore.
Would it do her any good to accompany Heidi
and examine Peter's grandmother at this opportunity?
Of course not.
Well, Heidi, will you take me with you?
I'd love to, but only if you promise me that you'll send Clara.
I promise.
They're supposed to be for us? I don't know how to thank you.
They're not mine, they're Clara's.
Can I try the fat one back there?
Finger away! When will you finally learn how to behave?
What can I do to get hungry?
At least give him a small one, Brigitte. He's been waiting all day.
Heidi, you're great! I'll try how this one tastes.
Well, does it taste good to you?
Yes, and how does it taste?
Ha, ha, ha, ha, you can tell that it tastes good.
Yes, and thank you again.
How can you guess what this is?
A scarf, a tree scarf for the winter.
Oh, how lovely and soft it feels.
This is pure wool, Heidi.
Thank you, Mr. Secret Agent, thank you very much.
I can use the scarf well, it can be very cold up here.
I've never been in the mountains in winter,
but I've heard that they often have meter-high snow.
Yes, yes, the winters are hard.
It's wet and cold, and sometimes you think the sun doesn't want to come at all.
But now I have a warm scarf.
The old woman may be very old, but her health is surprisingly good.
I'm glad you think that, Mr. Heimerath.
If I only knew how to decide.
I am convinced that there is hardly anything better for Clara than the good air.
Look at Heidi and then imagine what she looked like when she came back from
Frankfurt.
Yes, I know, she was pale and slim, she was sick.
I'm just afraid of the steep slopes.
Tell me, I wanted to ask you that earlier.
Do you really believe that Clara will ever be healthy again?
Well, at the moment I can't answer your question with a yes or a no.
What?
Clara would have to do the prescribed walking exercises regularly.
But she's not strong enough.
That's why I'd like to send her.
Star cuddling. If I had a star cuddling, I could wish that Clara would come and
then it would be fulfilled.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Today the view is even better than yesterday
From now on, you have to pick the freshest herbs on the meadow, Swinley.
Your milk must be especially good.
We have to prove to the secret council that it is good for Clara to come here.
Good morning, Haydn.
But you got up early.
Not early enough, I wanted to be the first.
But you were even earlier than me, as you can see.
Ah, fresh goat's milk.
It's still warm, they don't get fresh milk in Frankfurt.
Ah, it smells good.
Yes.
Drink it all!
Delicious! Fresh, healthy milk!
That was very nice of you, thank you!
That's good, yes! That's even very good!
If the milk is as healthy as she said, then she must also be healthy for Clara!
Yes, of course!
Clara could drink as much goat milk as she wants, she can do that, right?
Heidi, now listen!
Why? Why are you making such a face? What is it?
Listen!
We talked about Clara's wheelchair yesterday, didn't we?
Yes, we did.
You have often seen that I have pushed the wheelchair.
Yes, in Frankfurt, on flat earth, on a stone floor or on carpet.
And?
Heidi, that's enough.
You sit with your head through the wall again, that's nonsense.
It's really too dangerous for Clara. I thought about it.
Then I just want to go through the wall with my head.
Believe me, I'll treat Clara with all my heart.
Can't you really understand that you can't drive with a wheelchair up here?
Well then, because what do you think would happen
if your Clara can't hold her wheelchair on your steep meadows anymore?
That? Yes.
Did you see it?
Wheelchair, wheelchair, you're always talking about this stupid wheelchair.
None of you think of Clara.
It's about Clara.
Clara wouldn't be alone.
Grandfather, Peter and I are here.
We would all be careful.
If we all help together, we can do it, right?
But the secret ride is against it.
No, no, no, he can't do that.
That can't be.
I want Clara to come visit me and she wants it too.
Our wooden cube.
Broke up.
Heidi, come in, we're having breakfast.
What does it matter if she can't sit in the wheelchair?
Clara hates her wheelchair. What does it matter to her?
Can she go wherever she wants with it?
You don't care about what Clara thinks.
You don't care if Clara is sad.
It's definitely possible without this wheelchair.
And even better than with it.
Please, grandfather, please!
Why shouldn't Clara sit in the grass on the meadow?
She would like that.
I know that. And she doesn't roll down the slope.
But you don't want to let anything else come to mind.
Clara would be happy here. She told me.
Heidi.
What the child says is right.
We actually only thought about Clara's wheelchair all the time.
I can carry her lightly and she can sit on the ground just as well.
Wait a minute.
Because I ... well, that could have been the problem the whole time.
Clara has relied too much on her wheelchair.
That is possible.
We didn't make it clear to her once that it could go without this thing.
Maybe she'll try to move when she's not sitting in this chair.
Exactly.
It's worth a try at least.
Yes.
One should ...
I'll give it a try.
I have to thank you.
So?
We'll do it.
Why not? I don't know what I was against at all.
Is that a promise or not?
It is a promise.
I promise you that she will come.
And you promise me that you will take good care of her
and that you won't let her out of your sight.
There you can see what kind of an old donkey I am.
A dear donkey.
Clara, come on.
That she can be so overbearing, I would never have thought that in Frankfurt.
Here she is always like that.
I have to tell him that right away.
I have to tell him.
Hurry up, Peter. I have news for you.
For Heidi, the world was back in order.
Finally, she would be able to show Clara all that she had always told her.
The mountains, the ponds, the meadows.
And, of course, Peter and the goat herd.
Day after day, Heidi waited, after the secret council had left, impatiently for
a sign of life from Clara.
She kept describing to Peter and his grandfather how Clara looked like.
And then one day came the long-awaited letter from Frankfurt.
Heidi was out of joy.
And although she knew exactly that the secret council would keep its promise,
she could no longer grasp it at once.
However, one thing Clara had not written.
She had not dared, out of fear that Heidi might be disappointed or would even
give up.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back home.