This is a work of fiction. Any resemblance to anyone, living or dead, is
coincidental and unintentional.
It is a work of fiction. Any resemblance to anyone, living or dead, is
Up here you are at home. Dark pebbles, green meadows in the sunshine. Heidi,
Heidi, you need to be happy.
Halala Edie, Halala Edie, Halala Edie, Halala Edie, Halala Edie, Halala Edie,
Halala Edie, Halala Edie, Halala Edie.
Halala Edie.
Heidi, Heidi, come home. Find your happiness. Come back again.
Where should she sleep?
Can we make her bed out of hay, like mine, under the roof?
Peter is whistling, I have to talk to him.
Svenli, Merli, Peter is coming!
Good morning, little ghost.
Peter, did you bring a letter?
Oh dear, it's starting again.
Tell me, do you have one with you today?
I want to tell you something.
You're asking me holes in my stomach.
Heidi, Peter will tell you when he has a letter with him.
He knows you're waiting.
Besides, it's impossible that Clara's letter comes so quickly.
Here, Peter, your breakfast.
Thank you.
Heidi, now forget about this letter for one day.
If you sit around here and wait, that's why it doesn't come earlier.
Yes, but it takes so long.
Goodbye!
To be continued
What? I'm really allowed to drive, Mr. Secret Wheel?
Yes, and I'm happy about it.
I wouldn't have known how to teach you the opposite.
When do I drive?
As fast as possible.
I mean, of course, as soon as a train leaves and as soon as you've packed.
Oh, thank you very, very much, Mr. Secret Wheel.
If you want to thank me, thank Heidi.
She beat me. She spoke like a waterfall.
And Ms. Rottenmeier had to thank you.
She was willing to explain herself to accompany you.
Oh, Mrs. Rottenmeier is driving too?
Yes, of course. I can't let you drive alone.
But I'm betting on it, Mrs. Clara, that you know that I'm against the trip.
Who knows what else is coming our way?
I accompany you because I feel responsible and I hope you behave accordingly.
Yes.
I would like to ask you to show obedience there as well.
Would you excuse me, please? I have to pack.
Of course, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Thank you very much.
Does that really have to be the case?
Including Mr. Rottenmeier?
She always spoils everything.
Oh, Clara.
Now, don't be unfair.
She's strict with you, I know that.
But I also know that I can rely on her in any case.
Yes.
She's too careful, of course.
But that's because she's afraid of you.
She doesn't mean it badly.
Believe me, it's the best thing for you, Clara.
Possible. I'm already quiet.
Maybe it's a good thing that she's coming with us.
Maybe she'll understand why Heidi didn't feel comfortable with us.
You think so?
Just for that reason, it was worth it to send Mrs. Rottenmeier to the mountains.
Maybe she even likes it here.
I'm even sure that she likes it.
Even Mrs. Rottenmeier has earned a vacation once.
Will you come visit us, Dad?
Yes, and I'll write to Grandmother if she also wants to come with us.
Let's surprise Heidi with it, okay?
Clara!
Yes, what is it?
I want to discuss a few things with you.
But first tell me, why are you so happy? You don't even know the mountains.
Of course I'm looking forward to Heidi.
That's what I thought. But I'm not just letting you drive so you can see Heidi.
I want you to know that.
Will you promise me something, Clara?
Uh-huh.
It was always very comfortable for you here in Frankfurt. Sebastian is there for
you. And the wheelchair.
You've never had to try running. You've never even wanted to.
Of course I've always wanted to.
Yes, a little.
You can never have really wanted to, Clara, because you've never tried.
And that's exactly what you're supposed to promise me.
I'd like you to try standing on your own two legs.
If you really want to, Clara, you'll be able to one day.
The next few weeks you'll spend up there in the mountains
won't be just a pleasure for you, you know?
You'll only be able to use your wheelchair in the vicinity of the hut,
otherwise it would be too dangerous.
I know, yes.
You only believe to know how it is up there.
You only know what Heidi told you.
Yes.
There are no roads and streets like here in Frankfurt.
There are steep slopes and deep sluices.
It's very uncomfortable for you up there.
Why? Why do they allow it?
Don't worry, I've thought about it very carefully, if it's right to agree, but I
have a hope for this trip.
You believe Clara?
Yes, don't be afraid to say it. I still believe that Clara can walk one day, if
she finally wants to.
For the first time in your life, it will be a bit difficult for you, Clara.
Maybe it will help you.
You think I'm just lazy.
So similar. Lazy is not the right word. I believe that you just don't trust it.
Then they mean it seriously. Is there still hope?
Yes.
I've always wanted to. I really can't do it.
You see, my child, that's what I meant. Do you understand me now?
That's exactly what it is. You admit that you can't do it and that's why you
don't even try.
I will try. I promise it to him, for sure.
Good.
You couldn't make a greater joy out of your father and me.
You know, a promise is a promise.
And it's not broken. You two taught me that.
Prove that it's true.
Yes, of course.
MUSIC
Heidi, he's here! He has arrived!
Is he Clara's?
Of course! Who else could it be?
Finally!
All three at once!
All three at once, you're good.
There's only one of them.
That's Clara's.
Give it to me! I'll bring the others to the Alps!
Yes!
Dear Heidi...
I'm so happy the secret guard said I can come.
Imagine I can come.
Hooray!
Clara is coming. The secret guard kept his promise.
Grandfather, she's coming. We have to prepare everything.
I'm so happy for you, child.
Who screamed at you?
Mr. Sesemann and the secret council.
Listen, Clara writes, she's lucky because she's allowed to come.
But she's also coming?
That can't be true.
Mrs. Rottenmeier is also coming.
Did you think Clara could travel all by herself?
Maybe I misread myself?
How terrible! How horrible!
What?
Unfortunately, I didn't read myself.
We'll be done with you somehow.
With Mr. Rottenmeier, no one gets done so quickly.
But Heidi, you make a face as if a ghost had just passed you by.
You have no idea.
Clara, Clara, Clara!
Yeah, well, I'm glad she's finally coming.
Well, if you think so, but is that all that's in the letter?
Isn't there something for me in there too?
Why, for you?
Dossi writes something, nice greetings to Peter.
No more?
Did you thank him too?
But it's weird.
Why didn't she write anything about new sausages if you said how good they
tasted?
Or is there something in there?
No, she doesn't write anything about sausages.
Ed!
Too bad.
You're an old fart.
Can you always think about food?
Can you do me a favor?
But of course.
Good.
Heidi and I want to go down to Dörfli.
Will you lock the goats in the stable tonight?
I'd love to.
Clara will see the moon and the stars for the first time.
Heidi, let's go to Dörfli.
Why?
I want to see if I can build a house
where we lived last winter.
Why don't we live here?
Why don't we all live here together?
You know Mrs. Rottenmeier will come with us.
Wonderful! She can stay alone in the village.
But she won't want that.
How do you want to do your work there?
I come here every day.
That's way too hard.
But Heidi, it doesn't matter to me.
You will help me somehow.
Grandmother!
It's him!
Finally, so far!
So?
Yes, what?
I have wonderful new news for us.
And what are these wonderful new news for us?
You can guess three times.
What can that be?
Just let me think.
Since there are so good news, it can only be one thing you mean.
Your friend Clara from Frankfurt is coming to visit us.
Yes, imagine Clara is coming.
Are you looking forward to it?
Yes.
Oh, yes. Aren't you happy at all?
Yes, yes. But I'm afraid.
You know, Heidi, I'm afraid that these strangers from Frankfurt will think of
taking you away from us again.
You don't seriously think that someone will manage to get me out of here again?
Oh, if that were true, Heidi.
Certainly.
I'm never leaving, but you know what? I'm going to bring Clara. She can read you
something.
That's good. Can she read as beautifully as you?
Clara can read a thousand times better than I can.
Have fun with your friend, Heidi.
Goodbye! I'll be back as soon as I can!
Do you remember? In this abandoned house the Almöhi and Heidi spent the last
winter.
Here they lived for many months with their goats while it was snowing outside
and cold.
Heidi loved this house and she wanted it to look as beautiful as possible for
Clara.
Every day she climbed up to the hut with her grandfather to do the daily work.
And although she was sometimes very tired, she never sat still.
Every day she asked Peter for a letter from Clara, because she knew that Clara
and Mrs. Rottenmeier were already very close.
Clara was supposed to get used to the new climate in a spa.
And then the letter came. Peter brought it to her.
Tomorrow they will finally come.
To be continued ...
Oh boy, there's a car coming!
Hey, look over there!
There's a car coming!
Yes!
Grandfather, I think they're coming!
Quick, come with me outside!
I'll run towards them! Hurry up, Grandfather!
Oh, there you are!
Clara!
Who's in there?
Come on!
We'll be right there!
Go back through the window!
Otherwise they'll catch us!
Yes!
I can hear them!
Clara!
Isn't that Heidi's voice?
Heidi!
Stop!
What did you say?
Clara!
Finally!
Did you have as much fun as I did today?
You don't know how much I waited.
It took so long.
Come in.
Sebastian!
Have a nice day, Miss.
I don't think I heard you right.
He said Miss.
Come into the carriage and show us how to drive.
Of course.
I greet you, nobility.
Thank you.
Good day, Miss Rottenmeier.
Something like that is ridiculous.
It's not ridiculous at all. That's what they do in the city.
I'm so happy.
Me too.
Look at this!
We're here! Grandfather!
You can get out. We're here, Miss Rottenmeier.
Is there a house outside the ruin?
Sorry, there are only apple trees and what you call a ruin.
I don't like jokes.
I don't dare to joke.
You have to tell us if Heidi lives here.
If we want.
This is the winter house.
Winter house?
Yes, they only live here in winter.
Hopefully I was just dreaming.
Sebastian! Why isn't anyone helping me get out of the carriage?
Excuse me, I'm coming.
Not even curtains yet.
Clara, this is the grandfather.
Grandfather, and this is Clara.
Heidi told me a lot about you.
Nice that you came.
I'm so happy about it.
I don't even know what to say.
Thank you very much for letting me come here.
You're welcome.
I hope with all my heart that you will like it here with us.
We've been waiting for you for a long time.
I'm sure I'll like it.
Have a nice day.
My name is Rottenmeier.
Aha, Mrs. Rottenmeier. Welcome. I hope you'll enjoy your holidays, too.
What will happen in the next few days?
Do you want me to show you the house?
Of course I want to!
Let's go! You've always said that in Frankfurt.
What kind of trees are these?
Apple trees. What else?
You'll have to see them in spring. When they bloom, everything is white and pink
here.
Tell them you were scared when I came here for the first time and saw the house,
too.
No.
It's just...
This is the stable.
Is Geißlein in there? Can I see him?
Not today. The goats are all up on the hill.
That's a shame. Can I see them tomorrow?
Yes, I think so.
Why don't you know exactly?
Because they stay at our hut all summer. We only bring them here in winter.
And where is Josef?
Up there, too.
Oh, then I can't see anyone. And now just say Peter isn't here either.
Of course he isn't here either, but he'll be here tonight for sure.
That's nice.
Come on, Clara, I'll show you what it looks like from the inside.
This is our...
You can't see that in the house from the outside.
Oh, huge.
The oven is beautiful.
I really like it in here.
Much better than from the outside.
I already thought that.
Tell me, what is that over there for a strange box?
This is not a strange box, this is my bed, where I sleep.
And that's your bed?
Yes, but I didn't take it away from you, it's not yours otherwise.
No.
I always sleep in that box.
The grandfather made the bed for you.
He did that for me?
Oh, I can only hope that this is the goat stable and not the guest house.
It goes along here.
Alm Oehi, one moment.
Excuse me for asking, but isn't there a guest house in the village?
Coincidentally, no.
Are there at least servants?
I mean clean and willing people who can do something for me.
I don't care if it's male or female.
The people here in the mountains work hard from early to late to earn a living.
I don't think I'll find anyone.
But I'm ready to pay particularly well for it.
How generous. Offer it. Maybe someone will come.
I didn't want to hurt you, but someone has to prepare the meals for us.
I'll do that, as always. And Heidi will help me with that.
Mrs. Rottenmeier, the more you get used to doing one or the other yourself, the
better.
Do you work for all the time, Sebastian?
Unfortunately, no.
Over there you can see the mountains best.
Have you ever lived in a house without a roof, Sebastian?
No.
I still can't believe it all.
Our grandfather and I live up there.
There is our hut and there are also our goats.
All the way up there on the top of the mountain?
Oh, what? Not all the way up, about half up.
Does Peter live that far up too?
Not quite that far.
Sebastian, let's go up right away. I want to look at it.
Please say yes. The sun goes down up there.
That's good here too.
Grandfather, Clara wants us to go up to the hut today.
What do you mean? That's not a question at all.
What's the point of this nonsense, Mrs. Clara? It gets dark at any moment.
That's far too dangerous.
No, we want to spend the night in Heidi's hut.
It's not dangerous. We just want to look at the stars through the roof.
Adelheid, please don't get involved in this.
I won't allow you to stomp around in the mountains with them in the middle of
the night.
Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Clara, we'll get up early in the morning to the hut.
The mountains are much nicer in the morning.
You'll be able to see the stars from up close, too.
But you won't be able to see anything from the mountains when it gets dark.
Yes, that's good. I'll wait until tomorrow.
We can go up there with the goats tomorrow morning.
I'm going to take care of dinner now.
It's not all that much I can do, but I do hope that everyone will like it.
Heidi, please be so kind as to show Mrs. Rottenmeier her room.
Yes, all right. Come on, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
There's nothing else left for me.
Grandfather can cook well. Hopefully you're hungry.
Yes, of course.
Man, what is it? Did you hurt yourself?
There's a bear out there. I knew there was something like this here.
Here I am!
Why don't you come in?
What was that?
Don't stand there like that!
Why did they scream like that?
Don't be a coward, Peter!
I don't want to come in!
Leave me alone!
That's Clara!
Hello, how are you, Peter?
I don't know.
Clara?
Peter wants to know if you brought him sausages.
That's not true at all.
I did.
What a shame.
Well, Peter.
Don't believe him, Clara.
Now he's ashamed, of course.
But Peter can eat all day.
That's not true.
Well, how good that I thought about it and brought some.
Thank you.
Well, you see, Peter.
Stop it, Heidi.
What should she think of me?
Ah!
Oh, no, no!
I've never tasted anything as good as today!
Good night, Peter! Get us off with the goats tomorrow, but don't oversleep!
Good night, Heidi!
Sleep well! See you tomorrow!
Come on, it's time to go in. You'll get cold otherwise.
Good, let's go to sleep.
Good!
The next morning, the two children got up very early and for the first time
Clara could see the hut that Heidi had told her so much about in Frankfurt.
She got to know Bärli and Schwänli and the many little funny chicks.
She was afraid of the big fat Joseph at first, but Peter and Heidi helped her
overcome the fear quickly.
Clara's first day up in the mountains was like a dream for her.
She wished that all of this would never stop.
Peter had even come up with something very special to welcome her.
But we want to tell you about it and whether it was really something special in
our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.
Bärli and Schwänli