Heide
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Heide
Heide wake up
Good morning, Clara. Aren't we going to the cabin this morning?
Yes. Can we get up now?
Yes.
It's not even bright yet.
Yes, I know, but I don't want to be late.
After all, we still have to wash and get dressed.
I say it's a mess.
Heidi, what's wrong with me?
Why?
You know, Heidi.
The wheelchair.
You just have to push him closer to my bed.
Oh yes, good.
Can you hold him for a moment?
Yes, will it work?
Clara!
What is it, Clara?
Say something!
Please ask Mrs. Rottenmeier if she can help me.
What?
How strange.
Yes, tell me, what are you doing here?
Good morning. Oh, the milk is burning.
Why are you cooking in our kitchen?
I wonder too. As if I didn't have enough to do at home. But I'm supposed to help
here.
Did Mrs. Rottenmeier go to you all by herself and asked?
Yes.
That's what she has. She's not really that friendly, I have to say.
Imagine, yesterday she suddenly stood up without knocking in the middle of the
living room.
She hasn't even apologized yet, but she says she would pay well.
And where is she? Has she already stood up or not?
Yes, for a long time. She's running around outside and putting her nose in
everywhere.
Well, then you have to help Clara. She's still lying in our room in bed.
Oh, her name is Clara. Very pretty.
Heidi, who are you talking to? You'll see in a minute.
Well, I thought so.
Peter has to come too.
Hopefully he won't forget it.
Are you coming for breakfast?
Yes, hopefully. Would you like some warm milk?
Don't bring Mrs. Rottenmeier with you for breakfast.
He's standing there. Peter!
Huh? Yes?
Good morning, Peter.
Good morning, Miss Clara.
You don't have to say Miss.
But I thought you do that in the city.
They all talk so strangely there.
Oh, what, Peter?
Someone tied a bear to you.
Can I say Clara?
Yes, of course.
I'll wait at the fountain for you until you have breakfast.
Until then, goodbye.
That can only be Joseph.
Yes, say Joseph.
You can't even see where you're going.
Joseflein, good morning.
That's my little dear Joseph.
What? Little? He's everything but little.
Doesn't he know?
He doesn't even know how to do it.
Well, I don't know.
Come, Joseph.
Well, come.
I'm so happy to get to know you.
I've never seen such a big dog.
You're already dressed. That's good.
Did you sleep well, Grandfather?
Good morning.
Well, what did you dream of tonight, my child?
I don't know. I don't think anything.
Then remember what you're dreaming of tonight.
You're babbling. It's only possible to fulfill what you dreamed of the first
night.
Not exactly.
Good morning, Mr. Oehi.
Good morning.
I have good news. I have solved the problem.
I have asked the villagers.
And the men are ready to declare to carry Clara.
Who is carrying whom?
Two farmers. They are carrying Clara.
Good morning.
They seem to want to carry you.
It looks like it.
What are you waiting for, gentlemen? What are you waiting for?
Yes, well.
We should have breakfast, children.
Adelheid, you too, please.
Did you see her face?
Yes.
Will you come for dinner?
Peter, why are you sitting there? Come on, bring the goats up, it's about time.
There!
Where?
What's that supposed to be?
Good morning, Helene.
Good morning.
I feel like the princess in Aladdin and the Wonderlamp.
Peter, it's about time.
Heidi, is the ghost with you?
I'm sorry, please.
Don't worry, I was happy to wait.
It's okay.
Well, good morning, Snuggie.
Good morning, little Snuggie.
You know her?
Yes, I know her. There's Snuggie's daughter.
And that's Snuggie.
May I pet her too?
Of course.
Here.
How cute.
Baa! Baa!
Stay! She won't hurt you.
He's afraid of you, but it will be at some point.
I see.
You know, I can pet your little ghost after that.
Tell me, how do you know the little ghost?
You would like to know that.
Over there, that's the old one.
And the little colorful one has to be a child of the colorful one.
That's right.
How did she know that?
I don't understand why you're so surprised.
You just know it that way.
But Peter, that's quite easy. Heidi would have always written me all this.
Oh, that's why. I thought you were magic.
Goat general.
It's getting too late for us. Drive the goats. We still want to have something
from that day.
What am I doing? Everywhere is wiggling of animals where you look.
Sorry, too late, but finally yes.
What a nightmare.
Why, this is your horse, and that's what you wanted to have after all.
Yes, excuse me.
I thought of a very small one.
What are you doing?
Oh, nice!
See you next time!
The one you told me about looks exactly the same?
Yes, exactly the same. Maybe he's even there.
There comes Tito's goat, look!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
I think it's a pretty girl.
It's beautiful. Can we stop for a moment?
There, Clara, the Alps.
How wonderful. It is much more beautiful than you described.
Thank you, Heidi. I'm so happy.
Clara, you don't have to thank me.
Clara, look over there. That's our hut.
I didn't think it would be so beautiful.
I'm running!
Peter, wait!
Wait, I'll get Swandy and the other two.
And these must be the geese that Heidi says they can talk to.
Come on, little ghost, Clara is there.
But she's cute. Little ghost, run, little ghost!
Here, little ghost, come on, jump!
Where is she going now?
But little ghost...
She's really cute.
Snuggie 2 is coming too.
They're both the same, aren't they?
I think so too.
If you also want to come with us to our pasture, we have to slowly make our way.
What kind of pasture?
Tell me, our pasture, what else?
Oh, you know, Peter.
Does that mean you stay here and don't go on?
Mrs. Rottenmeier, please don't send her away. I want to go on.
Oh, what? It doesn't look different up there either. It was hard enough to get
here.
You have to be able to be satisfied with something.
I thank you, gentlemen. Please come back on time tonight.
We will. Until tonight, Almöhi.
Up, come on.
So, they're leaving.
I thought so. Did you forget me again?
Just because your girlfriend is here.
But Peter, what's going on with you all of a sudden?
How should I know?
Stop it!
I'm angry! That's with me!
No! No!
Come on, didn't you hear him? He's whistling.
Sometimes you have to be strict with them.
Mrs. Clara, I'm sorry, but you have to rest.
Why?
Mrs. Rottenmeier was right. I'll help you.
Oh, Meier.
Oh, that's more comfortable.
Thank you very much, Ayme. Thank you.
To be continued
I still can't believe it. It's so beautiful and how blue the sky is.
Soft white clouds
And the wind is blowing
Yes, you're right, the sparrows are talking
Wait, I'll get you to them
Adelheid, leave your wheelchair!
No, I can do it
Let's go!
Adelheid, watch out!
Adelheid!
Don't worry, it's not dangerous here. Nothing can happen here.
That's what they say.
You should hear how they roar when the autumn storms are here.
I can imagine it.
Sometimes they just whisper, but...
But when the wind is strong, they scream and in the winter the animals hide
among them and seek protection.
I also want to experience all of that.
They are really huge. Do you know how old they are already, Heidi?
No, they were already there when Grandfather came.
I can tell you everything. They understand everything.
I can tell you everything.
I had to get so old to experience that.
No one knows what can happen here.
Dangerous sources everywhere.
She will have to get used to it.
Here you can...
Food? Nobody came up with that idea at home.
I hope you're hungry. I've made a lot of food and I have to eat it.
Oh yes, I'm hungry. I've never had as much hunger in my life as I have today.
It'll take another minute.
Are you calling us?
Don't be afraid, it won't happen.
We're going to crash!
Phew!
Watch out, she's falling over.
Somehow you have to be more careful about her than about me.
Why aren't you coming? The food is ready.
Finally! I didn't think you'd be here any longer!
Another one!
Oh, I don't recognize you at all, Mrs. Clara. In Frankfurt, you eat like a
sport.
I don't like it that much either. No one has ever given me such delicious cheese
bread.
That only makes the fresh air. Eat slowly, my child, so that you get red cheeks.
Here, Clara. Thank you.
You haven't had a single sip yet.
What? Yes, I don't like it at the moment. I'll drink my milk later.
If you let her stand too long, she won't be fresh anymore and won't taste so
good anymore.
To be continued
Hey Heidi, will you show me your hut after dinner?
Oh, what a huge pot!
That's what the grandfather and I always make the cheese together.
Aha! Is that the ladder back there that you always have to climb up?
Yes, exactly!
Aha! I would like to see it so much!
Then you will see it too.
This is my bed, Clara.
How good it smells. Is that the hay that smells so good?
Yes.
Oh, you can see the sun shining.
Not only that, in the evening you can also see the moon and the stars.
If there are no clouds.
Of course, you smartass. I would like to sleep here too.
I would love to stay up here in the hut right away.
Oh yes, we stay up here. We won't go down again.
It would be nice.
That's not allowed in Rottenmeier.
Why not? Just ask her.
We can take care of you up here as well as we can take care of you down here.
Do it!
But you have to ask her if you want to. I'm sure she won't allow it.
She'll definitely start screaming.
It's not even a question.
And why not?
Why, why, why? It's too dangerous.
I admit that the murmel animals up here can live quite well, but certainly not
humans.
Grandfather and I are also humans and we live quite well here.
Yes, of course, but that's something completely different.
That's nothing at all.
Oh, yes.
I can understand that you are worried about Clara.
It is unusual for you here.
But please don't forget that Heidi and I know each other up here.
We can take care of Clara.
No, I don't think you can.
Clara is not comparable to Heidi.
Where do you actually take the right of Mr. Rottenmeier
to want to know better than the secret?
After all, he was the one who sent Clara here.
He came to see everything here, isn't that right, Mrs. Rottenmeier, or did I get
it wrong?
No, the secret guard sent me here on purpose because he liked it so much.
Yes, he did.
Oh, I don't know where my head is anymore, maybe it's good here for you, maybe
not, but I can't live here.
I can't stand it, there are abysses everywhere.
But Mrs. Rottenmeier...
Yes, it's all right, I'm sorry, I've been caught again.
You can live in the village if you don't like it up here.
And how do you imagine that I will take care of you?
You can come up every day and look at the right.
That's impossible.
There they come.
Ah yes, we're being picked up. Now please be reasonable again and come down with
me.
I stay, I don't go with you.
Please?
You are disobedient?
Yes.
Good.
As you wish. But I'll make you responsible if something happens to the child.
You can stay, Clara.
That's nice, isn't it?
I will come every morning and see if you are doing well.
Please take your breakfast on time at 7 o'clock.
And don't forget your studies.
Unfortunately, I have to make up your decision.
Live well.
I've never had such a big neck in my whole life.
Goodbye, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Goodbye.
Don't forget that you have to pick up your studies from today.
Is Peter coming?
Yes.
Let's go!
Hello, Peter!
I brought something for you.
Thank you.
How nice of you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, Peter.
You are wonderful, beautiful.
Yes, Schnucki, good evening, pretty little ghost.
No, that's not true. That's Schnucki and that's little ghost.
Heidi und Klara hatten an diesem Abend noch lange miteinander getuschelt und
gekichert.
Sie hatten sich so unendlich viel zu erzählen, aber dann fielen ihnen
schließlich doch vor
Übermüdung die Augen zu und sie träumten von all dem schönen, das sie noch
zusammen erleben würden.
The next day they both stood up in the sun.
Clara could not find herself at all at the first moment.
But then, when she looked out the window and saw the flowers,
the mountains shining in the sunlight, she knew again where she was.
Everything could have been beautiful,
if not for a reason for complaining by Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Heidi, however, did not let her good mood be spoiled.
Together with Peter, she thought of a new surprise for Clara every day.
But we want to tell you about it in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world is the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness.
Come back home.