Holadio
Heidi, your world are the mountains
Heidi, Heidi
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs, green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Hollywood
Have you been awake?
Yes, for hours.
Do you like it?
Oh yes!
Look at that!
That's wonderful.
Nanou?
What?
Good morning, Joseph!
What is he looking for?
No idea.
Maybe a snail.
A snail?
He's eating something disgusting.
Do all dogs do that?
I don't know.
A terrifying thought.
Yes, but you get used to it.
Does snails taste good?
Joseph! How do snails taste?
Tell me, have you ever tried one before?
No, really not.
I'll get the grandfather.
Joseph!
Are you really looking for snails?
The grandfather is coming!
Yes, good!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
What was he looking for?
I'd like to know that too, Joseph.
Something like that.
And then a deep hole.
You know what? I think he had no reason at all.
Dogs sometimes do such strange things.
Possible.
Oh, let him be.
Look, they're bathing too.
Now I know what you meant when you wanted to let Hansi fly.
I forgot the towel in the bucket.
I'll be right back!
Here's a towel for you.
Thanks.
Here you go.
Nice, icy cold water.
But where do you wash yourself in winter when it's cold outside?
In there, and then Grandfather Snow dives into a bowl.
I'd like to be here in winter too.
Yes, then come in winter.
Yes.
It's best if I don't leave now.
We should also have a well with cold water at home.
There, come on. Do you want to come here?
Come to me!
Oh, that's exactly what Peep Mats looked like.
Do you know how many birds are in the tub?
No, I have no idea. Maybe a thousand or more.
Too many?
Oh, what a shame.
Look over there.
I can't see anything.
It's too late. I think it was a hare.
I think it was a hare.
Listen to how they scream
Ah, now they have come, they are thirsty
Ssshht
Why can't she ride?
I won't take her with me.
I don't think so.
Peter, wait!
Yes, why?
Be so kind and take me with you.
You know the way.
I want to go up to the hut.
Yes, gladly.
Drink it. It's better than any medicine.
The milk is fresh. He milked it last night.
Hopefully that's not all.
I won. I was faster.
Oh, Peter, be so kind and wait. I can't do it as fast as you can.
I can only do it as fast and slowly as my herd can.
Then tell your herd to run slower.
Unfortunately, that's not possible.
So, is it possible now?
Now it works!
Please, go away!
If you don't want it or you can't, then give the money back!
It's not that steep! Give me the bag already!
I don't want to steal it, I want to wear it!
We're done!
No more cheese bread?
At best I don't want to!
Can we go out and play?
Yes, of course! Can we get up from the table?
Of course! But promise me that you don't go near the slope!
Yes, I promise!
What a tramp!
Wait!
Auntie, did you do something to yourself?
Do you know me? I would like to ask you for reliable advice to leave this kind
in the future.
Oh, you wear these strange shoes from the city.
What's with it?
With it you will break your neck.
I asked you before not to address me so trustfully.
Why? We've known each other for two days. Better walk barefoot.
Do you think I should walk without shoes?
You're not going with us, are you?
I don't care.
Peter, you can't leave me here alone!
No, I can't!
How did I deserve that?
And who tells me that they don't bite after all?
Make sure you get out of here, asshole!
Can you give me some old...
What are you doing here? You have to be at the top of the meadow.
I'm sorry, it can't change.
May I have that?
Please? What do you want with it?
I want to give it to her. I'm sorry.
Who do you want to give it to?
Fräulein Rottenmeier!
What are you looking for?
Go to the others!
Peter! Peter!
What?
Oh, this monster! Get me out of here! It wants to bite me!
Oh, come on!
They are a bit too small and the color doesn't match my dress, but at least
better than barefoot.
You can't say thank you.
That's funny, what is that?
Just a grasshopper.
Aha.
And that there?
Come.
Look!
A marine beetle, yes?
Yes.
And now?
Yes, fly!
I think something happened.
What?
Peter should be here by now.
Yes?
I don't understand.
Yes! He's here!
It's really time!
Peter! Where are you staying so long?
Why are you asking me? Ask your aunt from Frankfurt!
What aunt?
Well, which ones?
My Rottenmeier.
Have you already met her this morning?
Yes, unfortunately I have that.
Yes, and?
If I run one step in these narrow things, I will die.
Not so bad, but it's good that no one sees it.
Mrs. Clara!
For God's sake, you can't do that!
What?
Oh, I got it!
I almost let you out of my sight, something is happening.
You can't possibly sit on the wet ground.
But it's not wet at all.
You can't judge that.
Grass is always wet, otherwise it wouldn't be green.
No.
Yes! Oh, sorry.
Mom, you have holes in your socks.
Yes, I have holes.
But still better than these screws.
Don't worry about my feet.
Thank you, Peter, but they're way too small for me.
Too bad.
Yes, unfortunately, I have way too big feet for a lady.
Yes, uh...
I have to have a serious word with you.
Why? What did I do wrong?
Don't say anything. I'll get the grandfather.
No, that's not necessary. Stay here. I don't need any help.
I'm way too heavy for you.
We'll see about that.
Watch out! They're going to drop you!
Thank you, Peter. You seem to be very hostile.
I've never seen anything like that.
I just don't know why she's always so upset.
Oh, forget it. Will you do me a favor?
Can you bring Swinley and Bearley to the place where the fresh, good herbs grow?
You know, I mean the ones we raised Snooki with back then.
I want the two of them to give particularly good milk.
I understand. You're not going with us today either.
So.
Am i so heavy? Good morning.
What do you mean? Good morning.
Why didn't you rent the horse this morning?
I can tell you that, Alm Oehi.
Yesterday evening I had a floe on my bedside.
We live here now in the country.
I have to talk to you.
If you take Mrs. Clara out of the chair next time,
then don't sit her directly on the floor.
Take a blanket or something.
I don't want her to cool down.
Of course.
How did you like to sit on the grass?
Oh, that was really beautiful.
I saw butterflies and grasshoppers and even a sea leopard.
Are those insects?
Oh yes, of course.
Warmth.
Insects can transmit diseases.
You think? Did you read that somewhere?
What?
Clara doesn't need a blanket. It's summer and it's warm. She doesn't get cold.
Shamelessness.
Can I rely on you?
Yes!
Clara, do you know what?
No, what?
Now the milk is getting better.
Why?
How long have you been living up here?
Oh, so long that I don't even know how many years.
Oh, nice. Really nice.
It's so quiet here.
I wish I could live here too.
Mrs. Clara, it's time for your studies.
Please, no.
Do I have to study in the holidays?
They promised in Frankfurt that they would keep their schedule.
Clara is currently learning.
What do you mean?
In my opinion, she's starting to make holes in the air.
She's seeing how someone makes cheese.
That's what I would call learning, for example.
I've never seen that before.
Well, if Clara is interested in it...
I'm going to do it outside, by the way.
I just can't stand the smell of it.
Excuse me.
Oh, oh, oh!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
Can you drink the water?
Try it. It tastes good.
It tastes awful. You're mean.
She fell in.
She's sleeping.
But don't wake her up.
We want to eat lunch first, then I'll start right away.
We slept for a long time.
I got you!
Heidi, I moved all by myself and got a flower!
I even slipped a big piece. The flower was far away.
Did it hurt?
Not at all. It was just very heavy.
I picked the same as you.
That's right, yes.
You know what? We'll pick more and then we'll make a wreath out of it.
A big one for you and a small one for me.
No, two equal sizes.
No, I know something better.
I know a place where there are much more beautiful flowers.
There are red and blue and yellow.
Shall we go there?
Oh, I could go there.
...picking up a huge straw...
...that must be a lot of fun.
I want to go to the top.
Miss Clara!
Now it's finally time.
Please not today.
Miss Clara, you have to keep your promises.
And you have given one in Frankfurt.
I'm tired.
Then let's have a nap.
I'll lie down too, okay?
To be continued...
Clara?
They're all not used to the air.
It's so beautiful here.
Clara should see all of this.
10, 11, 12...
Twelve. Thirteen.
Tell me, have you run away again?
Come to the others!
Peti?
Heidi, what are you doing here?
I think you're with Clara.
I'm planting flowers.
Clara wants a wreath.
I see.
And where is she?
She fell asleep.
In Frankfurt she always makes a nap, you know.
What?
You can't tell me that.
She's so big and she's still sleeping at noon.
She's at least two years older than us and is being treated like a baby.
Why are you so mean?
You keep nagging.
I'm not nagging and I'm not mean.
If you want to know exactly, I'm angry.
Yes, why?
I don't even know what I did to you.
Oh, always just Clara.
Aren't you happy that she's with us? I think you like Clara.
I like her too, but she annoys me.
No time for me.
Well...
I've got it! You both have to come with me!
That's not possible!
And if it's possible?
She can't walk.
Oh, I see. Then I have to carry her.
Way too heavy.
We'll try it with you!
Yes!
If I can carry you, I can carry Clara for a long time.
How much heavier can she not be?
Haha, haha, haha, hahaha, haha, haha, haha, haha.
That´s okay.
But with me.
Clara is a lot bigger than me.
So eat the dinner.
Yippie!
Ah, haha, haha, haha, haha, haha, haha, hahaha.
How can we bring her here?
You can't let her fall.
I know.
Oh, Heidi, are you awake already?
You got up. Didn't you sleep?
No, I couldn't sleep.
Did you pick them? Where did you get them all of a sudden?
I was on the flower meadow I told you about.
Beautiful, huh?
And how beautiful they are.
But tomorrow you have to take me with you. Do you promise?
Peter promised to carry you.
That's nice, but I'm too heavy for him.
Oh, I dreamed so beautifully. I was very far up on the mountain.
Did you see mummies in your dream?
No, but many thousands of flowers.
Good evening, you two. Were you also brave?
Peter, I have allowed myself to put on my shoes again.
That's good.
Miss Clara, I want us to start with the lesson tomorrow.
Yes.
And please don't forget the medicine.
I'll take it for sure.
I'll be back early tomorrow.
Goodbye, Mr. Oehi, see you tomorrow.
Good, see you tomorrow.
If she comes with me too, I don't want it anymore.
It's okay.
It doesn't matter if she comes with us or not.
Psst! Tell me, what are you two whispering about all of a sudden?
Oh, nothing.
Nothing at all, just like that.
Peter wanted to say goodbye to me.
You wanted that, didn't you?
Mhm.
Oh, you two are lying. That was something else.
Peter!
Do it! Get out of here, you morons! Disappear! Stand up!
Go! Go!
She needs me!
Goodbye!
Come back early tomorrow!
I can't take it anymore!
Let go of my hand!
I'm stuck!
Goodbye, Mrs. Rottenmeier!
Don't forget what you promised today!
Be punctual!
Goodbye!
To be continued
The next morning Heidi wanted to show the plan of Clara to the girls and finally
put it into action.
As fast as she could, she went down to Brigitte to borrow a pair of old trousers
from Peter for Clara, in which she should feel comfortable.
Brigitte thought Heidi's idea at first was extremely strange, but then she gave
Heidi what she wanted.
Clara was a little embarrassed.
But it didn't take long until Heidi had convinced her and Peter was able to
fulfill his promise to carry Clara to the pasture.
But we want to tell you about this in our next story.
Heide, Heide, your world are the mountains.
Heide, Heide, because up here you are at home.
Heide, Heide, come home.
Find your happiness, come back home.