Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio, Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Holadio
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
You
Heidi, Heidi
Now I've fallen asleep again. Heidi!
Heidi?
Yes, you long-sleeper. Good morning. Where is Heidi? They stormed out of the
house early in the morning.
Yes? Where did she go? No idea. She didn't tell me anything. Come on, let's have
breakfast.
Heidi?
Good morning, Brigitte!
Yes, what do you want down here with us?
You're as fast as the fire brigade.
Did something happen?
Will you do me a favor, Brigitte?
Can you lend me some old pants from Peter?
That's why you ran away like that.
Mhm.
The good one he wears. I only have an old one stuffed here.
That's enough. I don't need a good one.
If you think so, I still want to know what you're up to.
I'll explain it later.
Haha!
Here, this is the only one we still have. You don't want to put it on, do you?
I don't!
Who else?
Thank you!
Give it to Peter later!
Yes!
Thank you very much.
Wasn't that Heidi?
What did she want so early down here with us, Brigitte?
She borrowed some old trousers from Peter.
I just want to know what she needs them for.
I'd like to know that too.
Surely our Peter has torn his new trousers
and now he's afraid to come home.
Now I just have to talk to Clara about it.
Good morning, Clara!
Where have you been so early?
I got something for you.
What is it?
Please put it on, yes?
I think it would fit you exactly.
Why should I put it on?
I already put on a dress.
A dress, but no pants.
Now I don't understand anything anymore.
You don't have to do that.
Just put on your pants.
My pants? I can't possibly put on a pants.
And if you can?
Where is your wheelchair?
Where were you?
Downstairs with Brigitte. I borrowed something.
Heidi wants me to put on pants, but that's not possible.
And she doesn't say why.
Yes.
That's something new. What did you screw on the wheelchair?
I would like to know that too.
What could that be? Think about it.
I have no idea. It doesn't even look nice yet.
Grandfather, now tell me what's good about it.
I'll show you. Push the wheelchair.
Yes gladly.
Lara, pull the lever now.
This one?
Ouch!
Now it's rolling again.
Weird.
Now I understand. That way I can slow down the wheelchair.
Now it's at least less dangerous for you.
I hope it helps you, Lara.
Yes, thank you very much.
Now you don't have to hold the wheels with your hand all the time.
Thank you, Grandfather.
You're welcome, my child.
So, Heidi, now tell me what you're up to with these pants.
Clara, she's supposed to put them on. I've already told you.
So? Why?
You'll see why she's supposed to.
Why are you making it so secretive?
Just like that. Clara, here, put them on.
Clara!
Put the brakes on!
Clara, put them on!
You think that's very strange. Did it have to be?
What's wrong with you? There's the brake.
Yes, that's right. You're somehow right.
But it wasn't good anyway.
Don't be like that. What can happen? I can stop now.
Calm down.
Yes, it's all right. I was just scared.
Tomorrow, Peggy. Are you still waiting for a goat?
Yes.
I can't believe it.
I can't do it and I don't want to. After all, I'm not a climber and I don't stay
here all night.
Oh, who wants something now?
What do you want, Peter?
The goats are slowly becoming impatient.
Get rid of this unnecessary animal stuff.
That's not possible. But when are you coming?
Later. How many times should I tell you that I don't want to be spoiled by you?
Oh, I always forget that.
I'll let a farmer help me today. Thank you.
Please.
You let her stand with the goats in the landscape for an hour and don't say a
word.
But you should say, but I'm going to get her.
Today he's coming so late.
You can't rely on him.
If you're in a hurry, something will happen to him.
That's how he is.
Who's in a hurry? We have the whole day.
No, I have something planned.
There, he's coming!
Finally! Now let's go!
Morning!
It's about time.
Good morning. Where is Mrs. Rottenmeier?
Down in the village and she's complaining.
Why? I have no idea.
She's in a terrible mood.
Wonderful, then she's not here today and everything will work out as planned.
Do you know what she has today?
What do you have today, Heidi?
You know it.
Yes, that's right.
I don't know what she has today either.
And now tell her to put on your pants.
No, I can't do that.
I'm a girl, it just doesn't belong and it looks impossible.
Tell her right away that it doesn't look impossible. Go on, please.
Clara, Heidi means... No, I mean... Yes, you know... Yes, just like that.
Clara, didn't I tell you yesterday that we wanted to go to the flower garden?
Oh, that's why!
What do you mean?
Just like I told you. Peter will carry you on his back.
Yes, you said that, but I'm way too heavy.
It will be fine.
Am I not too heavy for you, Peter? Oh, if you could take me with you, that would
be wonderful.
Yes, that would be it.
I also make myself very light.
Thank you, Peter, that's nice of you.
And now the pants are being put on.
Peter, we're done!
Yes? Great!
It can start now.
Yes, it looks strange.
No one sees you, and Mrs. Rottenmeier I hold here firmly.
Mhm.
Hopefully you have not taken too much.
Oh, it's going to be fine.
I'll get it done.
Come on, Clara.
Hold on tight.
Don't drop it.
Is it okay?
Yes, better than I thought.
Come on.
Will it be okay, Clara?
Do you feel safe?
Yes, it's very comfortable.
Have fun, children.
Peter, take good care of where you go and don't come home too late today, okay?
Yes, I know. Goodbye.
Come on, Heidi, you carry the backpack.
Yes.
Everything will be eaten up, do you hear?
I can do that easily.
I didn't expect that from you in any other moment.
Please leave something for the others too. Especially Clara has to eat.
I will. What do they think of me?
And you, Clara, close your eyes wide open and look at everything carefully.
Yes, of course, you don't have to tell me that.
Go on, Joseph, go with the children and help Peter to pick up the goats.
Don't overwork yourself!
Definitely not! No!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Can't you sit down and take a break?
I planned it and will do it. No break.
Careful.
Uli, please let me down.
I won't let you down.
So this is your pasture.
That's how you described it. Oh, look over there!
Those are marmots.
That's how they look, so cute.
They'll stay there for a long time today.
You're lucky, otherwise they'll disappear much faster.
There, gone, like swallowed up by the earth.
Let's stay here, okay? There are enough flowers for us.
Oh, what? Peter's carrying you. He's strong.
Oh, what? We want to go a little higher.
We'll be there soon.
Well, good luck.
He needs that too.
Oh, we're here.
Just wonderful.
Yes.
Get up.
Listen to the flowers.
There are so many.
It's like a fairy tale.
Yes.
We're finally here.
Millions of flowers.
Yes.
As far as you can see, it's so wonderful that I just can't believe it. Just
fantastic!
I'm picking my bouquet back there on the rock. You can pick it here.
If they don't come back...
What if she forgets me?
Oh, come on, Heidi, she'll come back for sure.
Oh, if I could run and jump and dance like Heidi. That must be nice.
I find that irresponsible of you.
How can you leave the children alone on the flower meadow?
Who knows where this strange flower meadow is?
Who guarantees that the children do not get lost?
Tell me, have you ever thought that you could go on the nerves of people with
your constant whining?
No, not yet. And I am convinced that intelligent people take my warnings
seriously.
I fear the worst for Clara.
You see, that's the difference. I think it's good for you.
I don't know if you really appreciate Clara's situation.
Clara is different. You can't compare her to other children.
But you don't want to listen to me. You don't want to see it.
Why don't you make yourself a cup of coffee?
I can't believe it.
There's fresh milk, too.
I don't like goat milk.
I don't like it either.
Clara is here so that she can feel the desire to finally stand on her own two
feet.
This is what the secret is based on, and I also have great hopes.
Get that out of your head. Clara will never be able to walk.
And I tell you, she will.
Clara was surrounded by you and the servants from morning to evening.
Every day she was told that she was sick and could not walk.
Have you ever given her courage?
Oh!
To be continued
Watch out! I'm going to eat.
Thanks!
Oh, a tablecloth made of flowers.
Yes.
It's festive.
Fresh goat milk can't be found anywhere else.
Yes.
Where's Peter's bowl?
Peter doesn't need any.
Why?
Just wait, you'll see.
Don't look like that.
You look like you saw a ghost.
Can't you really imagine how Peter would do that?
No, unfortunately not. But now I'll see for myself.
You have to eat first, I'm starving!
The bread is smeared.
And where the milk is, you know.
You can say that.
Well, do you know now?
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
I don't know. I don't know. I don't make such accusations.
You should actually be the one making the accusations.
None of us has any reason to think of accusations at all.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Do you want to take a break, Peter?
Careful!
Clara has...
Let's take a break.
We don't have time. We promised to be home on time.
Did you get hurt somewhere?
Not a bit, really not.
Wait, I'll get the Grandfather!
No, you don't need that!
Let's wait for the grandfather. It's not far anymore. He'll come and help us.
You've really done enough today. I'm way too heavy.
Fine by me, but I would have made it.
I can only see and smell the goats. I can't find the children anywhere.
Grandfather!
Stay here!
Heidi, quick! What happened?
Grandfather!
Imagine, Peter has...
Peter has...
What's wrong with him, Peter? Is he hurt?
Speak up!
Why didn't you wait?
Mrs. Clara!
You should have waited!
You're a fathead!
Are you alright?
Of course. We're back.
Yes, we're back.
Very good, Peter. Great.
I think so too.
All right, Clara?
Oh yes.
Peter, what's wrong with you? Are you sick?
Are you hurt? Are you in pain?
Peter, say something!
There's nothing to say at all.
I'm hungry, that's all.
Then you'll get something to eat.
Are we going home?
Wait here for me.
I'll get you something to eat, then you'll feel better.
Oh dear.
I'll be right with you, then it'll be faster.
Do you want to go again tomorrow, child?
I'd love to, but it's too hard for Peter.
When will I carry you?
That would be very nice, but I...
Mrs. Klara, how are you?
Why shouldn't I be well?
It was a wonderful day, wonderful, wonderful.
But you should have told me.
What did Mrs. Rottenmeier say earlier, Klara?
Not much yet, but it will come soon.
You can see it in her face when she's furious.
If you're talking about me by chance, then you're right.
And I have every reason.
It's hell.
It's the peak of shamelessness.
I'm really sick of fear.
At last, keep your mouth shut.
Don't you see that you're impressed by what you've seen today?
Leave the children alone, at last.
Is it better here? Can you bring the goats back?
Hmm, now I've eaten.
I'll go with you for a while.
You don't need that.
I know I don't need it.
Hurry up, okay?
Goodbye.
Thank you, Peter.
You're welcome.
Nobody told you to shake hands?
Isn't it time for you to go home?
Oh yes, I totally forgot about that.
Peter, Heidi, wait!
Peter!
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Why are you crying?
It was so beautiful today on the flower meadow.
But it was so hard for Peter.
It's so bad that I can't walk.
Someone always has to help me.
Calm down.
It was exactly what the Alm-Öhi had hoped for.
For the first time, Clara wished to be able to run.
The next morning the tears were forgotten and with joy Clara welcomed animals,
flowers and mountains already as old acquaintances.
A few days ago, Heidi had to call her the names of every single flower and every
single beetle.
But in the meantime, Clara already knew her way around here as well as Heidi.
For her, every day she was allowed to spend up here on the Alp was a day out of
a fairy tale.
Because Heidi and Peter did everything they could to make her holidays as
beautiful as possible.
But we want to tell you about this in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back again.