Hon-la-di-o
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Heidi, because up here you are at home
Dark fir trees, green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi, you need to be happy
Highlanders, highlanders, highlanders
Lallylally lallylally lallylally
Heidi, Heidi, come home
Find your happiness, come back again
Did you like it? Subscribe to the channel to not miss the next video!
You're still not on your way?
Yes, I'm almost done.
Hopefully. If you wait any longer, it will be too hot for the goats.
Hurry up, or you'll get in trouble.
Yes, I know.
The dress is good, but why do you need it?
Will you please bring me my things?
Yes, with pleasure.
Please don't forget my hat.
No, no, I already have it.
Sometimes I want to know what's going on with him.
Sometimes he's so lazy that he can't move.
And today he's up in the middle of the night to do something.
You seem to have overslept, Peter.
No!
I'll be right there.
Okay, Tantchen, I'll get you.
Tantchen?
Good morning, Joseph. How have you been?
Joseph always sleeps like a moody animal.
Heidi, do you think Peter is...
Got sick because he hasn't come yet?
Ah, good morning, little ghost!
Baaah!
Have you at least heard him whistle?
No.
I'm afraid he's sick.
There come these nasty tits again!
I will never win my life against this disgusting beast!
You've lost your way! The way is here!
Peter?
Yes?
Please carry my bag.
It's just the right size.
Come on, let's go.
I really didn't do it for her.
Clara!
I've never seen one before. Isn't that funny?
A little bit. At least the colors are funny.
Let's see if I can find another one.
If I only knew.
If someone could tell me.
If at least Miss Rottenmeier finally came here.
But do you know if she's sick?
He must be sick, otherwise he would be there and everything just because I can't
walk.
He was so tired last night, he must have put too much effort into it.
I found a snake, should I give it to Joseph or do you want it?
Doesn't matter.
Peter!
Good morning!
Good morning Heidi, good morning Clara, good morning Peter, where have you been
for so long?
At home.
I had to do something for us!
Can you take my bag, Heidi?
Did you do that so that you can wear the bag better?
Peter, I want to thank you again for yesterday. Are you feeling better today?
I'm not feeling bad at all.
You were too tired yesterday. I thought you were sick.
We really didn't do anything about wearing it. I'm tired.
A little bit of wearing. You wore me.
Are you going to the pasture again today?
Of course we'll come with you. We're going, aren't we?
What is it?
We're going to the pasture.
Good morning.
How are you?
Well, also there.
Oh, good morning.
Good morning.
I'll be right back. I'll get our breakfast.
Oh, Adelheid!
Yes, what is it, Mr. Rottenmeier?
What did you mean by our breakfast?
You want to go back to the pasture, don't you?
Of course!
And that I forbade it last night doesn't interest you, does it?
Have you forgotten how tired Clara was yesterday?
Peter carried her, didn't he?
Still!
Miss Clara, I assume you're still tired.
I'm not tired at all. Not a bit.
Clara wants to go to the flower garden. She liked it.
Please listen to me. You will stay here today and rest.
Do you understand me? We can study when we have the opportunity.
Yes.
What? You have to stay here today?
Unfortunately, Peter. Today, yes.
But Clara...
Now I've built the frame for nothing.
I'm sorry.
Very nice. I'm very relieved.
I'm glad to see that you've become sensible again, Clara.
That doesn't mean that you have to stay, Heidi. Just go with Peter.
Grandfather!
Don't worry about me. I'm doing my homework today. Go on.
I have to drive the herd to the pasture now.
No, wait a minute. Show me what you're wearing.
It's no longer important.
Why? It looks good.
What did you make it for?
Just tell me, Peter. What did you make it for?
Oh, of course, for Clara.
Peter, you're wonderful!
You wanted to wear Clara with it?
Who else?
Oh, Peter!
She's strong enough to carry two Claras.
Did you come so late today because you built the carrier?
Ah, yes.
Clara, let's see if we can do it.
Be honest, do you really think you can carry me up the mountain again?
Now tell me, but be honest.
Of course I think I can. Why do you hold me?
That's why I made this carrier for you.
Do you think it will hold me?
We'll both remember that early enough.
No way!
I can't allow it! Didn't we just decide to do the homework together and get the
degree?
Ms. Rottenmeier.
No, Mr. Oehi, I'm sorry. Please don't interrupt me. You know you have to keep
your promises.
No, I'm sorry, Ms. Rottenmeier, but I'm going.
I never promised not to go. I only promised to get my degree at some point.
Come on, Peter, we'll try the suit, okay?
Good, but promise me that you're not afraid.
Peter, I haven't said yes yet.
I say yes.
We'll give Clara a blanket so that she doesn't get cold.
She can still do schoolwork.
But how often has Clara had the opportunity to come to the mountains?
From me.
Well, good. Under the condition that tomorrow is learned, Miss Clara.
Did you hear that? I'm allowed to go with you!
Yes!
And Joseph will help you and watch out for the goats.
Then it will be as beautiful as yesterday!
Joseph, come! Joseph!
How do you feel up there, Clara?
Like a princess on a wobbly castle tower.
Shouldn't we take a break, Peter?
No, it's not necessary.
With the carrier it's really going well.
But let me know, okay?
When you get tired.
Now you have to hold on tight.
Don't fall down.
You can open your eyes again and you too, Reine!
Yes! Come on, Joseph!
Go on!
I'm sorry that I'm making you such difficulties.
They're not!
I'm so heavy and if I could walk, you wouldn't have to carry me, you know?
You can't normally walk.
Yes, unfortunately.
I want to walk so much.
Get really healthy first, Clara.
Why don't you walk a little slower?
Why?
I don't want to walk a little slower.
Oh no! It's pouring down!
Then we will have to get the children.
Yes.
You will certainly not rest until you are back here.
You do not know what I will do if the poor child gets cold.
What then?
Put on your old pants from me. That's better than complaining.
No, please. I think I did not understand correctly.
I want you to put on your old pants from me.
Or do you want to climb around in this elevator outside?
You seem to have forgotten, my dear Almöhi,
that I am a lady with decency.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Now come on, no one will see you here.
Would you please go a little bit slower? I can't go any longer.
Good.
I'm not used to the pants. My legs feel very stiff.
I'm glad to believe that.
Would you like us to turn around again?
Oh, for heaven's sake, no! I would be worried about Mrs. Clara coming around.
You're breaking your head for nothing.
In a few minutes it will stop raining again.
How do you know that exactly?
Take a look at the sky, it's getting brighter.
You think so?
I don't mean it, I see it.
You have to decide, should we go on or turn around?
No, we definitely don't turn around.
After all, I bear the responsibility, I know what my duty is.
You don't know me yet, but I'll never give up.
Follow me.
The road is a bit slippery.
May I help you?
No, thank you.
I just wonder why I was trained as a teacher and not as a climber.
And at home he hangs in laundry.
Oh, Clara!
Children!
Heidi! Peter!
Fallen in the rain.
Now don't overdo it. Heidi and Peter know each other here.
I just hope it's true what you're saying.
They took the basket of bread and wine and left.
They walked a long, wide path through a forest.
And then they suddenly came to a forest light with a beautiful flower meadow.
As beautiful as we are.
Many thousand blue bell flowers and yellow key flowers grew on the meadow.
And the little red cap thought that the grandmother could actually pick a flower
bouquet.
The little red cap picked the flowers and suddenly it ran away.
I ran away, it called.
I ran away. Where am I?
And suddenly a quiet voice says, come with us. We are the seven dwarfs. We live
behind the seven mountains. We have a little hut and seven beds and seven chairs
and seven plates and seven cups. And we need someone to clean the hut for us.
Wasn't that always Snow White with the dwarfs?
Of course it was Snow White who cleaned it.
Yes, but that was before she got married.
So that's new to me.
You think Little Red Riding Hood paid attention to the dwarfs after Snow White's
wedding?
Sarah is always making her own fairy tales.
It'll be over soon.
It looks like it.
Clara! Are you okay?
Tell me!
Did you do it on purpose this time?
Definitely not.
So you know, you have to be a little more careful.
Well, I might have been scared just now.
My heart is still beating to my neck.
It has to be like that when you're riding a sled in winter.
Look, I slipped from up there to here.
Pretty far. You're completely soaked.
And you too.
Me too.
Yes. Yes, and how? And what now? Drying clothes, what else? And how?
We still have the wool blanket. We can wrap ourselves in it. Wait, I'll get it.
Did they really climb so high?
The poor young man could have carried Clara so far away!
We're here.
Oh, yes?
Oh, yes.
Yes.
Hear that? They're alive! They're laughing!
What did I tell you, Mrs. Rottenmeier? You're doing yourself in vain.
Mrs. Klarow!
We dance today, ring-a-ling, ring-a-ling, ring-a-ling
Because today we want to be happy, to be happy
We dance with the bat, ring-a-ling, ring-a-ling
La-la-la-la-la-la-la-la, la-la-la
We dance today, ring-a-ling, ring-a-ling, ring-a-ling
The party is still on
Long not out! Long not out!
La-la-la-la-la!
Miss Clara!
What are you wearing?
A pants. You can see that, can't you?
Miss Clara, I am shocked!
You both only have your underpants on!
Of course, our clothes had to dry!
Oh, we're sitting in the rain.
got into it
Yes, but we didn't get very wet. Peter built a tent for us and we sat under it
all the time.
You'll all get cold. All three of you.
No, I'll never get cold.
You think so?
Peter is cold.
Where are you going?
I hope they really didn't freeze.
Have you at least wrapped yourself in the wool blanket?
Yes.
Oh, look, a rainbow!
Heidi, Peter, a rainbow!
Oh!
Shame!
Oh, I've never seen one in real life.
It's so beautiful!
Really beautiful.
You, Heidi, you...
Grandmother asks if you can bring Clara with you.
From me? Yes, but I don't know if Clara wants to.
I would like to get to know the grandmother.
Oh yes, then we'll go and visit her tomorrow. May we, grandfather?
From me.
Fine!
In a friendly little town I enter. In the streets lies red evening light.
From an open window just above the richest flower floor you can hear bells
ringing.
The world is still calm in the fog, the forest and meadows are still dreaming.
Soon you will see, when the veil falls, the blue sky undisturbed,
the dampened world in warm gold flows vigorously in autumn.
I know what you read out. Both poems are by Eduard Mörike and I recognized them
again.
One was the beginning of On a Hike and the other is called September Morning.
I used to learn a lot of poems by heart.
Really? Did you get a reward for every poem you learned by heart?
No, we didn't have any money for that.
I enjoyed it and I said it to her at school.
You read well, Clara. You must be a hard-working student with whom everyone is
very satisfied.
No, I can't do math so well.
Me neither. Counting together was fine, but I couldn't take a picture.
I always had to write it off with the others.
Clara, what's wrong with you all of a sudden?
Did you mean that earlier when you said that you liked my lecture?
Yes, of course.
You know what? I often read to you now.
Of course, only if you want.
I would be happy about that, but doesn't it strain you too much?
Not at all. It was fun for the first time.
Reading to you is much nicer. You don't talk in between like my teacher.
I don't have to improve you.
I can try to learn one by one.
Try it. Maybe it will be as much fun for you as it will be for me.
You, Heidi?
Tell me, did you actually notice it too?
Today I learned something that others couldn't.
Well, I would laugh at your part if I was happy and not cry.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Can we go back to the meadow tomorrow, when it stays so beautiful?
There, Peter! And friend Rottenmeier!
The next morning Peter brought three letters from Dörfle.
One was for Clara, one for Heidi and one for the grandfather.
And all three were written by Clara's grandmother.
Mrs. Sesemann announced her arrival.
Clara could not understand it at first.
Clara and Heidi made plans all day long what they wanted to show the
grandmother.
They remembered the trip they made in Frankfurt and the many funny games that
the grandmother always thought of.
They couldn't wait, it took them way too long until it was finally time.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back again.