Heide
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back again
Heide, Clara, pass to you
and even three letters to Heide
Heide, my legs are no longer as fast as yours
Ah, this untouchable creature!
Just let me stand in the landscape.
A letter for Clara.
One for you.
And one for you.
My letter is from the grandmother.
Imagine, mine too.
It looks like you, that they give individual letters.
I want to know what's in it.
Open it.
Yes.
Not again.
Imagine, Heidi, she wants to come here.
Read at least loudly.
Clara's grandmother says she wants to come here to visit us.
You know, the nice one from Frankfurt.
Is that the one from which you have the big fairy tale book?
Exactly. Grandfather, did you hear that Clara's grandmother is coming?
Not only heard, even read myself. It's also in my letter.
Do you think it's true?
If grandmother writes something, it's always true.
Wonderful, wonderful.
Oh, Adelheid, stop!
I said stop!
The place is closed!
What are you doing with that, Miss Clara?
Mrs. Clara, are you going to get dizzy?
I'm not going to get dizzy, we're just a little happy, that's all.
What do you call your behavior?
I call it monkey theater and not happy.
A lady, Mrs. Clara, has always been reserved to behave.
Even excessive joy is not shown.
Dear Mrs. Rottenmeier, do you know that you are starting to hurt me?
I can do without it for the rest of my life.
I know what you mean by that, but Mrs. Clara is now different from the others.
But why should she understand that?
After all, she is a SESEMAN.
And a SESEMAN is not a mountain farmer.
She looks just like normal people.
Man!
At some point you will understand that you are not making fun of me without
punishment.
Is she angry again? Did I say something wrong earlier?
No, you didn't. I'm sure she already knows.
And since she doesn't get along with my grandmother, she's angry now.
Grandmother can't stand Mrs. Rottenmeier, Heidi.
She's always said that Mrs. Rottenmeier is way too strict.
There must be something behind it, for sure.
I wrote to him that he should come here to see the right one.
And now his mother is coming, whether the Almöhi is behind it.
Good bye.
Will you please send me to the hut now, Heidi?
Yes, thank you.
I can't wait, Clara. I just can't wait to see your grandmother again.
I've been so happy to see her in Frankfurt.
Do you remember how she showed me her favorite room so I could hide somewhere?
And do you remember how she walked through the city with us?
Yes, but do you remember how she dressed up as a bear and promised us to always
be funny?
Sometimes she danced with me and then we sang songs that she taught me.
Yes, do you remember how she conjured flowers into the glass in the evening?
Of course I remember that. I remember everything.
The hand dolls that she bought us, for example, and the glass melody.
Yes, and the many hundred butterflies in my room.
If she had been there, we would have been able to keep the kitten.
Definitely. She was always so nice to me.
Yes, that was her. She liked you very much.
In contrast to Mrs. Rottenmeier. She was sometimes really mean, Heidi.
I always wanted to run away. I wanted to go home all the time. I always wanted
to come here.
But sometimes it was all bad.
Tell me, are you crying, Heidi? What is it?
Oh, nothing.
It's over. I just had to think about something.
Do you know about the time without your grandmother?
When she wasn't there, it wasn't very nice.
Yes, I know.
Are you still angry?
No. How do you know that? Not at all!
Heidi!
H-heidit!
I'm so sorry!
I...
I can't do it anymore.
Can you find her?
She has to come at any moment.
Yes.
There's someone coming! Look!
Grandmother!
I hear the children calling. We'll be up soon.
Hup!
Help me!
Stop!
Put the horse down!
Careful!
Pull the reins!
Hold it back!
Grandmother, help!
Grandmother!
That would have gone almost wrong now.
Heidi, greetings to God, my child.
At least I seem to be alive and not in heaven,
because you are standing in front of me, at least something joyful.
Greetings to God, grandmother.
Please be so kind and help me get down from this elephant.
Yes, of course.
Thank you. How long have we not seen each other?
Incredibly long.
You have grown, my child, and become strong. You look good, Heidi. I'm so happy.
I'm still here.
Clara.
Why aren't you coming here?
Clara isn't sitting in her chair. How nice.
Come on, let's wait for you.
That's really shameless of us.
Welcome!
It's so nice that you came.
I'm also happy about it, Clara, my child.
My little boy.
How good you look.
Tell me, are you really my granddaughter Clara?
I can hardly believe it. You look like a healthy mountain girl.
You must have had a few wonderful holidays up here.
You can see it.
Well, hopefully I will recover as well as you.
Certainly.
Not to be believed, brown, burned and radiant, a completely different girl,
round and healthy.
No, I didn't get fat, but we've been out all day and everything tastes so good.
You don't even know how nice everyone is to me here, Grandmother.
I can imagine it, very good even.
Let's go and greet the Almöhi, yes?
I seem to have taken something.
Let's go.
What did you take?
That must be at least a cent.
You're as heavy as a sack of potatoes, my child.
Oh, you're exaggerating. It can't be that much.
Peter can still carry me well.
Peter the goat herder?
Peter was the boy Heidi always told me about in Frankfurt.
Hopefully I'll get to know him soon too.
I'm so curious about your friends, Clara.
You've already seen them all?
Yes.
The goats, the dog, the marmots? 也有狗和猴猫。
And if we're lucky, even an eagle. 嗯。如果我们有幸运,连一只猴猫也会有。
Children! That sounds like a lot of promises. 孩子!这很像是很多的承诺。
Good thing I'm here. 太好了,我来到了。
Will you come back tonight? 来到晚上再来吧。
Yes, but no excitement. 没什么惊喜。
But on time, if I may. 但我能请到时。
And over there in the hut, we live. 还有那边,在那边的屋子,我们住。
But no! Oh, Zezelman, you can't sit right on the grass.
但是不!哦,Zezelman,你不可以立刻坐在草地上。
Is that to say that you haven't sat on the grass all the time you've been here?
是不是说你一直都在这里,没有立刻坐在草地上吗?
Of course not! Of course not!
First, it's unhealthy, and secondly, for a lady, it's an extremely unkind lady.
当然不是!首先,它是不健康,而且第二,是一个非常不善良的女人。
Oh, you never change, Ms. Rottenmeier. 哦,你绝对不会改变,美女。
A little bit she has already changed. 一点她已经改变了。
Once she even put on her pants and climbed up the mountains. 一次她甚至穿上褲子和爬上山。
And recently she found the rainbow beautiful, didn't she? 而最近她喜欢了玉米,对吗?
Not possible! 不可能!
Of course not! Of course not!
Stop making fun of me! Stop making fun of我!
Well, she still doesn't have any sense of humor.
Good day, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Good day!
Welcome, Mrs. Sesemann. I am pleased that you have fulfilled your promise.
Heidi told me a lot about you when she came back.
I can only hope that there was not all too much bad in it.
In any case, she talked a lot about you.
And now that I see you...
Do you know what I think, Clara?
Heidi confused you with a picture.
Excuse me, please. I don't know what you mean.
Heidi brought no picture with her from Frankfurt.
Oh, for heaven's sake, that's not what it was meant to be.
We have an old oil shaker at home in Frankfurt.
Oh, excuse me, an old oil painting that the children loved very much.
The picture shows St. Joseph and he looks like you.
That's what it was meant to be.
Oh, excuse me, please, that I reacted so strangely.
But I thought you thought Heidi had taken something that didn't belong to you.
Heidi?
For God's sake, how did you come up with the idea that I could think of
something like that?
Apparently I never learn to express myself properly.
Tell me, grandfather, do you want to stand here forever?
Why don't we go and sit down?
You're right. We stand here and talk.
And you have to be tired of the exhausting journey.
Should I get you some fresh milk right away?
Yes, please, Heidi. That would be nice.
Now I'm finally going to try the goat's milk you've always written to me.
I'm so curious.
All right, let's go.
Why don't you go, Grandmother? What's the matter with you?
Oh, Heidi, I just thought of something for a moment.
Come on, I'll show you everything.
I'll show you everything.
Do you like goat milk as much as I do?
I think it's delicious.
I think everything is wonderful. I can't believe it.
I sit here in this wonderful landscape,
drink milk and a few days ago I was in the big city.
I think I'm dreaming.
It can't be reality.
I can understand how you feel,
but please excuse me, I have to...
What a pity.
May I ask you something?
Yes?
Did you happen to read the letter that I wrote to your son a few days ago?
No, I only heard that you sent him a letter.
Mrs. Sesemann, I have to talk to you.
If your granddaughter stays here any longer,
not only will her studies not be picked up anymore,
but also her behavior will be ruined.
Since Mrs. Clara looks a little healthier,
the purpose of your visit here seems to be fulfilled.
I'm on immediate leave.
No!
I don't want to go home yet.
No, Grandmother, be honest, you didn't come here to get me out of here, did you?
Dear Miss Rottenmeier, I'm afraid you have to explain everything to me in more
detail.
Yes, I can. Miss Clara refuses to listen to me.
She doesn't take a nap, doesn't take her medicine, and neglects the written
homework.
Is that so?
What a mischievous child.
I have to say, if I look at our Clara like that,
then she doesn't seem to need any medicine at all, does she?
Uh-huh.
And what about books?
She should keep her eyes open and look around.
What do you mean?
I'm afraid I don't understand her.
Clara has also once earned holidays
and I am very happy that they are such beautiful holidays.
Tell me, what did you do? What did you spend your time with?
We were with the goat herd on the pasture, where they go every day.
And then we were even further up, on the flower meadow.
Yes, tell me, did you do all that with the wheelchair?
No, Peter carried it on his back.
He made an extra carrier for me.
The heavy child, all the way?
Yes, how big is the boy? That must be a giant.
I couldn't even lift you up before.
Clara and Heidi, the grandmother, described everything they had experienced
together in the past few days.
Clara was particularly fond of the rainbow they had seen.
And Heidi reported how Clara and Peter had told a fairy tale under the tent.
Mrs. Sesemann only understood the children's enthusiasm too well.
She was happy to see her granddaughter so happy and carefree.
It must have been a wonderful experience for the children, Mrs. Rottenmeier.
I just don't understand that Mr. Almey let her go alone.
That's not...
That's exactly what I think, Mrs. Sesemann, but he was deaf to my arguments.
See? That's why I wrote the letter. He's got an incredible big head.
Sometimes I talked to him like I talked to a little child.
I'll ask him for his reasons.
That's why I'm here.
And now to you. Of course, you can't go without homework.
But you just said that I earned my holidays.
Yes, I said that. And you also had your holidays.
But I think, Clara, it's not too much to ask if you do homework for an hour
every day.
The day is so long.
Well, if it has to be. But I don't think that's nice of you.
If you learn with me, it'll be faster.
It has to be.
Please, Grandmother, but not more than an hour every day.
An hour is long enough.
Yes, an hour is enough.
To be continued
I don't know anything about that.
My son didn't tell me that.
I understand him very well.
I assume he wanted to save you from disappointment.
There is a chance that Clara can walk?
I don't understand that at all.
I know it's just a hope, but at least that.
I haven't dared to think about it all these years,
let alone say it out at some point.
How did that happen? Why do you think she'll be able to walk again one day?
I'm sorry for my excitement, but it's so surprising.
We've already visited so many doctors and experienced disappointments.
I don't know if you can imagine what that's like.
Maybe Clara will be able to walk again.
Maybe she'll lead a normal life, just like all the other girls in her age.
Believe me, Mrs. Sesemann.
For me, it's no longer hope.
For me, it's certainty.
Yes?
I've observed Clara's behavior in the last few weeks.
How she moves, what she does, how she reacts.
She will be able to walk again one day.
No, you can't be sure.
But I am sure.
And that's why I want to ask you to leave her here longer than you originally
planned.
You have to leave it to chance.
It can go very fast.
But it can also take an eternity.
Because, unfortunately, she doesn't dare to do it herself.
Unfortunately, she has not yet understood how wonderful it is to walk around
with other children and to die.
She has felt the desire, but not intense enough, and we have to bring her to
that.
She must think of nothing else but the desire to finally be able to walk.
I understand, so that's why you left her alone with the children on the pasture.
You will get any kind of support from me that you need to help Clara.
And I'm sure, if someone is able to give you self-confidence, then you, Alm-Öhi.
I'm so nervous, I can't even understand it.
Keep Clara here as long as you think it's right, okay?
We're done, Grandmother, we only started today with half an hour.
Oh, there you are. Are you going to play with us now? We're done.
Unfortunately, no.
I can't. I urgently have to speak to Miss Rottenmeier.
So, and we've learned.
We only did that because you promised to play with us afterwards.
You used to keep your promises.
Don't pull a face.
At the moment it's not possible. We still have so many days left to play.
That's not true. You'll probably be leaving again soon, as always.
Not this time.
This time I'm not leaving voluntarily at all. This time I'm staying.
Are you lying to yourself? You're exaggerating again.
Maybe I'm exaggerating a little. Maybe I'm also lying a little.
Do you understand what's going on with you?
The two of them must have talked about something.
Yes, what can that be?
I could burst out of curiosity.
I'd rather not.
I'm sorry, I have to disturb you. I have to discuss something with you.
What is it?
I would like to ask you to return to Frankfurt by the next train.
In heaven's name!
In my opinion, the servants have been alone in the house for too long, and you
know, there are always difficulties without supervision.
I fully understand that.
Then it's good. Make sure that everything goes as usual in Frankfurt.
Just too much! You don't even know how much I hate this place!
This smell of goats and cheese makes me crazy!
I immediately pack clear things.
Oh no, I was just talking about you.
What, please?
I, uh, I don't know, did I, uh, possibly, I mean, did you just say I was just
talking about you?
That's exactly what I said. I can understand that you're surprised, but I need
you in Frankfurt and I want my granddaughter to stay here for a while.
You're not going to leave mother souls alone here in this wilderness, are you?
Yes, and I've never raised Clara as well as I do at the moment. Here she gets
everything she needs, do you understand?
Love, understanding, friendship, and security.
Haven't you noticed how happy she is here yet?
You want to take her away from me?
You're acting as if you don't get all of this from me.
This child is my one and only, my life's content.
Calm down.
Please forgive me, I shouldn't have let myself go.
I know it will never happen again.
Take care of yourself, Clara, and come home strong and healthy.
Please don't be so nice to your Almöhi, she's so tender and helpless.
Please, children, don't overdo it.
Man, Heidi, Mrs. Rottenmeier is crying.
Yes, I'm crying. Even a teacher has human feelings, but that doesn't interest
you.
Yes, you've never seen that.
With a good education, she would have spared herself this answer.
I'll talk to you about it later.
Oh, Peter's coming!
Then I'll finally get to know him.
This Peter must be a very talented boy.
He did so much for Clara.
Come on, you two!
Peter, imagine, the grandmother is here!
Good day, Peter.
You don't even know how happy I am to see you.
I am the grandmother.
Good evening.
I would have recognized you everywhere.
That's exactly how Heidi described you.
You are unique.
Clara wrote that you can cut so well, that's why I brought you something.
A pocket knife.
I want to thank you for being so nice to my Clara.
I've always been nice. Just wonderful. I've always wanted something like that.
We chose it.
Me?
Well done. Now you have to cut something for her.
I'd love to, you know.
See you in Frankfurt, Ms. Rottenmeier.
See you. Good luck. See you tomorrow.
Did you win?
Did you know that Miss Rottenmeier can cry?
I would never have dared to tell her.
You look weird.
The next day brought many, many new experiences for Clara and Heidi.
They got up even earlier than usual and to their own surprise, they regretted
that Mrs. Rottenmeier left.
Immediately after breakfast, Grandmother came up the mountain.
This time she went to Clara's joy, the horse did not pass.
In the morning they all made a trip together.
Even Josef went, Mrs. Sesemann to love, voluntarily with.
Apparently he wanted to make a good impression.
It was a beautiful peaceful day, except for one experience.
Well, that was less peaceful, but we want to tell you about it in our next
story.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges