Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark pines
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
I thought Grandma was coming for breakfast.
It's way too early.
She has to go to sleep.
She should sleep at home.
Clara!
Tell me when she comes.
No, don't tell her.
Heidi, Clara, go and wash.
And then come for breakfast. It's all done.
Yes!
Heidi!
Mrs. Sesemann, it's time!
Has anyone else come yet?
Huh?
Ouch!
Take good care of Clara, please.
Don't worry about it.
But please take care of the house in Frankfurt.
Of course.
I have planned to stay here longer than planned.
And please, Clara has to do her homework every day.
Otherwise she will forget what she learned.
I know. You have to hurry.
Otherwise you will miss the train.
I have to go.
Goodbye, Mrs. Sesemann, and please greet Mrs. Enklara from me again.
Yes, gladly.
Fräulein Rottenmeier is gone.
Look, another Peter.
Good morning.
Good morning, but why are you hiding?
I want to get her.
Oh yes, but unfortunately I can not come with you right away.
I have decided to go shopping before.
Please be so kind and tell the two girls that I will come back later.
I was so tired last night that I fell asleep without doing anything.
I'd love that!
That's how fast you should be able to be again.
Good morning! Good morning!
Why are you alone?
Where is the grandmother?
Did you notice if Mrs. Rottenmeier is gone?
Hm?
What first?
Why?
Which question should I answer first?
I don't know what you mean.
Me too.
We asked three questions in a row earlier.
Ask one after the other.
Oh, what? You know what we want to know.
Good.
One has left and the other is going shopping.
Hopefully not more knives.
I don't know what to start with.
Me too.
Did she tell you what she wants to buy?
No.
Too bad, she's probably buying presents for us and I'd like to know what.
I think so. See you soon!
See you tonight!
See you!
If I get a present too, please pick it up for me.
He already got the knife from her yesterday.
What a romantic little hut!
Do people live here or is it just for the holidays?
Peter lives here.
The boy lives here?
Please take me there, I want to say good day.
You are always so nice to Heidi and Clara.
Yes, well.
What a beautiful work.
I am glad to meet you.
Heidi has told a lot about you.
And Clara has described you in letters.
I am glad too.
And I would like to use the opportunity to thank you
that you were so nice to our Heidi in Frankfurt.
That's why you don't have to thank me.
That was a matter of course.
Heidi is a lovely girl. You can't imagine how happy she made me.
We sometimes laughed together. We could play together wonderfully.
I'm just sorry I understood too late how much she wanted to go home.
Oh, that's all long forgotten and hurt.
A child like Heidi could not feel comfortable in the big city.
Heidi needs the mountains.
Yes, now that I've met everything, I know it's too late.
For a long time, I was afraid that they would come one day to get Heidi away
from here.
But God forbid, Heidi promised never to go again.
I think she's coming!
Finally!
I couldn't have waited any longer!
Good morning, children!
Good morning!
Where have you been so long? We've been waiting so long!
So? How rude of me!
Please help me down.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Would you please carry my bag into the hut?
Yes, I'd love to.
There they are!
I think so, too.
Oh!
Oh, why can't you just invent more comfortable horses?
Everything hurts me.
I can imagine.
Grandfather?
Good morning.
Would you say it would be shameless if I asked you again for such a wonderful
glass of fresh goat's milk?
Not at all.
I made it.
Well, thank you.
Now finally say it.
What should I say?
What's in the bag.
Come with me.
We'll just take a look.
Good-bye.
Oh, there's nothing better.
Now show it to us, please.
What did you buy?
Oh, that's what you mean.
A wonderful bedclothes for everyone and a head pillow here.
A warm night's dress for Clara, but also wear it.
You know, my child, the nights are getting colder again.
And then a few work trousers for the palm oil.
So, is that what you want to know?
Is that all?
Yes.
We thought you would buy us a present. You also brought something for Peter.
Yes, we thought so.
Well, then I have to buy you something.
Yes, it doesn't have to be anything big and expensive.
Chocolate!
Well, nice. But that's why I'm not going down the mountain right away.
Oh, too bad.
No, certainly not. You can't ask for that. You'll have to wait.
Besides, I'm terribly tired again.
I just don't believe it.
But listen, Clara. You have the whole closet full of toys at home.
What more do you need? Now go and play outside.
I'm sorry, Grandmother, but I still don't believe it.
Well, you torturers, I have a present for you.
Grandma!
Show me what you've hidden!
You can't see my present.
Can you give something like that away?
And if you can give something like that away.
How are we supposed to recognize it if you give us something transparent?
I don't give you anything transparent, I give you something invisible.
So, and now I don't want to hear anything from you anymore. Wait until tomorrow.
Yes, but just say it.
No, I can't do that.
Let us guess, with hot and cold.
That looks like you. If you don't want to give up, you don't want to give up.
And now you're trying to get me around with all means.
Why not?
Keep going, Heidi. Maybe you can do it.
She already looks like she's about to tell us.
I don't think so.
Will you at least go for a walk with us?
No, I'm tired. I want to rest today.
I'm not used to the mountain air yet.
Why don't you go to Peter?
Me? If Clara has nothing against it?
I'd like to go back to the pasture.
Besides, I have to make sure that the little ghost gets good herbs.
Don't come back so late.
Say hello to Peter.
Why? I don't understand. Don't the goats eat on their own?
Yes, but she always gives him special herbs so that they give good milk.
Especially for me.
I've always said it. Heidi is really nice.
To be continued
Clara is missing. When all three of us are together, it's more and more fun.
I think she's nice. She's not arrogant at all.
Well, you see, and you got so busy when I said she was coming to visit us.
Oh, yes.
It doesn't smell at all. I didn't think it was right that she complained.
I mean Mrs. Rottenmeier, she always complained.
I can imagine. She must have always walked around with her cloth in front of her
nose.
What do you think of Clara's grandmother?
Very decent.
I also imagined her to be worse.
She's not bad at all.
Because of me.
Mrs. Rottenmeier said that I never had a nap, but that's not true.
We always lay on the meadow and dreamed.
We then looked at the clouds and everyone had to say what they were reminded of.
Most of them look like sheep.
And that was fun.
Yes, and how.
You know, sometimes I wish so much that I can walk.
I know, but you have to be healthy and strong first.
Maybe you can do it one day.
Tell me, have you ever tried to stand up?
But no!
What do you mean, but no?
Me, at your place, I would try it every day, secretly, so long until I suddenly
can.
Well, I've tried it before, but it didn't work.
THE END
The islands in the sea, surrounded by greedy waves, lonely exposed to the
primordial wilderness of creation.
So in ancient, long-past times, the few human settlements were taken out.
They were surrounded by unbuilt, partly unrealistic land, by swamps, primordial
forests, seas and mountains.
In the middle of the forest, there is a small forest, surrounded by swamps, by
swamps, by swamps, by swamps, by swamps, by swamps, by swamps, by swamps.
At that moment, a dry
Dear Clara, you jumped up. You stood up. I saw it.
It's true. You can go. He's right, Clara.
Hopefully it wasn't just an imitation.
Oh, Clara.
No, it wasn't.
What is it, man, for heaven's sake? What happened?
Clara can walk. She was afraid of the cow and suddenly jumped up.
Clara, say something.
What should I say? I don't even know what to think.
I knew it. You see, I knew it all the time.
I'm glad. Isn't that wonderful, Clara?
Do you think I can get up?
Yes.
I still can't get it. Only yesterday did we both talk about it.
Show it to us again. Try to get up, my child, please.
Something so stupid. How are you supposed to get up, poor thing, if I'm holding
you down all the time?
I can't get up at all.
Oh yes, you can. You just have to try.
Sure.
Aha.
Well, I could spend hours looking over there. 当然的,我可以找到几个人。
Please, have courage. 请,有勇气。
Just try one more time, okay? 尝试一次,好吗?
You'll see, it'll work. 你会看到,会成功的。
Try! Try really hard! You have to want it!
I want to, but I can't!
Now, Clara!
Please believe me, it's not possible! Leave me alone!
Clara, one more time! You could have stood up!
No, it's not possible! No, no, no, I can't! I'm scared!
It's not possible, she has to want it alone! Come on, Clara!
I'm sorry, Clara. I thought it would be easy now.
Calm down, that was very exhausting for you.
We'll try it again later.
Grandmother, I brought you something!
Grandmother!
Clara! Grandfather!
Who are you?
Heidi!
I brought you something. There!
Yes, what? What do you have?
Something's not right. Is Clara sick?
No, she got up.
On her feet? They're lying to me.
No, they're not lying. It used to be like that, but now it's not.
Yes, it would be like that now, too. She just doesn't dare.
What?
Well...
Why is she still being carried?
Lord, Clara will run at some point!
Don't you want to show it to me?
I want to see it so much, Clara.
I don't know, Heidi.
Don't force her.
She'll try it on her own some day.
We saw that you can do it.
Have self-confidence, my child.
It works.
Aren't you happy, Clara?
She can run!
One day she will walk with us.
One day she will walk.
So beautiful to be true.
Don't you want to stop working for a moment?
You also have a few days of rest.
You work from morning to evening.
Oh, what am I talking about?
You will know what you are doing.
Excuse me, but I'm so confused.
It's exactly what you said.
And I didn't believe you.
I don't know what to think anymore.
What if I just imagined it all?
But no!
I saw it with my own eyes. I can't imagine it. Suddenly she stood up.
She will be healthy.
Excuse me for getting so upset, but I can't understand it. I'd rather scream.
Do it.
If I only knew how I could give her self-confidence.
If she would try it just once. Just once, then she would believe it too and
would be healed.
Maybe I should go on a trip with the children. Maybe then an opportunity will
arise.
Oh, if only my son would have been there too.
Now I can only write it to him and he won't be able to believe it.
And we owe it all to you and a cow.
Don't tell fairy tales again!
No, I don't tell fairy tales, it's true!
Clara!
Heidi says you can stand up.
Yes, they all say that, but I don't know if it's true.
Clara, now stop it, the grandmother saw it.
I know, but I'm afraid that she only dreamed it.
You just don't have to be afraid.
No one dreamed, you were afraid of the cow.
It would be nice, right?
Yes.
Then I could run around with you everywhere and no one would have to carry me.
Why do you always say could? It's true, you can do it, you just have to try.
Exactly.
Why don't you just try it?
You're back already?
I didn't feel like it anymore.
Would you like to take the girls and me to the mountain lake you're talking
about?
Yes!
If you all feel like it, then we can go too. I'll take food with me.
Oh yes, but please take a lot with you.
Clara is on the way for three.
As much as we can carry.
Good.
Heidi has often written in her letters from the lake.
I always wanted to see him.
Do you think we can all do it together,
to bring Clara up there?
It should be pretty unobtrusive up there.
We'll do that.
Let's promise not to turn around.
Promised is promised and will not be broken.
And again.
No one should know until Clara has seen the lake, no matter how hard.
Yes, no one.
Promised is promised and will not be broken.
A lullaby, a lullaby, a lullaby, a lullaby
lullaby, lullaby, lullaby, a lullaby
lullaby, a lullaby, a lullaby, a lullaby, a lullaby
lullaby, a lullaby, a lullaby, a lullaby
lullaby, a lullaby, a lullaby
When they came home in the evening, they all told their grandfather about this
magical beautiful day up at the lake. Although Peter was tired of the
exhausting hiking, Heidi persuaded him to take part in a
mysterious plan, which she didn't want to explain to him yet.
Together with Clara and the grandmother, Heidi had a surprise in mind.
A bright, colorful, funny surprise that made Peter forget all his tiredness.
But we want to tell you about it in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges