Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark berries
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio,
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio
Holadio
Jaijaijaijai, Holadio, Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Look, kids, up there!
Tell me, Clara, isn't the water like a mirror?
Look closely!
Heidi's right. It's a glass mirror made of pure silver paper.
I don't know that one.
Clara, Peter, Grandmother, hurry! There are flowers I haven't seen yet!
I know them!
They'll be here in a few minutes.
I wish I could run as well as Heidi.
It would be wonderful, Grandmother,
if I could run all the way up here on my own.
You can do it if you want to.
You just have to get up, as you know.
Oh, what do I get out of trying it?
It hurts, my legs aren't strong enough.
It's all education.
When you were afraid of the cow, you could do it.
Clara, don't look so sad.
I mean, it's not bad, even if it sounds like it.
The next time you'll come all alone.
I'll try. I hope you're right.
That was a nice idea to climb up there with us. Maybe we can go again.
Maybe next year, Clara.
Now I'm going to the next best resort to recover from these exciting climbing
tours.
I'm not the youngest anymore.
We will write to you regularly, then you know how I feel.
And as soon as you two have the news to report to me that I want to hear,
I'll get on the next train and come to Braust.
Do you promise me to write at least one long letter every day?
Does it have to be every day?
Of course!
Can't you understand that I absolutely have to know if you've made any progress?
I like to write to you. Clara can teach me new words so that I can read better
what I'm scribbling together.
That's great! That's awesome!
We're both going to write a letter every day.
And when the letter I'm waiting for comes,
it's going to paint a thick red circle on the envelope.
I'm going to tell the postman what it means.
Then he can call from afar.
Hopefully we can ever write that letter.
You're going to write this letter, believe me.
Yes, Grandmother.
So, Almui.
Please take good care of Clara.
But you don't have to ask me for that.
Then come back.
Good thing you're back.
Heidi!
Hurry up!
Try to run with the whole herd.
He will protect himself.
Will something happen then?
What do you think he should do to the goats when they pass him by?
But what do you think of a farewell party?
For you?
No, for Peter.
I would like to thank him for that.
I have good news for you. You will get a farewell party.
What is that?
So you ask questions like a little child.
Well, I'm a little child too, aren't I?
You, Clara!
We shouldn't tell him how we imagine it.
You rascal! What will you see tomorrow?
It's a secret.
A big one.
There are no big secrets. There are only secret secrets.
Doesn't matter. Come to our winter party tomorrow evening.
Don't forget it.
Is there something to eat tomorrow evening?
Clara, you tell him.
You can't know that now.
Surprises have to surprise.
Otherwise they are not surprises.
Yes, if you think about it, you're right.
You notice that you are very serious.
Peter, don't you want to accompany us?
Or do you plan to stay here for a while?
No, too bad.
I have to go now.
What about the surprise?
I notice that.
See you tomorrow evening.
I also thought about it tomorrow.
that you wanted to come with us.
This stupid head.
Well.
Heidi and I will come down tomorrow morning and help you.
Yes, but don't oversleep.
I'm afraid that I won't sleep at all today because of excitement.
No, children.
Better come with Peter in the evening.
What?
You just said we should help you.
Why?
I just thought about it differently.
Why should I actually just surprise Peter?
I would also like to prepare a surprise for you.
Then it's much more fun.
So, and what now?
It's going to be fun.
Unfortunately, we can only wait. That's all. Good night, children. We'll see you
tomorrow evening. So, it can start.
See you tomorrow, children. Sleep well tonight, mom. I can hardly wait.
Good night. Goodbye.
I'm curious what she came up with this time.
Grandmother always has good ideas.
Do you remember the wedding then?
Yes, it was funny.
You were a pretty bride.
Yes, it was.
We danced and then your grandmother slipped away.
She was afraid to say goodbye to us.
Yes, that's right. That's how it was.
Did that make you sad to think about it?
Oh, if I knew it, I wouldn't have told you just now.
I just had to think that Grandmother is sitting somewhere nearby in a clinic and
is waiting for a very specific letter.
That's quite natural. Why not?
Clara, what is it?
Oh, what could it be? What do I do if I have to disappoint her and can't walk?
Stop it! You can walk quite well now, Clara. But if you don't practice, it'll
never get better. It's clear, isn't it?
It's hard.
It's easier than you think. Try it.
You only have to practice every day. I'll help you with that.
I'm scared.
And why?
That I'll try it and it won't work in the end.
Yes, I can understand that. But it'll work in the end, believe me.
Hopefully.
We'll start tomorrow.
Promise me you'll join us, Clara.
Good promise. But promise me you'll be patient.
Yes, of course.
THE END
I'll never believe in life that I can do it.
We're going to the pasture this morning and tonight together to the farewell
party of Grandmother.
Heidi, you two stay here today.
Why?
Clara should not overwork herself.
Both would be too much for her.
Besides, Clara has to start her walking exercises now.
Oh yes.
Better next week.
See you tomorrow, Clara.
Can I watch while I'm studying?
I can't imagine that Clara likes it. We should leave her alone.
Say something.
What is it? Don't you want to go with the goats for a while today?
And hurry up, today's a party.
So it's on time.
I am. Today, yes.
So see you then.
Good evening.
We're supposed to practice today.
We decided yesterday that we would practice today.
No, tomorrow is early enough. Give her some time.
So Clara, why do you have such a face again?
I don't know.
Because...
You know what, Heidi?
No, what?
I feel like a baby has to practice running.
I don't know, Clara. Sometimes I think you don't want to be able to run at all.
You're always complaining about me.
Now you have to be carried by other people all the time.
Don't you feel like a baby at all?
Yes, I do.
It's only starting to come to me now that you're saying it.
Well, then stop complaining.
We'll try it the way the grandfather said it before.
Come on, don't be like that.
Come on.
So, now we want to see it.
Does it hurt?
Yes, a little bit.
And that? Did that hurt?
Not at all.
Well, then.
Just one try.
Come on, just one.
Very slowly.
Come on.
No, I can't. I'm scared.
Heidi, let me go.
Please, let me go.
I can't.
I'm sorry. I thought it would be okay.
Clara, does it still hurt?
No.
Just because I couldn't help enough.
It won't be okay.
I can't do it anymore. It's my fault.
Shall I get you a nice big glass of goat's milk?
Yes?
Yes, please. I can use that now.
Sleep for a moment. I'll be right back.
And don't be sad.
Don't be angry with me.
I'll be right back.
If only they would leave me alone. I can't do it anymore.
Now I feel better.
Then it's good. Let's try again. I know what I did wrong before.
No, not today. Your grandfather said we'll start tomorrow.
Yes, I know. One try. Come on.
No, let go.
Tell me, aren't you curious what Grandmother thought of as a surprise?
No. You only ask because you want to distract.
Clara, one more try.
Oh.
Now, finally, stop.
Okay, I'll stop. But it's still so long until tonight.
The sun hasn't set yet.
I just can't wait any longer.
It probably doesn't want to get dark at all today, stupid.
Well, then I'll give Geißlein some herbs.
It stinks boring without the others.
Geißlein!
Why are you so late? We ran away with a stupid goat. I have to find her.
Clara, Peter came back with the goats.
You're late. I know.
Yes, Geißler ran away.
I see.
Did she get lost?
Yes.
Come on.
You have to stay alone today.
We can.
Finally.
Oh, there.
The one from the island.
It must be the little girl from the city who is wearing that.
Peter?
Yes?
Oh, nothing.
Good evening, how are you?
Thank you, Heidi. Good.
Except for my Rheuma.
Oh, hello.
Good evening.
Let's see if Barribbel knows what they are all looking for together down here.
Do you know if there is a special reason?
What should have a reason?
The old woman from Frankfurt has sent all kinds of people to villages
and made a huge theater.
The grandmother?
She's organising a party for me tonight. 她今天晚上为我举行了一场庆祝。
I don't think so. 没想到。
Give it to her again, will you? 再给她一次,是吗?
But a party could be something like that. 但是一场庆祝可以是什么呢?
Come on, you're invited to join them. 来吧,你被他们邀请了。
I'll distribute the goats for you. Go ahead. 我会给你们分配的,你去吧。
Thank you. Thank you so much. 谢谢,谢谢。
You, Peter, tell me tomorrow, okay? 你,Peter,告诉我明天,好吗?
I'd love to know why she bought all of this. 我想知道她买了这些东西的原因。
Where are you going? What is it?
To the children!
What are you doing here?
What is she doing there?
Who is doing what?
There!
A party?
That can't be! Look at this!
Peter! Clara!
Come on, Grandfather! Look at this!
What are you doing?
How beautiful it looks! A party! A real lampio party!
To be continued
And all the circumstances just for me.
Oh, you're coming just in time. The food is ready.
Play on, musicians!
Please step in, children, and take a seat.
Come on, Grandfather, let's go.
Simply wonderful.
Very wonderful.
Oh, welcome, Alm-Öhi.
Thank you very much for the invitation.
That's good. He thanks you for the invitation, but it's his house.
Yes, you're right.
Grandmother, are the children allowed to come in and look at everything?
I'm going with them to a class.
There's enough food for everyone.
Go and tell them that they are all warmly invited.
You are allowed to come in. You are invited.
Thank you.
Do you look so good? Is it comfortable?
Yes, thank you very much. It's all good like that.
Grandmother, you always have the best ideas. It's just wonderful.
Grandmother, these are my classmates.
Jakob, Klaus-Jürgen, Liselotte, Peter the Second, the long Oskar, and this?
Who is this?
This is the daughter of my oldest sister.
Then you're her uncle.
Yes, that's right.
You've got more friends than I thought. I think I need to have more bread ready.
The sausages probably won't be enough either.
Here, the first floor.
Heidi, look what she's doing there.
I've got you!
Come on, let's play catch!
You're up, you're up, you're up, you're up, you're up, you're up!
Yes!
Watch out, Peter!
No! No!
I got you! Stay here! No, faster!
Ha! Ha! Ha!
Here we are! You're running yourself, you fool!
Here I am! Here I am!
Don't go up there! But I'll get you too! Just wait!
Do you have to run after me all the time?
Find someone else!
Aha! You're the one!
It's our turn!
We call the game running after.
Don't you want to join us?
Oh, yes.
A relaxed band.
I used to be like that, too.
It's your turn!
That's the way it is when you don't pay attention for a moment.
Let's try it.
Not tonight.
Good night.
Here I am! Here I am!
That's how it has to be. That's how it should be for you too.
Yes.
And that's how it will be for you too when you practice hard.
Yes, maybe.
For sure you have to want it.
With all your heart.
You can run, Clara. You have already proven it to us.
You have to practice hard.
Do you think that helps?
Yes, that helps you.
But you have to wish it, my child.
You can't think of anything else.
You can do it.
Let's believe it, Clara. You can do it.
You must never give up on believing that you will be able to do it one day.
Please promise me that, Clara.
I promise it to you.
Then let's start practicing tomorrow morning, okay?
Yes.
We won! We won! We won!
If you sit there, everyone will come to the table.
It's the last one!
I fell on it.
It has to be eaten up!
It won't stay crunchy!
Hey, leave something else!
Good morning, you are so quiet in the evening clouds.
You are so quiet without feeling that I am without peace.
Write to us too, big mama.
But yes, Clara, of course I'll write to you right away when I get there.
Grandmother, I'll try.
I'll wait for a message every day.
I know she'll come.
Yes, I think so too.
Goodbye, Heidi. Help her.
Goodbye and thank you.
Thank you very much, Almö.
Goodbye.
Somehow a pity.
To be continued...
Goodbye, Grandmother. I will write to you.
I know that I can walk. I can walk.
I can walk. I know it. I can walk.
I will write to you.
I can walk. I can walk.
Right the next morning, Heidi and Clara made the promise to always practice
hard.
They practiced every day and very slowly they could notice a slight improvement.
Peter was of course the most impatient of all. He just didn't want to wait until
Clara was finally healthy.
But until that was the case, Clara, Heidi and her grandfather had to work hard
for many, many hours.
And then suddenly a letter came from the grandmother who made Clara very, very
sad.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home, find your happiness, come back home.