Holadio
Heidi, Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark pines
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi, Heidi
You need to be happy
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio,
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio
Holadio
Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio, Holadio
Holadio, Holadio,
Come on, come home
Find your happiness
Come back at last
Good morning, Clara.
You slept a long time today.
We came to bed late yesterday.
Yes.
Today the exercises start.
Oh, you don't want to anymore.
Yes, but I have to think about Grandmother. It's a pity that she's gone.
She's not far away. She'll come to visit us again.
Clara.
I know all that. She doesn't want to go home before I can walk.
Well, there you have it. Then start practicing today. You promised it to her
yesterday.
A promise is a promise. How will you ever be able to run if you don't start
practicing?
Good. Let's start. I promised it.
You don't have to be afraid. You've proven that you can run. You just have to
believe in it.
Yes. Good.
That's not how it works. You have to turn to me.
I want that all the time.
Wait, I'll help you.
Heidi, what are you doing? You're hurting me.
And now you just have to get up.
When the cow ran up to you, you could do that too.
Your feet are already on the ground. Did you notice?
It doesn't hurt at all.
Well, you see, now you just have to get up.
I don't know if it's possible.
Hold on to me.
I don't trust you.
I don't know.
Slowly.
Clara.
Does it hurt?
Please say something.
Grandfather, quick!
Come on, help!
Is it bad?
No, it's not.
Clara.
How did you get on the floor?
She tried to stand up.
Hm?
Yes.
And did you make it?
No, my legs didn't move at all. And I was scared.
Why? You don't have to be scared.
I know.
That she fell is my fault. I couldn't hold her because she is so heavy.
Did you convince her to this attempt?
Or did you feel the desire to try, Clara?
No.
It was me, but Clara wanted it, too.
Next time, it won't be without me. Understood?
It's still too early.
Clara's legs are not used to running yet.
Now don't let yourself be discouraged.
We're starting slowly, step by step.
This won't work overnight.
Copyright WDR 2018
Did it hurt you?
Yes, a little.
Very good. Really excellent.
I was afraid you didn't feel anything at all.
I would have preferred that.
I can imagine that.
But the pain proves to me that your muscles react.
Can I do that, yes?
Do you want to?
Yes.
One, two, three.
One, two, one, two, one, two, one, two.
Very slowly, Heidi.
The way I did it.
One after the other.
Mhm.
One, two, one, two.
Like this?
Yes, that's right.
Slowly and evenly.
Is that clear?
And how long is it?
As long as you can.
I'll call you then.
Good.
You know, Heidi, I think it's going to take an infinite amount of time.
We've just started. We're not going to be impatient, are we?
One, two. One, two. One, two. One, two.
That's enough. Let's stop.
Oh no! Grandfather said we should practice as long as we can.
And I can do it for a while. One, two. One, two. One, two.
Good morning! Have you already run?
Good morning!
Good morning, Peter!
Are you coming to the pasture today?
No, we can't. We'll start practicing today.
Ah, then of course we can't.
We'll be late by tonight!
Good morning, everyone!
Watch out for the goats!
Yes, and give the ghost a herb! You know why!
I want it to be the best milk in the world!
You don't have to tell me!
Goodbye!
I promise we'll practice hard!
Puppet light! Go!
Let's keep going!
Ice!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10! 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10!
And now try to lift your legs up on your own. And now try to lift your legs up
on your own.
Okay, I'll try it. Okay, I'll try it.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10!
Don't give up.
It will never work.
Yes.
Oh no.
One, two, one, two, one, two.
Now watch out, I'll try again.
You moved it.
All of a sudden I knew what I had to do.
I told myself I could do it.
See?
Do you finally think you can walk, Clara?
Now I have to believe it.
We have to practice harder. It has to get better.
One, two. One, two.
Ghost, come on, you should have some too!
What do you say to that?
We're just getting started with the practice and you're already making such
progress?
Clara, I'm happy. Together we can do it.
Yes, now I know it too.
Is Clara already gone?
Good evening, Peter, good evening!
Go, say quickly, have you already got up?
No, not yet. That would be too early.
What? Why?
Now don't be so disappointed. I can show you something else.
Pay attention. Here.
Yes, tell me, Clara. You can move.
All of a sudden it went all by itself. Right, Heidi?
Yes, tonight we have to write a letter to the grandmother.
She must know that you can move her.
Yes, and you'll give it to her tomorrow at the post office.
Huh? Oh, Heidi.
Oh.
Heidi, a big kiss, please!
Yes, of course, we'll do that.
It's getting better and better!
Slowly, one more piece, come on!
So...
Can you run now?
Now tell me, Clara, quickly, have you already walked today?
No, not yet, but almost. It won't take long.
Today I would have sworn that you can do it.
Well?
Oh, the letters. There, they are for you.
You didn't get them upstairs in the garden, did you?
Of course not, I forgot them again this morning.
I thought of the grandmother. There, Clara.
Thank you.
But now I'm curious.
I'm afraid I won't be able to help you.
You're welcome.
Dear Heidi, thank you so much for helping Clara practice every day.
I'm thinking about you and I'm trying to imagine what you're doing.
The sanatorium I'm in is very nice.
When I look out the window, I see the mountains right in front of me.
And then I know that somewhere up there are my two children
and that at some point Clara will learn to walk up there.
I had a dream the other day. I saw how Clara walked across the meadow and was
faster than you, Heidi.
Did you hear what I just read? She dreamed that you could walk!
Leave me alone!
All of you are waiting for me to finally be able to walk!
And what if I can't?
But Clara...
I want to tell you something. It doesn't matter to me if I ever walk.
But...
Stop crying.
Clara, you will be able to walk.
I don't want to walk anymore.
I don't care anymore.
I don't want to practice anymore.
I just want you to finally leave me alone.
And I don't want Peter to ask me every night.
Clara, it's okay. Maybe they're all too impatient. You're right.
We will give you more time. Peter doesn't ask anymore and Heidi doesn't push
anymore.
We wish it for you. Nobody wanted to hurt you.
I'm sorry. Me too.
If I did something wrong, I'm sorry. Me too.
I'm sorry, please.
I'm sorry, Grandfather. I can't go on like this.
I give up. I want to go back to Frankfurt.
Good.
Before we started our sound exercises, you couldn't even move your legs.
And now you can.
Is that right or am I saying something wrong?
Now say something, Clara.
It's right.
You see.
In the beginning you thought it was going very fast.
You just have to practice a little bit, nothing more.
And now all of a sudden you see that it's not going the way you think.
That makes you impatient and makes you doubt, because you didn't believe in the
effectiveness of the exercise from the start.
How do you know? I really didn't believe in the exercises.
Every time I wanted something from you, you saw it.
Clara, I know you in the meantime. You lose your temper so easily.
You know, I won't take one from you. I don't think you really want to go back to
Frankfurt so quickly.
I don't think you're that weak and cowardly.
Of course you want to be able to walk, but you can't walk fast enough.
And that's why you're crying.
No, not because of that!
Ungrateful people can not run and will never be able to live in it.
Fortunately, you don't have to listen to him, because you can run if you want.
It shouldn't matter how long it takes.
Tell me, isn't the main thing to know that you learn it one day?
I'm sorry. I don't know what happened to me.
Somehow the courage was gone.
Hm, I knew it would come.
Ah, Clara, what a beautiful sunset.
Yes.
I don't understand anything anymore.
Well, Almö, looking for a house again, or are you just passing by for no reason?
Oh, where are you from? I want to ask you something.
Is your butter still as good as it used to be, or has it been left behind?
Left behind? My butter is the best butter in the area, and you know that.
Otherwise you wouldn't have come.
Michael, bring me the butter we just made.
Look at this. What does it look like? Huh?
Hmm. Yes, quite decent. Tell me.
Why don't you repair your pot? The water's running out.
I know. I just didn't get the hang of it.
I'll make you an offer. I'll repair the pot, and you'll give me the butter.
Yes, I have nothing against it.
Strange.
Why doesn't he take his own butter?
I think he needs ours for the maimed girl from Frankfurt,
who is in his hut upstairs.
And he wants to pay for the butter somewhere.
Hard to believe how he has changed.
Copyright WDR 2018
So you're still standing here.
Now I haven't been up here for years and everything is still as it was.
Heidi! Clara!
I picked them for you, because you must be busy again today.
Thank you, Peter, that's nice of you.
Nice, thank you.
I don't care and I don't ask.
Yes, today you can ask.
He can, right?
Yes, it's getting better and better.
That makes me happy. Keep practicing, okay?
Oh dear.
What happened to her?
Come on, let's see what's going on.
Oh dear.
So don't stand around, make sure I get rid of the goats.
I can't do anything about it, they ran away on their own.
Watch out that I get rid of them.
Get lost, make sure you get away, go!
What about the goats, they've never done that before.
Nothing special, I've collected their favorite herbs and they smell good.
And do you want to give them to Swain?
Of course, their milk has to be just as good as Geislein's.
Now go.
All for me.
I can't just take them away.
What am I supposed to do?
They don't listen to me anymore.
If I don't want to stay in here all night, I'll have to come up with something.
Joseph!
Come here!
Come back!
Good job, Joseph!
Stop it! Not again!
Not again!
Goodbye, you two!
Goodbye!
To be continued
The goats are fed, now we have to take care of our food.
They're hungry.
You did all this for me. You looked for the herbs for me.
Who eats the herbs, you or Swenli?
Grandfather, you mean...
You mean...
I've already written a lot more than you. Come on, show me!
Oh, stop it! That's mean! Give it to me!
No, Heidi, give me the letter! It doesn't matter what I've written! Give it to
me!
Heidi, give it to me! If you don't stop, I'll read your letter! Give it to me!
Heidi!
Please don't.
If you read my letter, I can read what you wrote.
Good.
There you have it.
Here.
Bye.
Let go of my hands, then I'll fall over.
Now!
That's not how it works. You just have to forget that you have arms
and just think that your legs are supposed to carry you.
You're good, I've been trying all this time.
Good, go on!
Clara, and?
Did it hurt?
Not the legs, but the hand. I fell on it.
Doesn't even sound like it.
Probably just a little stung. Come on, let's keep going.
Don't be a frog.
Oh, stop it. That has nothing to do with it. I don't feel like it anymore today.
When will you all finally realize that it doesn't make sense?
I'll never be able to walk. Never.
Stop complaining!
I can't hear it anymore.
All the time you say you can't do it. You don't want to do it at all.
And all the time you shout that your legs don't want to carry you.
Your legs are fine, do you hear? You just don't want your legs to carry you.
Because you don't want to be able to walk at all, Clara.
No, Heidi, don't wake me up. Stay here.
No, I don't even think about it. Heidi!
This can't be happening.
A little more wobbly, but I'm standing on my own two legs.
She can do it all at once.
It can't be, I don't believe it.
Hold on!
Heidi!
I'll hold you, be careful, Clara.
We did it.
Yes, it looks like it, but maybe I'm just dreaming.
No! You're not dreaming!
We did it! We did it! We did it!
When Peter came up to the Alps the next morning, he didn't dare to look at it at
first.
But then, when he finally understood what had happened, he was overjoyed.
Heidi and Clara practiced running every day from now on.
And every day went a little better, Clara was able to go a little further.
First still supported by Heidi and later even a few steps alone.
But Clara still didn't want to believe that she could finally run.
And when the bad luck with the wheelchair happened, it was unbearable.
But we want to tell you about it in our next story.
Heidi, Heidi, your world are the mountains.
Heidi, Heidi, because up here you are at home.
Heidi, Heidi, come home.
Find your happiness, come back home.
To be continued