Heide
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Careful, I'll hold you.
We did it, Clara.
We did it.
But maybe it's just a dream.
No!
We have to write a letter now and tell it to grandfather.
Yes, do it.
Oh, you're even standing free-handed. Grandfather!
Grandfather, come with me quickly. I want to show you something. Come quickly.
Grandfather, quickly!
There!
Clara.
Clara is standing free-handed.
Just run!
I can't believe it.
I'm so happy.
You would never have thought that.
I can't believe it.
I don't know what to say.
I'm proud of you, Clara.
I'm very proud of you.
And thank you very much.
No, my child.
You're not to be thanked.
You made it all by yourself.
No, not yet.
Let me stay here a little longer.
I want to try for a while to see if it really works. I don't believe it yet.
I'm afraid that I'll never be able to do it again when I sit down.
You can forget this fear. You've only been able to do it once and will be able
to do it again and again.
Hopefully. Hopefully you're right.
It's just that everything looks so different. It's so unusual and strange.
It looks much bigger.
I don't dare to look down at the earth at all.
The ground is suddenly very far away.
Strange. For me, it's very close.
Now I'm curious what he's going to say.
We'll get him now.
Hello!
Hello Peter! Good evening!
Good evening!
How are you, Clara?
Have you made any progress?
No, Peter, I'm sorry.
Unfortunately not yet.
Why is she whining like that?
Keep practicing, okay?
She's crazy.
Well, now it's time.
Yes.
Peter!
Man, oh man!
There's no way that can't be true.
You're amazed?
Yes.
Calm down, stop screaming!
Clara, I'm sorry!
I think I have to sit for a moment.
Yes, I can understand that.
So, I sit. Thank you.
You look like you still couldn't believe it.
I can't somehow.
Peter!
Huh?
If you don't hurry up soon, your goats will arrive in the village without you.
Oh dear.
Goodbye, see you tomorrow!
Goodbye!
Do you want to stay here?
Come tomorrow, not so late!
See you tomorrow!
It's a pity that I can't see Grandmother's face when she reads the letter.
So either she cries for joy or she laughs and dances through the room.
I think she doesn't do anything and is speechless for the time being.
Oh, what? Grandmother and speechless? Never in life. That doesn't suit her. I
think she dances.
Well, maybe you're right.
Or wait a minute. We don't write that I can stand. I want to be able to walk
first and then we say it.
What? Can we do that?
And then we both surprise. Papa and you.
Oh, what?
Yes, Heidi. I want to see your faces when you find out.
That's going to be nice.
Right foot, left foot, right foot, slowly.
And right, left, right, left.
Nice and even, don't get tired.
Good morning!
Good morning, look what we're doing here tomorrow.
Do you know roughly when she can go to the alleys?
That will take some time, but please do me a favor and let me go for a moment.
Gladly. You have exactly the right size.
That even works better than with me.
One and two and three and right and left and right and far.
One, two, one, two.
It's getting better from time to time.
It won't hurt anymore, will it?
So you don't want to give up, you two?
You're exaggerating.
It's way too exhausting what you're doing.
No, not at all.
Really not.
I'm not tired at all.
Nice and even, nice and far.
Four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
What? It's early again?
What are you doing?
Just like that.
You're already here?
It's her fault. She ran away from me.
Of course I had to follow her and catch her.
You're lying!
Listen, you're just curious.
Me? Curious? No.
Yes, curious.
Believe me, he just wants to know what we're doing.
Well, then he should see it.
One.
What are you saying? Without my help.
Fabulous, Clara. I would never have thought that.
Yes?
Are you leaving the goats alone again?
Please don't scold him, Grandfather. He can't do anything about it.
He has to see it.
Hm?
Yes.
Peter, I understand your impatience, but the herd is more important. So go.
Run!
Stupid.
Swinley and Geisel have to have herbs.
Leave me alone!
Don't give up, Clara. I'll be back tonight.
Don't worry. I'll never give up.
I don't understand. She should...
It's been weeks since I last saw her with my own eyes.
She can walk. She showed it.
Today I'll write it.
Grandmother doesn't think you can't walk.
Of course not. I can't walk yet.
And the bar doesn't count.
What am I supposed to write then?
Why don't you write,
Clara tries every day, but she can't walk yet?
No, it's enough for me.
I'm slowly getting it done.
Just do it. The surprise gets bigger and bigger afterwards.
So good.
I'll write that you like to practice every day
and laugh at it.
Good luck.
She never believes that. She never believes that I laugh while practicing.
And why not?
So tell me, can't we write that we threw the wheelchair away because the wheels
were stuck?
Ah, does she believe that?
Yes, I can imagine that she believes that.
We can write that he was standing in the rain and is now completely rusty.
It could have been a thunderstorm.
Do you know what amazes me?
That you're not even red yet.
If I had to look at her, I might be red, but the ink can't change, can it?
I don't think I'm writing anything.
She won't take that off your wheelchair. She knows I can repair it.
Well, then I'll just write that the wheelchair was rusted.
To be continued...
We're not going to throw the wheelchair away right away, we're just going to
hide it.
Yes, good.
Doesn't it matter to you that he's gone all of a sudden?
No, it's kind of weird, isn't it?
Very nice.
Slowly. Then nothing can happen.
One. Two. Slowly.
Left.
Up to here and all the way to the end.
I won't be able to do it anymore.
You could do it because we hid the wheelchair.
It looks like it.
Come on, Heidi.
Good morning, Clara. Good morning, Heidi.
Look, it's still working.
Oh, my God.
I even hid the wheelchair in the shed this morning.
Good thing the old thing is gone.
I think so too.
Well then, see you at work today!
Goodbye, don't be so late!
Good, you can do it.
Yes, let my hand go now, Heidi.
Yes.
I don't know, I think I can do it alone.
Do you think so?
Yes, let's go.
Clara, be careful!
I'm probably not that far yet.
Too bad, I thought it was possible.
Oh, what's wrong?
It was too early.
Unfortunately.
Is there milk?
Of course, I'll get it for you.
Wait, okay?
I'll get it for you.
Heidi, quick!
Come on, hurry up! I can't hold on any longer!
No!
This is...
Stop!
Help!
It's so dizzying!
Oh dear, Clara!
Grandfather, quick!
Stop!
Just say something, Clara!
Now all that's missing is that you broke a leg.
Tell me, does it hurt more than usual?
Clara, what happened?
Do you feel pain?
Now tell me, what is it?
Come to me.
I'm scared.
Why scared?
I wonder too. When I went to get milk, she was at the fence. She must have
walked all the way alone.
Yes, that's right.
Yes, but then you don't have to be scared anymore.
Congratulations, Clara.
You probably don't want to hear that.
I think Clara got scared because she fell down.
What now?
For today you have practiced enough. We don't want to overdo it.
Good.
Then come.
Yes.
You two stay in the living room in this nice weather.
Isn't that good for you, Clara?
She doesn't feel like going out today.
Grandfather, will you please bring me up? I would like to sleep. I'm so terribly
tired.
As you wish.
Now sleep well, my little one.
Yes, I will.
It tasted good, as always.
It can't have tasted good. You didn't drink anything.
I don't like today. I didn't practice today, so I can't be hungry.
I don't like today. I didn't practice today. I can't be hungry.
I don't like today. I can't be hungry.
Just a bit more.
Then its all finished.
She's strange.
It was going so well.
She doesn't feel like it anymore.
Well, well.
Clara needs a few days of rest.
Leave her alone.
She has to sit down for a while.
Still, I find it strange.
Because you, as always,
want to achieve everything from today to tomorrow.
Heidi,
let her go. Please.
No!
No, what am I going to do now?
What was that?
Clara!
Oh dear.
What are you doing there?
You ran all the way there!
Clara, please stop crying.
Please, Clara.
You have no reason.
You ran all the way there.
Do you understand why she's crying?
Clara, what is it?
I broke it!
I knocked the wheelchair down!
Clara, stop it!
Now it's all over!
Nothing is over.
Now everything starts right. Don't cry. I know what you think. I know what's
going on in you.
I think you wish at the moment everything would have stayed the way it was.
You just got a little discouraged. That's over.
Watch out. If we've overcome that, everything will go much faster.
I always do everything wrong.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
And they didn't know that this morning?
Why are you standing there all wrinkled?
Here, make yourself comfortable
Are you on vacation today?
Something like that
Look, the eagle is in the sky
Do you want to help me?
Yes.
Heidi, you too.
Yes, of course.
Now you walk up here for the first time.
Attention.
Ready.
Everything seems much bigger to me.
The mountains are much higher than usual.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Six, seven, eight, oh, look at that. 六,七,八,哦,看看吧。
Careful. 小心。
Be careful not to stand still. 小心。
Slowly.
Right.
You made it!
I picked it up. I ran over and picked it up. Now I can write to Grandmother.
Finally it was time. Heidi and Clara wrote to the grandmother that she should
come and the grandmother immediately announced her arrival.
But she was not alone to the great joy of the children. Clara's father, Mr.
Sesemann, came with her.
And so much Clara's surprise exactly as she had often imagined it.
But unfortunately it was also said to say goodbye at the same time. The
beautiful summer was over.
The carriage was about to bring Clara home.
Even Peter had to swallow a few times not to burst into tears.
But we want to tell you about that in our next story.
Heide, Heide, your world are the mountains, Heide, Heide, because up here you
are at home, Heide, Heide, come home, find your happiness, come back again.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges