Holadio
Heidi
Your world are the mountains
Because up here you are at home
Dark firs
Green meadows in the sunshine
Heidi
You need to be happy
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back home
Heidi
1, 2, 1, 2, 1, 2, 1
No, no!
Just a little bit more. Good, Clara.
One, two, and one, and two, and three.
You did it!
Now no one has to help me anymore. Now I can walk really well.
Really well not yet, but it will be.
Shouldn't we write to the grandmother that she's coming?
Yes, let's do it right away.
Good morning, the postman is coming. I have mail for you.
She writes that she can come right away. Her cure would be over soon anyway.
She writes, she's happy to see you standing.
Me too.
I still haven't told her that I can walk.
That's right.
Is that supposed to mean that the grandmother doesn't know yet?
Yes, I want to surprise her with that.
How can you keep something like that to yourself?
I would have told that to everyone.
You're also a trach aunt.
I want a...
A trach aunt, the chickens are laughing.
Here, listen. She wants to leave on Saturday morning and would be here by noon.
Today is Saturday. Then she'll come today.
Of course, as always. I'm not there when she comes and can't take the whole
theater.
That's not a theater.
Something like that.
Grandfather, did she write it too?
Yes, she did.
Stand up, you lazy...
...and go to the meadow with Peter and the goat.
As far as I know Peter, he'll sneak away by noon.
Go on, Joseph, to the meadow.
That's good. That's really good.
You're doing your theatre.
Peter, are you happy now?
Yes.
Soon.
Come on, it's not too late.
You'll hardly ever find her again.
You know, she's tanned and healthy and laughs all day.
I can imagine. When I was little, we were in the mountains, too.
Do you still remember? Do you still remember how you rang the church bells?
Yes. At least I remember how Father laid me on my knee back then.
Who did it hurt more?
Your pants, or Father's hand? You didn't shed a single tear.
If I'm honest, it didn't hurt at all.
But when he caught me when I left the dog in the henhouse,
he gave me a little more trouble, and that's when it hurt.
You and your dog, you were inseparable.
To be continued...
Mother, Mrs. Sesemann is coming back and a good-looking man is accompanying her.
Maybe that's Clara's father, but Peter didn't tell anything about it. Don't the
children know?
Possibly. It could of course also be the doctor.
I can't tell you anything about it. You saw the doctor back then, didn't you?
Yes.
What do you have? What do you think?
Do you think they're taking Heidi away again? They're taking her with them to
Frankfurt?
No, I don't think so.
I hope, I hope you're right, Brigitte.
Welcome! Good day!
Clara, your father, Mr. Sesamann!
Oh, Clara! Clara!
Clara! My child, how are you?
How beautiful!
Oh, Clara.
You've become even more beautiful.
You're all tanned and clean.
You always say that.
Grandmother didn't say a word about it.
Yes, I asked her to.
It was supposed to be a big surprise.
She succeeded.
Well, little friend, how are you?
Oh, what am I asking?
You can see how you're doing.
You look great.
Yes, when she sees our surprise for the first time.
Are you quiet?
I'm sorry.
Clara, Heidi, how are you, children?
Did you just talk about a surprise?
No, great-grandma.
Just look, mother, at how the children look.
Don't they both look gorgeous?
And isn't Heidi really pretty?
You can't even recognize her.
Yes.
Let's welcome the Almöhi.
We owe it to him.
I'm glad to have you here.
My father has come along.
Hello.
Do you think we should do it now?
Yes, I would like to thank you from the bottom of my heart for everything you
have done for Clara.
Not necessary.
And yet, don't be so modest.
You just have to look at my Clara to know everything.
I've never seen my child so radiant.
If you want to thank someone,
then thank the mountains, the holy, Peter and the animals.
Apart from that, I think you should thank them much too early.
Why?
The children have a surprise for you.
Attention!
I think I'm dreaming.
Clara has woken up.
And off she goes.
Look, the child. The child is running.
Clara can run.
The surprise was a success, Clara.
That can't be true.
Clara.
Clara, my child.
Why don't you congratulate me?
I don't know.
And he didn't write me a word about it,
where I waited for it so long.
If you knew, it wouldn't have been a surprise.
Clara, my little...
What are you saying?
I'm speechless.
My little Clara.
Finally I can run, just like other kids.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Now we're standing here and crying like little children.
Thank you, Almudie.
I don't know how we can ever do that again.
You don't have to.
Peter, I thank you.
I thank you.
I don't know if I'm awake or if I may have just been dreaming.
Our surprise was quite successful.
Yes, you can say that.
You can say that.
Copyright WDR 2018
Now they're all coming back and the girl from Frankfurt is wearing the balm oil.
I'm scared, Brigitte. I'm scared that they'll take Heidi with them.
Ask her. She's running towards us.
I'll be right back!
Good day, Grandmother!
Heidi!
I'm sorry I haven't been here for so long.
Tell me, child, are you going with them to Frankfurt?
What?
I want to say hello to you too.
Hello, Mrs. Sesemann.
I'm so happy.
The children will have told you.
Our Clara can walk.
I had long given up hope that one day it would come true.
Please, may I ask you something?
Do you intend to take Heidi with you when you return to Frankfurt?
But no, how do you know that?
Do you still worry about that time?
Can't you finally forget that?
I couldn't forget it. I always have to think about it.
You know, Heidi belongs here.
Yes, we know that now.
We have learned to understand why Heidi can never feel at ease with us.
Heidi belongs here to you and to the mountains.
That is the world in which our Heidi is happy.
Heidi, tell your grandmother that you're not going anywhere, so that she
believes it.
I'll stay here.
Yes.
Are you calm now? You really don't have to be afraid.
I will never go away from here voluntarily.
Promised.
Yes, of course. This is promised.
And promised is promised and will not be broken.
You know that. But you have to promise me now that you will never be afraid.
Please forgive me for being suspicious.
You don't have to apologize to me. I understand.
I just don't want you to worry about anything in the future.
Well, now I have to believe it slowly.
You don't know how much I've worried about myself.
It's over.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
I'm going to miss that.
What?
When I see you eat, I always get an appetite.
In Frankfurt, I only see Mrs. Rottenmeier.
Why Frankfurt?
Oh, because I have to go back, unfortunately.
No.
Tell me, you're not serious about that, are you?
Is that really serious?
Yes, tomorrow they're leaving. Klara is supposed to spend the winter in
Frankfurt.
To stay here she's not strong enough yet.
Oh, I see.
Don't be so sad. Klara will come back next spring.
That's right.
Yes, at some point I'll have to learn again.
Oh, I see.
And you can't do without learning.
Yes, I can, but the others won't let me.
Frohling!
No, Clara. This pattern you can't do...
...and that you can't do, and this you can't do and that you can't do.
and this, and this you can't do, and this you can't do, and that's not.
Yes, Mrs. Rottenmayr.
Next year you can come on stage with us everywhere.
Yes I know!
Come sing something.
If I practise hard the whole winter...
...then next year I can dance with you two.
Yes!
The moon has risen, the golden stars are twinkling in the sky.
The forest stands black and silent and rising from the meadows the white fog is
wonderful.
How is the world so quiet and in silence?
Good-bye, Swindle. Good-bye, little ghost.
It's about time.
Good-bye, Bearly. See you next spring. I'll be back, for sure.
Now off to the stable with you until we come back.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Joseph.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
Please, stand still.
All right, Clara.
It's over now.
I'll be dreaming about it now.
I won't see it for a long winter.
I'll paint it for you.
Can we go on now?
Yes.
Clara, you are always very welcome.
Yes, I know. Thank you.
Heidi, don't forget me and write to me often.
Yes, please.
Clara, goodbye.
Dear Clara, I'll write to you for sure.
And I'll write to you too.
And you too, Peter.
You don't need that. I don't like to read.
Goodbye, Clara.
Goodbye.
Next time we'll see each other again.
Don't forget to write. Goodbye. 再见.
Clara, goodbye. 再见.
I'll be back next year. 下年我会回来。
Live well, Clara. 生日快乐,Clara.
Goodbye. 再见。
Send me back to my motherland. 送我回家。
Live well, Heidi. 生日快乐,Heidi.
Goodbye, Peter. 再见,Peter.
Goodbye, Clara. 再见,Clara.
Goodbye. 再见。
We'll see each other again in spring. 明年我们会见面。
They'll be gone in a minute.
Now. 现在就消失了。
Promise me that you'll definitely come back. 保证你一定会回来。
Here we are. 希望你会回来。
Perfect. 太好了。
One grape is more beautiful than the other.
Dear Heidio...
Today I'm writing a whole magazine.
The warm bed is for the grandmother.
Grandmother wants her to have it.
Dear Heidi, today I can only write a short letter.
The candidate has now added a new subject.
And that concerns me very much, because it is very difficult.
Geometry.
One, two, one, two, one, two, one, two, one.
Wonderful, Mrs. Clara. If you keep going like this, you'll soon be able to go
back to the mountains.
You have nothing against it?
Nothing.
Thank you for watching and see you in the next video!
What do you see out there?
Grey sky, snowflakes and snow.
And what's so special about it? Why do you have to stare at it all the time?
I see.
I want the snow to disappear so that Clara can come.
That will take a long time. How is she doing? Has she written again?
Good.
Aha.
She's already climbing stairs.
Subtitles by Stephanie Geiges
The sun is getting warmer.
Yes, it is.
Shall we go?
From me?
A train is falling!
Nice, like a toy!
If we get in there, we could visit Clara.
And she could visit us.
Hello! Railway! Bring us Clara!
Hello, railway! Bring us Clara!
Clara!
Hi, Peter! I'm here!
Hi!
It wasn't too late.
Heidi, Peter and Clara were still only dreaming about the colorful flower
meadows.
But they knew that one day it would be exactly the same as they imagined it to
be.
They knew that this day would come and that it wouldn't take that long anymore.
And they were looking forward to it.
Oh, what a shame. It was all just a dream.
I'm going crazy now. Did I really pull the curtain out?
Put it back on quickly, or you'll catch a cold.
For a moment I thought it was really coming through the snow.
What a shame. What a shame.
What a shame.
Heidi, Heidi, your world is the mountains,
Because up here you are at home
Heidi, Heidi
Come home
Find your happiness
Come back again